I think I checked into the residence in
on March 27th when we had 30 visits. I
mean, I I live in Tulsa, so I'll get
home maybe one or two days of the
weekend if we have time. And then, so
I'm just ready to get back and see my
family. But, uh, no, it's so exciting.
We put all this work in starting in
really in June, you know, starting we
get the list of kind of who the
prospects are and then really, you know,
once we break training camp, we're into
these colleges and it's like, okay, here
we are. We're finally there where we can
we can make our team better, right?
>> And your direct title is director of
college scouting and and you've been
with the team for how long now?
>> 21 years.
>> That's incredible.
>> What is the difference now for you in
this process? Because if there's any
element of football that has changed the
most over the last five to to seven
years, it's probably been the college
ranks and NIL transfer portal and all
the different moving and shaking that
you've had to endure from the pro level.
How has it changed your job and how you
do things? Yeah, just the gathering the
character and background on these guys,
it's it's really tough. I mean, when you
have guys that have been to three
different schools, sometimes you get
sour grapes from the old school, trying
to talk to all your sources throughout
all these different places and just
trying to understand like what we're
bringing into the building. It's just
tough. I mean, trying to just you have a
small period of time to like get to know
these guys. So, like what type of
football character, how do they learn,
like all that stuff. Like a lot of
times, hey, if you're on a six-month
contract at a new school, you're going
to be your best behavior. But is that
truly who you are, right?
>> Has the development changed at all in
any certain positions with kids kind of
jumping around. Maybe you're not in one
system and you get to see them kind of
grow.
>> Yeah, I think it does. Yeah, absolutely.
I think it's helps a lot. I mean,
sometimes just like even look at like
Caleb DS. I mean, you know, he played
for Sabin, played for uh who's the guy
at Penn State? Uh yeah, Jim. Yeah,
Nolles. And then and then Patricia. But
I mean, hey, three different systems and
you're like, "Okay, this guy's
unbelievable.
>> He gets it."
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. How how much specifically, like
you mentioned Patricia, and that's
thought to be just such an advanced
scheme defensively relative to how a lot
of colleges run things. How beneficial
of that is that for Caleb DS coming into
the NFL of just like, hey, we already
know he can handle a lot of the stresses
that exist with 100%. I think that's
kind of what put like Alabama and
Georgia players ahead in the last 10
years, like playing for Kirby or or
Nick. Like I mean they put so much on
these kids and if they tell you, "Hey,
this guy's an average learner." You get
him at the combine and they're like
advanced compared to some other kids and
you're like, "Wait, he's average." Like,
"Oh my god, this guy's unbelievable. He
can draw up all 11. He knows what's
going on." And you're like, "Oh my god."
Like Yeah. So it really when you get
guys from some of those programs, you
know, exactly like they've been they've
been through it, right?
>> Walk us through your anxiety on Thursday
night as you see the board kind of
falling in different ways. And at in the
beginning when Carell Tate comes off the
board, you have to think that's pretty
good. Giants take Ree and then those
defenders start coming off. Just walk me
through the anxiety.
>> Yeah, we were just like we we know
there's going to be offensive players
drafted. Like please come off the board,
right? But it's like okay, we had have
12 12 guys in our first round and like
historically we try to like just hey
let's grade these guys year to year.
Let's not push guys up because of need
or or whatever. But it was usually I'm
sorry six 12 to 16 guys most of the
years
>> and and so like yeah it was it was
please have one of these guys fall to us
and I know like
>> we were hoping that that there would
maybe like a couple surprises like
especially the O line maybe um the
receivers we could see both those guys
like we understood that one but we were
hoping one of a couple more O linemen
got pushed up
>> with the way that everything has fallen
so far and how everything went yesterday
you've got three fourth round picks How
do you feel like your board is set up to
where you're at now and how things have
fallen in front of you?
>> Oh, it's been it's been really good cuz
I think we still have about eight guys
that we have third round grades on. So,
that that's huge for us. I mean, we have
some guys that we really like and it's
like, okay, we don't have after the
fifth like I don't think we have
anything till the seventh. So, um No, we
don't have a fifth. Yeah. No,
we got rid of it. So, I mean after that
I mean maybe we have a chance to move
down if some of those guys are still
there.
>> I guess we'll see how that plays out.
But no, we have guys that I think we can
come in and like really help us. So,
it's exciting.
>> Director of college scouting Mitch Le
Point joining us here on our coverage of
day three of the NFL draft. You you
mentioned the fifth round pick and and
sending that to San Francisco for D
Winters and getting a linebacker that
has starting experience and bringing him
into the building. That changes a little
bit of what your your job is as the
director of college scouting, but he was
in college not that long ago back in
2023. What do you remember about him
through that process?
>> Yeah, I mean just that run hit factor. I
mean, the motor, the physicality, and
then just having like Nick Sornson who
is part of San Francisco staff and then
with our coaches watching him. I mean,
like it's, hey, he's coming in at worst.
You're thinking about your third
linebacker and he's going to push to
start and just kind of honestly like
took like a little bit of like, okay, we
don't have to reach for one of these
kids later in the linebacker room.
Obviously, we had a big glaring hole
there.
>> And then we've kind of done a good job
now kind of just filling that, you know,
and then other, you know, Merist is a
guy that can kind of play both, too. So
that's kind of given us an opportunity
to like at least okay marriage can do
either or
>> you know there I know it's sort of a
misnomer in y'all's world the risers
that we talk about in the media it's
normally just us catching up to what
y'all are already doing. Um but somebody
who's viewed as a riser at least for the
analysts was Malachi Lawrence. Can you
just talk about the process of like when
you guys first became aware of him and
and how you guys graded him throughout
the process? I'll give uh Eric
Ellingworth, our Southeast scout, a
bunch of credit cuz Central Florida Rosa
one visit school like we they didn't
have a whole lot of like draftable guys
and and after October we meet we kind of
go through hey how's your season going?
He's like blinking light we need to get
somebody else in there because of
Malachi Lawrence. So Chris Vaughn goes
down there and is like oh my god like
this guy is unbelievable. So like really
like from November on like we had him in
really in the top two rounds. So, and
then through the process, I mean, just
crushed it at the East West. Obviously,
the combine was unbelievable. And then
just when we got CP, just the the way
that everything came together. And then,
you know, our pass rush specialist, we
hired BT Martin, who and I mean, he's
unbelievable. And everyone just kind of
said, "Hey, like this is this guy is
checking every one of these boxes, and
the character is great." Um, so yeah,
that that was kind of it. You don't want
to see guys like who ascend through the
season but then also ascend through the
spring and he did that. You know
>> you mentioned that having some
linebackers that could do a little bit
of both. Maris being one of them. Jan
Barum Brian Seimer said yesterday he's
going to start at inside when you
watched his tape and it was inside. What
did you like about where he played
there?
>> Oh the physicality and the speed and
athleticism. Like I went back and
watched all of 24 he started inside
backer but I mean he's 240 lbs long arms
and he's nasty, you know, and he's got
ability to pressure the quarterback. He
can blitz. He actually in coverage he's
for his size he's really good. So I mean
going back there like okay week three
after week three they move him to edge
really just to get their best 11 on the
field. But yeah he he's got he's got all
the tools to play linebacker.
>> Walk us through the process of the draft
when you don't expect to be picking on
day two and then about a month out the
OSA trade happens. You pick up number
92. Does that change the process at all
or because y'all are so stuck to the
process over the course of the last
couple days that you've been here you're
ready for it?
>> Oh we're ready? Yeah. I mean, we're
just, hey, we're just getting these guys
right, trying to make sure we have all
the coaches watch the right guys. We got
our cross checkers on the right guys
like, but we Yeah, it doesn't really
change our process.
>> So, for a guy like Malachi Lawrence,
let's say in January compared to
yesterday, how many guys in your
scouting department watch that specific?
>> Seven, I would say, like between Well, I
bet we have seven grades between Will, a
position coach, and then with our staff.
Yeah.
>> Very cool. Very cool.
>> That's awesome. Mitch, thanks so much
for taking some time and kicking us off
the right way. Yeah, let's go, baby.
This is awesome.
>> It's gonna be fun today. I mean, we've
been pretty fortunate. I mean, Chris
Cany, Marian Barber, we we've went
through I showed Jerry. I was kind of
talking through all our fourth rounders,
but we've had some really good players.
>> Starting quarterback right now.
He was He was pretty good.
>> Not bad, man. Tony Pardon. Good point.
No doubt. Mitch Le Point, director of
college scouting, joining us here on the
draft show. Mitch, thanks so much.
>> Yeah, thank you guys.
>> Appreciate it. All right, we're going to
cycle these out back and forth. We got a
couple other interviews throughout the
day and and we'll continue to talk to
the coaching staff, talk to the scouting
department, and the ones that are making
the decisions in that Cowboys war room
with each one of these picks. The next
gentleman up is one of our favorites.
He's been on the show a couple times
already. This is national scout Ross
Winchie, uh, who's stepping in. Oh, he's
got a sweet shirt on, too.
>> Watch the Watch the condensation. It
just got you.
>> It just got you on the shirt. We got a
little AC issue going on in here. It's
been going on all week and Bobb's been
sitting in that chair so he's been
>> I deserved it.
>> Yeah, it could be a little gross.
>> What's going on, Ross?
>> Not much.
>> How uh how has this week turned out
based on your expectations going into
it?
>> Uh what? So, today's Saturday? Um it's
gone well. Uh yeah, I mean, three guys,
um all three will play for us. All three
have chances to be difference makers. Um
we've been active. Uh it's been awesome.
Haven't had to panic. Haven't had to
reach for anybody. Um Thursday was fun.
It was uh it's very active. Um
I've never I mean this is my 14th year
here and I've never seen a room so
excited for a player when we took Caleb.
>> Wow. Yeah. And that includes the I guess
the virtual draft in my wife. Oh, she
was big that I somebody asked me the
same question. When have you seen that
type of reaction? I was like, I think CD
would have had that reaction.
>> My wife brought that up. So, she's very
pregnant and I couldn't go to sleep.
Um, and so I'm rambling about, you know,
how much fun we were having and I was
like, "That's the most excited I think
we've ever been." She's like, "What
about CD?" And I was like, "Well, we
were all
>> Mhm.
>> at our homes, you know, watching that uh
>> on our laptops and stuff." So, it's a
little different, but yeah, that was it
was unreal, man. So, Is is that why is
it the big celebration for downs? Is
that why you're wearing the glitzy watch
today?
>> Yeah. So, uh yeah, this is my grandpa's
Rolex. I wear it on special occasions.
>> That's awesome.
>> Um yeah, CP is a a huge watch guy. So,
um watches and shoes are his things and
so I kind of let him know um when was
that draft dinner that I'd be wearing it
and I showed him uh you know Thursday.
It's Yeah, it's a heirloom for us. It's
really cool. So, I wear it this weekend.
I wear special occasions, but yeah, it's
it's a Caleb DS watch, I guess. Now,
>> Caleb D watch.
>> Will was saying last night that Caleb
popped on his radar when he's a true
freshman at Alabama. When did he come
onto your radar? And what separates him
from some of the other safeties that you
guys have had graded high, maybe not
that high in recent years?
>> Well, I'm an Aggie, so unfortunately I
saw him make a lot of plays against us
as a freshman at Alabama. But um
he's probably the most complete one I've
watched. Um
the instincts are elite. Um what's makes
him so different is just like he erases
the middle of the field. Uh the hashes
are where he is such a threat. Um and I
I just think it's it's it's very
dangerous and we can play him from the
nickel. Um CP's vision for him is really
cool. Um in base he can play too high.
We can rotate um off rotation. I mean
he's his ability to insert from depth,
fill a B gap. I mean he's just he's a
freak. And the the wiring of how we're
trying to build our team culture-wise.
Um he checks that box tfold. So
>> when when he's talked he's talked about
how instinctual he feels like he is and
you know everything everybody says about
him. He's always a step ahead in the
football IQ. When you're watching film
on a player, regardless of position,
what what is it that you see on tape
that makes you right, hey, this guy is
really smart?
>> Um, that's a good question. I think in
the college game, it's it's a lot
probably easier maybe in the the pro
game because I think there's so much
conflict that they're put in constantly
uh RPO game. Um,
uh, quick action stuff. Um there's a lot
of eye manipulation and just seeing like
you know single puller it's probably BS
double puller you know there's something
to you like stuff like that like there's
a lot of eye candy in college that I
think um a highly instinctive player can
you know snip out really quickly and
that's one thing he does. Um,
uh, yeah, that's that's probably the
easiest part of it is just, you know,
seeing what's going on and what's what
they're trying to do behind that, if
that makes sense.
>> I I'm I'm curious. This is feels like
such a pivotal draft for you guys, just
where you're at with team building. You
hire a new defensive coordinator, all
new defensive staff, and it just feels
like a really tight time frame to figure
out, all right, what do these guys need?
How did you guys manage to accelerate
getting on the same page with the
defensive staff and knowing what they
need? Shotty and Will do a great job
with that. Uh we call it our across the
hall meeting. It's a long um one or two
days usually where we just sit there and
like we present um we show them what we
do.
>> Uh give them a respect for how much time
we spend on the road. Um how much time
we spend on an individual player and um
show them, you know, what areas we hit,
colleges, all that. And then vice versa.
They show us traits they're looking for
in players and then they tie it to the
tape so we can see it like that. And
then couple weeks ago, uh CP gave us uh
we sat down with Will and gave us about
an hour of just like watching some of
the tape he had at Philly and we just
watched you know basic down a distance
like I mean he was teaching us like it's
day one install. He's like, "Hey, you
know, it's first and 10. This is the
call." And then we're looking at the
front structure and then we're walking
through the play and he brings it to
life of like, "Hey, this is why we're
looking for this. This is why we're
looking for that." Um, so it's just
really cool. Like he's um that entire
staff, man. Like they grind. Um Shotti's
done a great job putting it's it's so
you know, we work so well together.
>> Raj, you mentioned CP's got a really
cool vision for for Caleb DS. Could you
elaborate on some of that vision and
maybe not just for Caleb, but the other
two players that you drafted as well?
>> Uh yeah, I mean he's just um I think
Will said it yesterday, multiplicity. Um
that that'll be Caleb. Um and then not
just him, it'll be, you know, all those
defensive back pieces. Um I don't think
we're going to take just one that can do
one specific thing. Um because injuries
happen and we want to be as versatile as
possible. like um I think if you go back
and watch
um Philly over the past couple years,
they've played boundary and field,
they've played left and right. Um and
that's corners, that's safeties. Um they
they they they can do a lot and will be
able to do a lot. And I think that's the
same thing with We were all juiced up
about Jan.
>> Yeah.
>> Um Jan's going he can play inside, he
can play outside. Um
>> I think Will made the Arll Reese comp
and it's there's a lot to it. Yeah.
>> Um I I don't think a inside backer
projection is anywhere near reach. I
think that kid can play it.
>> Um
>> and I I think he can bring a juice
element. We're going to go penny looks.
Any five down looks is going to cause
hell. Um he he's a he's a really really
really cool pickup.
>> Will was saying on Thursday night that
the first time that he had watched
Malachi Lawrence was in November. And I
know first round picks that can pop up
at any time. Is this probably the latest
one that you think has developed for you
guys over the last dozen years or so?
>> I don't think so. Um like when we just
get like you know some of these guys I'm
just a pure film evaluator and like it's
like one of those tape and I call CV and
it's kind of the same thing like with
Will. It's just like like who is this
guy and like we just it was like one of
those early ones where we kind of
identified him you know once the tape's
in and like Eric did a great job of like
hey you know this guy's got some stuff.
CV went in there he echoed that
sentiment and we just kind of like hey
let's let's watch this kid. He did a
good job out here and uh we just stayed
on him, brought him in for 30, all that.
>> Can you talk about the collaborative
process of y'all's department
specifically and how y'all maybe do
things a little bit differently than
other teams?
>> Yeah. Um there's a um
it's it's a lot of work for us, but it's
it's a very thorough process and we
continue to, you know, adjust it every
year, but we start in
the summer when we have our summer
project of like, hey, you know, we're
going to watch a certain amount of
players and then when we head off to
camp, we're a one draft class team. We
focus on, you know, that single draft
class and we're thorough as hell about
it. Um, and that goes up until we lock,
you know, our our laptops in March and
April and when we were freaking grinding
the meetings. Um, so everybody's focused
on that. We're not talking about next
year's quarterback class. Like we don't
we don't care. That's for next year. So
we're just we're strictly focused on
what we're doing. Obviously, we're like
very well aware of who's coming down the
pipe. Caleb DS. Like we know the guys.
Like we're it's very easy to see who
pops on tape, but we're trying to figure
out who helps the Cowboys this year. So
that's that's kind of how we do things.
>> You know, there was a lot of talk about
positional value this year. Does a
safety have to be more than a safety to
go as high as Caleb DS does?
>> I think that's a good question. Um
I would say yeah, but like
yeah, I just think Caleb's he's unique,
man, because he's you can't put him in a
box really. Like I think he could play
corn if you had to. Like he's just he's
elite, man. like he's he's a very very
unique football player. Um there's a
reason we all went I mean I I'm sure the
mic you know probably had to bleep out
some there was we it was it was elite.
He's a he's a he's a game changer. So
yeah.
>> Yeah. Appreciate you stepping by Ross.
It's always great talking with you and
and congratulations on your rise as
well. You're you're just continuing to
take steps up and up and we can see it
every single year. you make an impact
for this football team in a very
positive way.
>> Appreciate you.
>> Ross Winy joining us here on the draft
show. We have to step aside. We have
more interviews coming your way,
including linebackers coach Scott Simons
joining us here in a matter of moments.
You're listening to the 2026 NFL draft
on the Dallas Cowboys radio network and
on DallasCowboys.com.
>> Made me get a text message about going
too long past our break.
>> I'm sorry.
>> It's okay.
>> Was that from Peyton? It was a good
question. No, if it's Peyton, don't
worry about it. It was not from Peyton.
Actually, it was from
Bobby.
>> Bobby,
>> what's going on, Scott? Good to see you,
man.
>> Hey, man. Great to see you.
>> Yeah, absolutely.
>> So, we've got we've got a uh we're in
the middle of a commercial break, Scott,
right now on the radio side, but on the
internet side, we're live on the air
currently. Uh but we'll we'll introduce
you here, and then you're going to hear
some music in your headphones here in a
minute, and then we're going to be back
on the radio side. So, just pretend like
it's not there and then we'll we'll
reintroduce you again. It's really
confusing for a little bit here, but
Scott Scott Simons, linebackers coach
for the Dallas Cowboys and a former
defensive coordinator for the SM
Mustangs. And you're a Dallas guy. What
has this process been like, your first
draft with your hometown team and then
you end up getting a couple guys that
are going to play for you as well?
>> Yeah, it's been uh been awesome. Been a
really exciting experience um just
coming in. First off, a lot of guys
that, you know, I had a chance to meet
over the years from uh Mitch to Chris
Vaughn uh on the personnel side of
things. So, there were a lot of guys
that I was already famili familiar with
just from them looking at guys that
we've had different places in the past.
Um so, that from that standpoint, that
was an easy transition. And then, you
know, just jumping into u you know,
evaluations, which is obviously u you
know, similar to the the college
standpoint when you're evaluating. I
mean, you're not watching uh quite as
grainy huddle film like you are. Um so,
so that's a positive, but uh going
through that process and just kind of
changing your lens a little bit on how
you look at players and um you know,
been really fortunate. JJ Clark's our
assistant linebackers coach, uh was here
last year and so we've been u you know,
we try to be really really thorough from
our input and our evaluations and and
getting to know these guys uh as we've
gone through the process. So, uh, yeah,
obviously growing up here, it's it's a,
uh, you know, surreal, uh, deal for me,
but, uh, ball is ball, and I'm excited
to to be here and, uh, be working with
the guys that we have.
>> Did you notice any advantage when you
were doing your player evals from having
just been at SMU and maybe you coached
against some of these guys? You got the
game plan for some of these guys.
>> Yeah, there's a lot of guys that that,
uh, that we knew pretty well in the
process. um either through high school
recruiting um you know whether it be you
know like uh um guys that were local
here, Texas guys in the state, guys that
we had seen to your point that we'd
played against um and then even guys
like on our roster you know Justin Baron
who was in the ACC right so um you know
I think I made a comment early on like
Shamar James guy that coached him
actually ged for me back in the day so
there was a lot of uh good carryover
from that standpoint uh which you know I
definitely think you
uh helps when you're going into this
process.
>> Scott, you correct me if I'm wrong, but
I think your first year as DC at SMU,
you played against Dwyers. What did you
remember about him that year? And now
you get to coach him. What What's that
going to be like, you think?
>> Yeah, he was uh he was very disruptive.
Um you know, extremely athletic
linebacker. Uh you could tell he was the
leader of their defense. Um Joe
Gillespie, who was their DC at the time,
uh has become a good friend. Um, and so,
uh, this is a this is a process that,
you know, like like we said, it's been
kind of going on for some time, uh, to
to try to, uh, make this happen. And,
uh, and I've been a huge advocate for
it. I just think when you look at the
production that he had this last year,
his ability to run, his ability to
cover, uh, the multiplicity, uh, that he
brings to the table, um, and what it
what it does to that room is is really
exciting for us. So, um, you know, feel
feel really good. I know he was really
excited when we got on the phone
yesterday. He said he just built a house
in in Arlington. So, um you know, I
think it's a u you know, really good
opportunity for him and good opportunity
for us to to add a a veteran guy that's
got really good experience and
production last year.
>> Linebacker light.
>> I'll go.
>> This is the reset.
>> Welcome to radio, Scott.
Welcome back into our day three coverage
of the 2026 NFL draft. We are now
catching up with linebacker's coach for
your Dallas Cowboys, Scott Simons.
Bobby, take it away.
>> Yeah. Uh, Scott, um, you know, the
linebacker, it feels like it looks
different for every scheme in terms of
like just the particulars they look for.
So, you walking into this, what would
you say like checks the box for you of
like that's the kind of linebacker that
I need. These are the traits that I
need. I need you to be able to do this.
>> Yeah. First off, it's physicality. Uh, I
I just think it's hard to coach a guy
that's willing to put his face on
somebody over and over again. Uh, that's
a mindset. That's an attitude, I think.
Um, so that's the number one thing is I
want to see is when we look at
linebackers, guys, they're going to play
downhill, going to be physical. Uh, and
then I think you look at instincts and
diagnostics next. You know, what's their
FBI? Um, and then from there, you know,
obviously you go into the traits, right?
Arm length, speed, size for the
position, uh, etc. We look at, you know,
pass rush ability, where does he add
value in that? That's a little bit more
down the line. And then, you know,
lastly is kind of ball disruption, guys
that are able to get the ball uh back.
Uh guys that are be able to for force
fumbles and and then within that in this
position, I think it's really important
to look at just, you know, the overall
alpha mentality. You know, I think um
you know, all guys don't have to be the
same. You can have two different
linebackers on the field. Um but you got
to have guys that have strong leadership
qualities. Um you know, I think much has
been made about Green Dot. And um that's
kind of one of the things that that that
we talked about. But I think these guys
are a little bit more exposed now to it.
It's not coming to the NFL where it's
all new. Um, so even though, you know,
you might have had, I mean, we had
safeties in practice that had green
dots, you know what I mean? Just because
it was like, okay, if this guy and this
guy goes down, who's the next best
option for us in that situation? Never
did it in a game. Um, but so I think
those guys are a little bit more um,
exposed to that process in college now,
which I think helps. So, if we don't
quote unquote have a green dot guy, you
know, at the end of the day, we would
rather have the best football players we
can on the field and uh and then make it
work from there and that's our job as
coaches, making sure we can get him
coached up to to handle that uh that
extra pressure of wearing the mic and
getting us lined up.
>> You talk about just kind of the roller
coaster of the off season of hey, you
you target a couple guys in free agency,
it doesn't work out for you, but you
guys don't panic. You you'll sit and
evaluate the market and then you get a
good guy like D Winters yesterday. just
overall looking at the totality of it
and how it worked out for you guys.
>> Yeah, I think um you know uh being
patient is key and I think uh going
through your process is is really
important. You we we had some guys that
that uh that we really liked and um and
we swung at and for whatever reason
didn't didn't work out. Um but not not
reaching I think is really important.
And um you but even backing up you know
the three guys that I've had an
opportunity to interact with uh with
Justin Shamar and Demo um you know over
the last couple months um you know I'm
really excited about the guys that we
that we currently have and then really
excited about the two guys that that you
know we've added to this room uh from a
culture standpoint, from a character
standpoint, from a leadership
standpoint. Um you know I think I think
we we we definitely have a really good
foundation to build on in there. So, um,
you know, I think not panicking and and
and just making, uh, good levelheaded
decisions and not reaching is really
important in this process. And I think
we did a good job of that. And I think
that that that starts from, um,
ownership and and our head coach all the
way down.
>> Scott Simons, linebackers coach and
former defensive coordinator at at SMU.
This is your first year back in the the
pro ranks, but what is the biggest
difference for you making the jump from
college to the NFL? cuz you're running
the show as the defensive coordinator in
a a power four program at SMU. Then you
you jump to a position group position
coach level here at the college or at
the pro level. What is the biggest
difference in your eyes?
>> Yeah. Um I mean first off, my job is to
make sure that you know our linebackers
uh are playing at an elite level and one
of the best linebacker cores in the
country and uh you know uh to to to make
Christian Parker's job easy, you know,
and so I'm excited about that. That's
one thing when had the opportunity to to
come in and interview for this that that
coach asked me and you know I said I've
coordinated for you know 13 or 14 of the
last 15 years and you know I'm kind of
excited to not have to do it for a year
or two and just be able to get focused
on helping us build this thing uh and in
Christian's vision for it. So um you
know all in all I think it's been it's
been a really a really clean uh
transition. you know, it's new
nomenclature, new terms, you know, uh
maybe a little bit new new systems that
I hadn't been or hadn't been in in a
while. Uh but, you know, football is
still football and there's um you know,
Christian's got a lot of great ideas
that are blended from from different
places that he's been. And so, um just
coming in and trying to trying to add
value where I can, but make sure
ultimately that like I said, Coach Clark
and I do uh the best job possible, you
know, developing the guys that we have
in our room. you've obviously got, you
know, linebackers that you're working
with, but with Caleb DS being the topic,
how exciting is it for you when you
obviously have seen him do stuff with
the line of scrimmage, you're like, man,
I'm really excited that he's going to be
in here in the box with us doing some
stuff.
>> Yeah, I I think, you know, backing up
first, like when you watch this system
and you look at what Coupe has done in
Philly and and you see the versatility
of him. Now, I know he was playing, you
know, outside lane corner in nickel, but
you see what he did, you know, in the
nickel spot. And then you look at Caleb
and you see the vision for what he's
going to be able to do in a similar type
of role in this system and and know that
that was, you know, a big area that we
wanted to to get a playmaker at. And uh
so, um, you know, I think we're as
excited as everybody, you know, in the
Metroplex is right now that we're able
to get the the top guy on our board. And
uh you know I I think uh like growing up
here obviously you know I got to I got
to watch one of the greatest safeties
that that's ever played you know and and
so you know even seeing that tweet you
know that that he put out there or
whatever like you know to have an impact
guy like that um is a big deal. So um
definitely excited about it.
>> Well we appreciate you stopping by and
sharing a little bit of that insight and
knowledge. We're excited to see how you
do coach up the the linebacker room in
your first year here. We're excited to
have you and as a Dallas guy as well.
That that always adds a little extra to
it. Scott Simons joining us here on the
draft show. Scott, thanks so much.
>> Appreciate it, guys. Thank you. Thanks,
Scott. There he goes.
>> I want to emphasize he's Tarant County.
>> Oh, okay. So, I shouldn't say down.
That's a good point. Thank you.
>> DFW.
>> I coach I coach for the Mustangs.
>> Yeah, that's true.
>> But I but I coach a Horn Frog now.
>> Yeah, there you go. Good stuff. Thanks,
Scott. Appreciate you, man.
>> Thank you. We're now welcoming in
Dimmitri Brim, the assistant defensive
line coach for the Dallas Cowboys. It's
my first time getting to meet Coach
Brim. What's going on, man? Good. How
are you?
>> Hey, coach.
>> And this is uh this is going to be
interesting because Nick,
>> this is his first year with the Dallas
Cowboys as well. He also comes from the
collegiate ranks. Yes, sir.
>> And his most recent stop was with the
UCF Golden Knights down there in
Orlando, Florida, where he coached one
Malachi Lawrence.
>> You don't say.
>> You don't say. You've you've already had
one big win under your belt now on draft
weekend. What tell us take us through
really the relationship you have with
Malachi and what that moment was like
getting to hear his name called.
>> Uh absolutely man. Well, it was a team
win for us, you know, for the
organization. Um and then obviously
having the opportunity to be there with
Malachi UCF last year, that was a good
thing for us or for myself. Um great
kid, man. Works hard. you know, we was
only in the building, you know, I was
only in the building for a year with
Malikai, but even in that year, you can
tell, you know, how special, how
different he was, you know, and kind of,
you know, the way that he approached
practice, the way that he went about his
business as far as attacking game days
on Saturdays and whatnot. So, really
excited to have him part of our
organization. I think he'll really help
us out.
>> He talked about it a little bit
yesterday in his welcome press
conference or just even the the day as a
whole, but about his loyalty to UCF, all
four years there in Orlando. you had
just the one year with him, but he said
you made quite the impact on it. What
was your first interactions with him and
and then what was uh what were some of
the things that you were telling this
Cowboy staff about him in the draft
process?
>> Yeah, well for me it was a little bit
more personal just because I played at
UCF as well. So being able to get into
the building with him and you know kind
of tell him you know what the program
means to us and a lot of other former
you know alumni that was in the building
coaching last year you know we was able
to kind of build that relationship off
of that you know and I think obviously
with me being a former player and a kind
of a younger coach in that sense as far
as you know being the coach Mike Dawson
who was his position coach um great
coach as well um but you know it was
good just to be able to get around him
and you know and kind of tell him you
know what we expect of him and you know
spend a lot of time with him you know
just breaking down film you know trying
to show him how to, you know, to be
successful on Saturday as far as his
rush plans and all that stuff. But, you
know, he he means a lot to me as well,
you know, just the brotherhood that we
have being UCF Knight. So, really
excited to give get him part of this
organization.
>> Coach, you mentioned the rush plan and
and Malachi was one of my favorite edge
rushers in this class because some just
have god-given athletic traits, right?
But he's got a plan. He's got multiple
tools in his belt. What stands out to
you about his game?
>> Yeah, man. I'll be honest with you. His
his ability to get, you know, off the
ball, number one. You know, his first
step is very impressive. Then obviously
his ability to change directions as well
as a rusher. You know, he has a plan.
You know, if his first move doesn't
work, he always got a plan to go to the
second move. You don't see a lot of
those things out of past rushers. Um
especially, you know, at the collegiate
level, you know, sometimes the
development piece is not there. Um even
at that level, but with him, man, he
just he's a a motor, man. He just keeps
going. And it's credit to him. It is
God-given ability because we ain't born
like that. I didn't have those traits
when I played, you know, in college. So,
Coach Chid, you know, I can't wait for
him to get with Coach Jadera, you know,
to be able to kind of, you know,
continue to develop that as well as, you
know, Coach BT.
>> What do you remember the uh the first
time that somebody on the scouting staff
or personnel department, anybody came up
to you and said, "Hey, tell us a little
bit more about Malachi and and what did
you tell them?"
>> Yeah. Um, I think uh for the most part,
you know, Coach Shotti want to make sure
that there's good people in the building
um more than anything. So, it's mostly
about his character, who he was as a
person um before the player as well,
just to make sure that he fits into this
family as far as what we're trying to
build here and continue to build here.
Um so, it's from a character standpoint,
I say, you know, you won't have any
problems with the kid, man. That he
loves football. He loves being around
the building. Everybody loved him at UCF
from athletic director down, you know,
to the uh people that was in the
classrooms and stuff with him. So, great
kid, man. Just really just talked about
his character and who he was as a
person. He showed up every single day,
you know, he worked hard. he did the
things that we asked of him when we got
to UCF. So, you know, we really held a
high standard for him and that was a
guy, you know, that could have left UCF
that could have entered the transfer
portal and all that type of stuff. He
ended up staying and it was a guy if he
had another year, he would have been on
the top of the list for us to bring
back. So, you know, he's a really really
good kid, man, and can't wait to work
with him.
>> He had a phenomenal draft process. I I
think it even exceeded his own
expectations. I had asked him yesterday,
hey, when you declared, where did you
think you could maybe go like best case
scenario? He was like, man, third round
would have been great. uh for you, when
did it kind of flip for you that like,
hey, man, not only could this kid be a
firstrounder, but this team I'm at now
might be able to take him.
>> Yeah, absolutely, man. I'll be honest
with you. So, I obviously just leaving
UCF, you know, I was still in the
collegiate ranks, but I had a uh very
close relationship with Chris Vaughn. Um
he recruited me when I was coming out of
high school as well. So, he came down to
UCF and, you know, came to one of our
practices. He was like, "Hey, like they
sent me down to see this guy and I was
like, CV, man, this this guy's a real
guy. like he's a dude, you know, and you
know, we coached at Nebraska for 5
years. Like we've been around, you know,
some very good players, you know, in
this league and whatnot. So, he was one
of those guys that stood out the most.
So, you know, it was just really good,
you know, to kind of, you know, be able
to speak highly of him and um, you know,
and kind of bring his name to the table
and and kind of confirm what the scouts
has already seen here, you know, once
they evaluated his film.
>> Assistant defensive line coach Dmitri
Brim joining us here on the draft show.
We've got to take a break on the radio
side, but you're cool sticking around
for a little bit more. All right. We
appreciate you as always. Once again,
you're listening to the 2026 NFL draft
on the Dallas Cowboys Radio Network and
DallasCowboys.com.
>> There's the voice. It's stay. You heard
it there for a second. It's already
starting to go. We got seven hours of
radio left.
>> We're also listening to Kyle's voice
break.
>> Yeah, that was tough.
>> Coach, I I wanted to ask you about
competition level. That that comes up a
lot this time of year. And you being a
UCF guy, have you had to fight like now
UCF's in the Big 12, right? So, you are
playing against I think higher
competition. Texas Tech went to the
playoff this year, but for for over the
years, like has that been something
you've had to fight for some of these
guys? Like that doesn't matter. My guys
are good. Just so you know, we're still
live on the internet side. Just so you
know, this is still a live interview.
>> Absolutely. Thank you. Oh man, to be
honest with you, I I think that's
something that UCF players have always
had to fight. You know, even when I
played there and even before myself, um
when I played there, we was in the
American Athletic Conference. So, I
imagine somebody like himself now being
drafted and being American Athletic
Conference team, there will be even more
questions in comparison to it being a
Big 12 team. Um, you know, but I think
once you know talent, you know talent,
you know, and at the end of the day, you
can see those traits show up no matter
who you're playing against. Now, it's
one thing if you're, you know, watching
a kid on film play against lesser
competition. I'm not going to name a
school. I'm not going to, you know, cuz
I coach at FCS schools and all that
stuff as well, but you can see the the
difference as far as, you know, guys, as
far as their traits and how it shows up.
And I think that's one thing about him.
It shows up against the the teams and
some of the top teams that we played in
the Big 12. And you know, it's it's a
competitive league. You know, it's a
very competitive league. Obviously, a
power four um program. Um and and just
continue to grow. But there's a lot of
guys that came from UCF before um
Clayton Gathers, American Athletic
Conference, uh Kamal Ishmamail, like
Brashard Pman, like there's a lot of
guys that had success in the NFL from
UCF before it got to the Big 12. And you
know, so we we pride ourselves in being
that program that's always kind of, you
know, doubted and shadowed a little bit,
but guys continue to show up and be, you
know, the alpha males and, you know,
competitive guys at the next level.
>> How about your journey here going from,
like you said, those FCS schools, you
played in or you coached in the Patriot
League, you go to the American
Conference, and then now you're you're
the assistant defensive line coach for
the Cowboys and the brand that it has,
but then you look up and you get to see
guys like Quinnon Williams and Kenny
Clark that are under your toutelage. I
mean, what is that like for you making
that jump and getting to coach some of
those veterans in the room?
>> Absolutely, man. I'm very grateful. Um,
it took a long time to get here, man.
And it took a lot of patience to be
honest with you. And, you know,
sometimes I sometimes I didn't have the
patience and sometimes I wanted to kind
of stop, you know, in my process and my
journey, but just incredibly grateful,
you know, for having this opportunity.
Uh, Coach Dixon, you know, being able to
kind of bring my name, help bring my
name to the table as well. I interned
with the Minnesota Vikings in 2024, so
that's where the connection came with
him. And then I obviously uh work with
Ryan Feeder at Nebraska. So just having
some of those connections, you know,
maybe helped me out a little bit, but
it's a blessing, man. So now, you know,
being able to kind of be in the same
room as Q Will and Casey, all those
guys, man, it's it's going to be
something for me. It's going to be a
development piece for me as well. I'm
going to learn a lot from those guys and
looking forward to, you know, helping
them. And then, you know, the tables
being turned a little bit and them
helping me as well.
>> Going back to Malachi real quick, you're
a UCF guy. You clearly have a lot of
pride in your alma mater. He's the
highest UCF defensive draft pick in
school history. How much pride do you
take in that?
>> It's a lot. It's a It's a lot, man. It's
uh you know, there's been a lot of great
players that's come from UCF, especially
on the defensive side of the ball. Um I
think, you know, being an American, even
when I played there, we had one of the
top defenses before we kind of got
exposed at the end of the season. But as
far as just, you know, just having
talented guys, um you know, he's one of
those guys for sure. And one thing about
us, you know, former players being at
UCF, we always say like if we look at a
player and we say like, hey, like this
guy could have played with us, like
that's how you know it's a kind of real
thing. And Malachi was never, you know,
without a question of doubt like a guy
that I always say like you could have
been my teammate and we would have did
this thing and rocked out together. So
very proud of him, man, and very proud
of what he's, you know, mean to UCF. And
I'm glad, you know, especially in the
the uh culture or the world of college
football now that he stayed around and
was able to kind of finish his career
out there through the adversity and then
obviously, you know, him being blessed
with the opportunity to have be a first
round pick.
>> How would you evaluate because I've been
fighting with people about him as a run
defender? I think he's better than
people are giving him credit for. How do
you evaluate his run defense?
>> Yeah, I would agree with that. Um he
definitely, you know, he can he can stop
the run. He he's he'll be used obviously
to be able to play the zone read, being
able to play the the surf technique, the
chasing the quarterback out to the
perimeter, but I think he's physical as
well. Um, you know, there's tools that
he still needs to refine and get uh get
developed that um and strengthen and he
knows that as well. Um, so that's what
coaches are here for. So, you know, just
it's going to be a, you know, good
opportunity for all of us to be able to
kind of get around him and, you know,
kind of refine those things to to make
him the best version of himself.
>> So, we're going to come back on the
radio side of things here in about 30
seconds. We're going to go ahead and say
goodbye to you here. We appreciate you
stopping by. It's been great catching up
with you, getting to learn about you a
little bit.
>> Likewise. Appreciate it. Thank you.
>> Demetri Brim, the assistant defensive
line coach for your Dallas Cowboys
joining us here on the draft show. When
we come back on the radio side here in a
moment, we're going to catch up with
college scout Brett Maxi who was one of
the scouts that helped bring Caleb DS.
>> Yeah, a lot of good stuff.
>> It is. Appreciate it. Thank you. I'll be
honest with you, I didn't enjoy.
>> All right. Welcome back into our 2026
NFL draft coverage on the Dallas Cowboys
radio network and on dallascowboys.com.
We've got about 20 minutes remaining
until the start of the fourth round
where your Dallas Cowboys have three
different picks. They pick at 112, 114,
and 137. We're still catching up with
both the coaching staff and the scouting
staff for your Dallas Cowboys. We're
going to hear from Brett Maxi, college
scout, here in just a matter of moments
as he walks into the door right on time.
>> Got a a great look to him. He looks like
he could still play right now.
>> Once again, alongside Bobby Belt, Tommy
Yarish, Nick Harris, Zack Walchuk, I'm
Kyle Yman. We'll be joined by Vach
Lombardi and Brian Bratis very quickly.
What's going on, Brett? How are you?
>> Outstanding. How are you doing?
>> Doing great. It was an exciting night on
Thursday for a lot of people. Uh
throughout the the the draft process,
Caleb DS was always right at the top of
the list for for Cowboys fans as what he
could bring here to Dallas. You were one
of the the guys leading the charge on
scouting him over the last few years.
Tell us a little bit about what you saw
from Caleb and and why he fit so much
here with the the Cowboys.
>> Absolutely. How's everybody doing?
>> Fantastic.
>> Fantastic. Nice. Um yeah, so no, I was
part of it. Um, I wouldn't necessarily
say leading the charge, but uh
>> I'm trying to give you credit here.
>> No, I appreciate you. I've been I've
been in the school a couple times and uh
you're just asking about like what's uh
what's unique about his game and
>> and what we're excited about or what we
are excited about since he's going to be
with us now. Um
>> he's an extremely smart football player.
Uh cerebral to me, he's one of those
players that um as the game goes on,
he's just downloading what the offense
is doing. You know what I'm saying? And
so at some point he's going to make a
play and I think he displayed that uh
throughout his college career. And then
obviously like the athleticism
um some of the um the leadership that he
brought to Ohio State and even Bama when
he was there as a freshman. Uh I
remember Eric Ellingworth uh our
Southeast scout. He was telling me about
Caleb and how he was as a freshman and
just how unique he was and how mature he
was um uh as a person. Brett, you
mentioned the intelligence factor for
Caleb. When you're watching a player and
what is it on film that makes you write
down, hey, he's a smart football player.
When you see something, what is it in a
game setting where you can say, "Yeah,
he's one step ahead." Um I think at the
safety position uh and part of it's like
your play temperament of like how hard
you play in like your motor and stuff
like that but he's always around the
ball whether if he's playing from a
split if he's playing in the post um if
he's in short zones if he's in man
whatever he's doing he's always around
the ball and then you can just see him
react so quickly to things as well.
>> You talk about Jan Barum one of your
guys and uh the versatility that he
brings and just what you think about
overall.
>> Yeah man it's our guy now right? Yeah.
No, no, no. Um, yeah, Jon's uh really
cool, man. Um,
>> so what's impressive about Jan is that
>> this was like his first year actually
playing like edge rusher in college. And
so the first couple of games I I forget,
maybe it was like two or three or four
or whatever. Um, he's playing stacker
and that's what he did at Maryland two
years prior to Michigan. Played uh stack
backer in Michigan his third year and
then he started off his fourth year. Um
so to me and um this is kind of like
what we talked about is just the
versatility he's going to bring to us.
Um another guy who plays the right way
uh right and um he's physical uh violent
player um he can run uh he can just do a
lot of things and we think there's a lot
of upside there as well.
>> Brett I'm curious you know we Ross came
in here he talked about the across the
hall meetings and the different ways
that you guys get an idea of what the
coaching staff wants. When you've got a
guy like Barum who it's like he can do
multiple things. How does that
communication go with the coaching staff
of like, hey, uh, the guys who are in
charge of like what we're doing with our
pass rush and, you know, maybe coach
Simons, what we're doing with our
linebackers, I'm going to have to
communicate, you know, with with
everybody here on the idea of what this
vision might be.
>> Can you repeat that again?
>> The idea of like your communication with
the coaching staff and like what the
coaching staff wants. How is it with a
guy like Bar who can maybe come off the
edge or play stack backer like you were
talking about, how your communication
with the coaching staff and what their
vision is for those type of things? How
are you unifying those when you're
evaluating a player?
Um just like our relationship with the
coaches and like how they break it down
to us. Um yeah, so um those across the
hall meetings are vital to our process.
Um especially because we have um pretty
much like an entirely new defensive
staff, but um they let us know uh kind
of like what we're doing um what we're
looking for and then we go back in our
reports and then we can be like, "Okay,
he's able to do these the this thing,
this thing, this thing." And when we're
getting into meetings, then we can like
really shape it up um to okay, this guy
can do this for us.
>> You joined the the scouting department
back in in 2017. So you've been nearly a
decade with the
>> 2015 actually.
>> Okay. So you were interning in 2015,
right? And then it was
he has been here for more than a decade
then. That's that's incredible to think
about. How much
>> that's a blessing for sure. How much has
your development changed from a scouting
standpoint going from an intern level
into a full-time role and then now of
course having the the type of input that
you do?
>> Uh it's uh certainly been a journey to
say the least.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh it's been really cool. Um as cliche
as it is, it's um I have um incredible
people around me who have helped me so
much to get me to where I'm at today. Um
starting with my family, uh dad Moses,
mom Uh, Mama Maxi, Angela, my brother
Adam, who's a pro scout uh for the
Panthers. Um, and then my two lovely
sisters, Maya Maxi, who actually uh is a
pastry chef who works here.
>> Yeah. Didn't know that.
>> She's a beast. Yeah. And then Olivia
Maxi um who's just so awesome. And uh so
>> they're a huge help for me. And then
obviously like um a lot of people um in
our scouting department and then uh
coaches and just people around the
building. This is a a very very cool
place to work and I'm very fortunate to
be here.
>> You said your brother is a pro scout for
the uh for the Panthers. How much do you
still have a conversation or is it no
football whatsoever since it's techn?
No, that's my bro. That's my bro. We're
going to talk ball, you know.
>> Yeah. What What are some of the things
that you guys talk about?
>> I can't tell you all that.
>> I haven't seen me and bro me and bro.
No.
>> Will you ever ask your dad like if
you're looking at a guy like DS or
somebody else? Will you ever be like,
"Dad, what do you what do you think
about this guy playing in the second?
was so crazy. We were um I was watching
tape at my place and um I have this um
this cool little setup now. I'm proud of
it.
>> I'm proud of my little setup now.
>> Talk about it. I want I upgraded a
little bit. No, it's just it's just a
desk and then uh I have like a nice
little monitor and then uh I don't know.
It just it's just it's a lot more
comfortable to watch tape um for me when
I'm at home. But um I FaceTime my dad
and I was watching Caleb. I was like,
"Dad, like you got to watch this
player." and my pops played safety and
so um it's really cool to get his
insight because he's done it. Um and he
was, you know, really good at it too in
my opinion. Um so we were just watching
the tape. He's like, man, he plays fast.
He's around the ball. A lot of the
things that I was saying earlier,
there's so many fans of the draft and
that like, you know, you're surrounding
to find tape, whether it's watching on
YouTube or people listening. So for you,
like what's your process like as a pro
scout? What are you looking for when
you're watching these players and and
how maybe that's developed and changed
throughout the years, if at all?
>> You're talking about just like my tape
watching process. Okay. Uh, no, that's
interesting. Yeah. Um,
>> so I find that it's uh really important
to watch the tape and obviously like we
got to watch a lot of players, but um
when you're ready to watch the tape.
>> Okay.
>> So, I try to like leave as many biases
as I can outside of my um evaluation
process. Oh, there goes the drip. down
to the drip.
>> Um, so whether it's like I get a workout
before or get some food or um I like
take a nap. So maybe I'll get like a nap
in before just so I can give the player
the respect he deserves when I'm
watching the tape. Interesting.
>> And I think that's one thing that has
grown throughout my process.
>> Yeah.
>> So the mentals.
>> Absolutely. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. because
you're you're watching so many players
and so you want to try to give each
player um the same process if you can.
Obviously, it's a little different
because um you know I'll be on the road
and and things like that, but um yeah, I
try to make it work in that way.
>> You know, it's interesting talking about
that film watching process. I remember
um Daniel Jeremiah had said that
he typically at the start of the draft
season, he said he'll go back and he'll
watch the top players in the NFL to kind
of like recalibrate what the standard is
supposed to look like.
Do you have anything like that that you
do a refresher before I dive back into
this of like I I want to remind myself
what I'm looking for?
>> I think that's extremely important
because you I think you can get caught
into just watching um this is not bad,
but just watching the college players
and not knowing what's in the league.
Obviously, I'll watch our game tape, but
it's good to go back and check myself
and be like, "Oh, maybe I was a little
wrong in this guy," or, "Oh, maybe this
was this was good." So, yeah. Um we do
this cool thing in the preseason where
um we have preseason teams that were
assigned and we help out with the
process because cut down days there's so
many players
>> um
>> who are gone at one point or whatever um
or cut or whatever you want to call it
and um that's a really good opportunity
for us to be like okay let's see how
these guys are doing now you know and
we'll also do summer projects where
we'll we'll have a team we'll watch x
amount of players and then um just to
get our eyes on on pro players because I
think it's important when you when
you're watching college players, you got
to know like what's playing in the
league.
>> Brett Maxi, college scout, joining us
here from the Star in Fris, day three of
the NFL draft. We call it the day of the
scouts. What are you excited for as we
go into the three fourth round picks and
then you got one more waiting in the
second?
>> Who we taking?
>> Yeah, you know, you know I ain't about
to do that.
>> Um, uh, I'm just excited. Uh we we all
put a lot of work into this, so it's
going to be really cool just to see what
what comes uh what comes of this um
these last couple rounds.
>> Yeah. Well, we're wishing you the best
of luck up there in the war room.
Appreciate you taking some time sharing
some insight with us. We always love
catching up with you.
>> Yeah, I appreciate y'all.
>> Absolutely. Brett Maxi joining us here
on the draft show. Not sure that might
be the final interview we have today.
It's one of our favorite hours of the
entire radio calendar and we've had the
chance to catch up with plenty of
incredible uh members of that Cal Dallas
Cowboys front office and can't wait to
see what they do here on day three. We
are about 8 minutes away from the
beginning of the fourth round and then
it's going to really it's going to be
fast and furious from that point forward
because the Cowboys pick at 112, 114,
137 and then we might be sitting for a
little bit here. Uh good stuff as
always, Tommy. That that was that was
fun to hear.
>> This is the best.
>> This is my favorite part of day three.
Uh I really appreciate interview mech
uh YouTube's account Tommy Dallas.
Thanks guys.
>> Like I was saying this is my that's my
favorite part of of day three. You know
I I just have so much respect for the
work that will mle the scouting staff
here. really scouts everywhere uh across
the league put into to this process and
this is like you mentioned this is their
day because this is the culmination of
so many long hours, long nights, long
road trips where they're away from
family for so long. They clearly love
what they do. So, uh so much respect for
them and and their staff and getting to
talk to them, pick their brains is
awesome awesome opportunity for us. So,
I really appreciate those guys making
the time for that. anything stick out
based on the the interviews that we had
there, Nick, that that we want to try
and recap here for
>> Yeah, I thought it was really cool how
they identified Malachi Lawrence and
just the process behind that just
because that's not an easy eval. You
know, if you look at a guy and going
back to my days when I was doing um high
school scouting and it's late in the
recruitment process, you have this
player who just explodes as a senior.
How do you value that versus, you know,
four years of experience and four years
of proven, you know, quality? And you
have to figure out a level playing field
for what that looks like. And I I
thought they had a really interesting
process of like, okay, one scout sees
it, they send another scout down there
being like, hey, I'm not seeing this
wrong, right? Like, this is definitely a
huge huge guy we need to be making sure
we keep an eye on. Chris Vaughn goes
down there, backs up uh that thinking,
and then during the draft process, just
continues to rise and rise and and trust
their eval with it, and eventually
landing on Malachi Lawrence with a
number 23 overall pick. I think it's a
really cool behind thes scenes look at
just how much work goes into just one
player on in this stuff and these guys
look at nearly a thousand because they
have to factor in the undrafted free
agents. They have to factor in uh you
know day three guys and so uh credit to
those guys. They do a fantastic job and
uh they're looking to cap off a really
talented draft class here today.
>> Yeah, it is going to be a fun one. In
just a couple of moments we will have
the beginning of the fourth round. It is
the 2026 NFL draft. You're listening
live on the Dallas Cowboys Radio Network
and on dallascowboys.com.
All right, gentlemen. Just continuing
that conversation on the internet side
of things. Zach, what stood out to you
out of the the different interviews?
>> Yeah, I know Shotti alluded to it
yesterday in the post uh draft pressure,
but I mean, even Ross kind of
emphasizing it. Bar's clearly a guy that
they've view inside linebacker to me
right now. I mean that that's that's the
gauge I got and and I kind
>> Maxi talked about it today. He played
off ball at the at Michigan for a little
bit
>> and I like I love the versatility, but I
I loved his tape as an offball
linebacker and his blitzing ability and
the ability to close downhill and and
you talk about him being disruptive and
a defensive weapon. I mean, I think they
just added so much when it comes to
speed, but also physicality and attitude
and they they've talked about wanting to
get an identity. I think that starts
with your first pick in Caleb DS, but
with Malachi Lawrence and in and Barum
and now what you're able to do and being
multiple and him being able to line up
in multiple spots. But I I do like him
as an inside backer. I thought that was
his better position. Now, it is a little
unfair because he only played a year at
edge. So, could he get better at that
100%. But but I like the vision that
they've got for him right now.
>> Tommy, what were some of the highlights
for you? I really appreciated Ross's
answer when I asked him about, "Hey,
when you're watching a guy and and you
write down this guy's really smart, he's
an intelligent football player. He's a
step ahead of everybody else." What is
it that makes you say that? What do you
see that makes you say he's a smart
football player? And you know, we talked
a lot about college offenses going more
to RPO style things, quick game where
their quarterbacks are getting the ball
out quick and these speedy wide
receivers just kind of doing the rest
with it. seeing how defensive backs
react to that, how defenders react to
that, and um just the processing that
goes in such a quick amount of time.
That being such a big part of it, I
thought was very good insight to hear
about. And you know, hearing more about
why Jan Barum is viewed as an inside guy
versus an outside guy because Michigan
did move from out there and Wink
Martindale is an NFL guy, the defensive
coordinator over there at Michigan. So,
he certainly knows what the league is
looking for and knows what the league
values traits wise in these kinds of
players. So what what it was about Barum
that makes him an inside guy at least to
start hearing from Scott Simons and and
Brett Maxi about that I thought was very
interesting. So again that's part of the
awesome part about this. Really
appreciate those answers.
>> Yeah, thanks for for all the guys that
that were able to come down and and talk
for a little bit. We talked with Brett
Maxi, we talked with Ross Winchie, we
talked with Mitch Le Point, Scott
Simons, the inside linebackers coach,
and then assistant defensive line coach
Dmitri Brim as well. So, five great
interviews. We we were hoping to maybe
get Christian Parker on, but when
they've got three picks in coming up in
the next couple of minutes, uh they said
he was unavailable for uh latter part.
So, I get it. I guess we'll be okay.
He's trying to do his job and make this
football team better, which I think
they'll be okay with.
>> So, with that being said, it's about
time to get ready for drafting. Votch,
what are you looking forward to today?
And what do you think the Cowboys need
to come out with? me personally and they
don't care what I think. Uh, but I'm
thinking take these fours and keep
throwing darts at defense. Keep trying
to hit on those guys. Uh, do everything
in your in your power to make that side
of the ball good. I know at some point
we're going to have to talk about
offense. We're going to have to talk
about offensive line. Maybe uh tight end
could possibly come up in the
conversation. I know Cowboys seem to be
interested in wide receiver at at some
point, but I would hope that that's like
a sixround conversation or maybe
undrafted guys that they're maybe
looking at to come in and be a
developmental swing tackle maybe or
maybe like a fourth tight end. I still
think that defense is quite the
emergency. And I know that that they've
made a ton of moves. Adding Caleb DS
bump you up 30 points alone, but I still
think there needs to be some more darts
and depth is important. And if there is
anything that Cowboy fans may be still
upset about is like your your team's
unit. So a lot of these guys that should
be kickoff, kick return, punt return
guys. So let's go get them.
>> What do you think Dallas could be
looking at here, Nick?
>> Yeah, I'm curious about offensive line.
That's really what I'm looking at going
into these fourth round picks just
because uh Brian Shanheimer has talked
about not only the need for interior
depth with the loss of Brock Hoffman,
but competition at the tackle position
too. You know, whether that's for Nate
Thomas or even for Tyler Gayton or even
for Terrence Steel. And so, you know, if
there's a tackle that makes sense here
in the fourth round that could make
sense as a uh competition guy, um then
yeah, I would that's what I'm at least
peeling my eyes on here early. Remember,
the Cowboys do not have a pick in the
fifth or the sixth round. One more in
the seventh. So, these three picks,
yeah,
>> there's a lot of pressure on getting
these right.
>> Nick Harris, can I ask you a question?
>> Absolutely.
>> After that we get come back on the radio
cuz you don't have headphones on.
>> No, just ask it. No, I'm fine.
>> Well, you know,
as a matter of fact,
Oh yes, it is day three of the NFL draft
as we continue our coverage. All 257
picks. We are 100 picks down. We've got
157 to go over the next 6 hours. We've
already been on the air for an hour
talking to the Dallas Cowboys scouting
department and coaching staff. Special
thanks to Mitch Le Point, Brett Maxi,
Ross Winchie from the scouting side,
Scott Simons, the inside linebackers
coach, and Dmitri Brim, the assistant
defensive line coach on the coaching
side of things for chatting with us this
morning. Back with Tommy Yarish of
DallasCowboys.com, Nick Harris of the
Fort Worth Star Telegram, Zack Walchuk
of 1053 the fan, and now joined by Vach
Lombardi from YouTube and from
Crownglobal Media. I'm Kyleman of
DallasCowboys.com.
Vach, you were just about to ask a
question as we get set to begin the
fourth round of this year's draft.
>> Just some context for the radio folk. Uh
Kyle just kind of asked me, "Hey V, what
are we looking at?" And um I was of the
mindset of keep throwing darts on on
defense. And then we kind of talked
about maybe the Cowboys are looking for
offense. Well, what kind of made me
upset about it a little bit is I'm
looking at my board on defense
>> and defense is still quite the emergency
for the Dallas Cowboys. And and there's
a bunch of names that I like still. And
I was going to ask Nick Harris cuz he
kind of put me onto this player, Keith
Abney. I had a second round grade on him
corner. Why why in tarnation is he kind
of falling around into this range like
Wheatly and guys like that? Please Nick.
>> Yeah, that was one of the names that I
looked at last night. I was like, whoa,
why is he still on the board? Uh for me,
I have him a CB10 in the third, but
still I it's it's uh he's got the nickel
flexibility, physical corner, uh jams
guys off the line. I think some have the
play speed concerns. I don't necessarily
have those concerns, but the play speed
is something that's been brought up. Um,
and it's more of a footwork issue in my
eyes. And I think that could be easily
worked out with a technician who feels
good in development. And I think, you
know, if you're looking at a Christian
Parker, for example, I think he has that
development, you know, skin on the wall.
Um, yeah. Yeah. If you're curious of
like what some of that bad tape looks
like, look at the Houston game from last
year. But overall, I I think um I I
think Keith Abney should have gone
yesterday. I I will say though, there's
a lot of these corners that are still on
the board. There's a lot of defenders in
general. My top 10 available players in
the entire draft on my board are all
defenders. And so I I feel like I'm a
little bit higher on these defenders
than than I guess the rest of the league
is. It's either that or they're trying
to get the slim offensive talent while
they while they while they can in the
third round.
>> And and and see Nick, that's kind of my
problem. And just more context for the
radio people. It's like when you mention
what the Cowboys want in offense is like
a developmental swing tackle maybe or
like a wide receiver forward to play
behind Floy or something like that. I'm
like man
>> Deon Moore can play right now. Max
Lwellen can play right now like Josh
Joseph can pass rush for you right now.
I don't know if they still want to look
pass rush and all that, but I don't
know, man. Goodell at the podium with
with with some people. But
>> yeah, I think he's going to take a
little bit here to to get things kicked
off for the fourth round. But I think
when when you're talking about that,
maybe that's the the byproduct of having
three picks all together here in the
fourth round is you can maybe spend two
of the three on defense, guys that can
play right now. Because I know in
talking with some of the the staff
members last night after we got off the
air, they're really excited about the
board and how it lies. They're pumped
about some of these players that have
slid down the board and where things
kind of got wonky in the back half of
the third round. They think it's going
to straighten up. It's going to get
right back to kind of how teams draft on
night one of the NFL draft or the
beginning of day two of the NFL draft.
And it's going to go kind of in order in
terms of value. But because of the names
that are already off the board and some
of those quote unquote reaches that
we've been talking about, Dallas is
sitting here saying even if they go
valuebased in these first 11 picks of
the fourth round, they feel like they're
going to get some starters and possible
uh playmakers on the defensive side and
or offensive side.
>> Wait a minute, Kyle. You mean to tell me
you talked to Cowboy officials and they
looked at you and said team sucker
drafting?
>> That's pretty much what happened.
>> Damn, boy. We on our way, man.
>> Now you're paraphrasing. I'm look
I'm playing I'm joking. They didn't
officially say that. It's something that
I say teams will let good players fall
to you. You know, teams have
philosophies and things that'll make bad
players kind of fall down the board. I
summarize that by saying teams suck a
draft. But if the Cowboys feel that way,
then good for them like because they
feel really good about a player falling
to them.
>> It's one of those those drafts and they
knew this would be the case. Nick, we've
talked about this a couple times before
where on the back half of day two, it
had the the possibility of completely
going haywire and teams just start
drafting because of their board and off
of their board because there is such a
conglomerate of players that you can go
with.
>> Dallas feels comfortable with the their
conglomerate of players and where
they've stacked those on their board.
So, yeah, they're looking at it and
saying, "Man, what a weird pick by those
guys." And then you turn around and
they're they're the ones that are making
picks themselves. As by the way, the
Raiders are officially on the clock with
the 101st overall pick as the fourth
round is underway.
>> The Raiders sent a seven to move up a
spot.
>> There you go.
>> In the fourth.
>> All right. So, we had a little trade
here. But I I do think that this was
kind of the strength of the draft,
right? I thought to me rounds two
through four
>> and and we talked about the top of this
draft. maybe didn't have the same kind
of elite talent that we've had in
previous years, but this is what made
this draft, I think, still quality is
you're going to be able to get starters.
I mean, I think you're absolutely right.
My top players are mostly on defense as
well, but I think there's still some
linemen that I believe could be
contributors early on in the rookie
year. Whether it's Sam Act from Kansas
State, who was my personal favorite
center in the class, Jaylen Farmer from
Kentucky, I think is a dude that could
compete and is not far away from being a
starter. Skyler Bell from Yukon's
another guy. Elijah Surrod from Indiana.
I get the 50/50 stuff, not a separation
guy, but he also does excel at 50/50
catches, right? So, I think that's a
dude that could compete wide receiver
three, wide receiver four. Hey, Connor
Lou from Auburn. We talked about this a
little bit yesterday, Nick. Like, if it
weren't for the injury, he would have
been fighting to be the top center in
this class. I mean, that's a guy that
could be a steal today.
>> He reminded me of Zack Frasier when I
was watching this tape. It's it's Connor
Lou is a is a mer and I I thought the
trenches played really well for Auburn
last year, even though the rest of the
offense was god awful. Um, and uh Connor
Lou was a big part of that. Well, Nam, I
know Dallas is looking into or at least
I'm looking into across the board is the
the possibility of a tight end in day
four or day three. I don't know if it's
going to be the fourth round pick, but
are there any tight ends that Dallas is
possibly looking at and and some guys
that might fit that bill?
>> Yeah, man. Some of the worst ones went
yesterday, but
>> Justin is here yesterday.
>> Yeah. Uh um Trigg is here, Jack Andrews
is here. Uh Dalon Bentley is here. Like
there's there's a lot of tight ends.
Craig is is very fascinating to me
because
>> he he's one of those guys that I think
could end up being talent-wise one of
the best I know the testing was poor. I
I don't care. He he dominated on tape as
a receiving tight end. I think some of
the stuff that you hear about the
background with him, he might be his own
worst enemy. Like he's got to lock in.
He's got to want it a little bit. I
don't know how teams feel about him, but
Michael Trigg, when you watch him play
was like, "Oh my gosh, this dude has to
end up being a supreme talent at the
next level if he's put into the right
system."
One guy that I really like and I know
Tommy will echo this cinem because we
talked about him a lot throughout the
draft process. I really like Tanner
Kosial, Houston tight end. I would love
that as a pick today. I had him in the
fourth. That would be right around where
they would pick.
>> That kid is so tough. If you go back and
watch Houston tape, it seems like every
game he was getting walloped, manhandled
like he just get leveled. Um they were
since you know Vaj clowned me for about
three hours yesterday. People were
whooping his feet it seemed like every
game and they sure were they were
knocking him around and he was just
getting knocked out and he just
consistently gets back up goes out the
next play and makes a play. So I love
Tanner Kosil. I know that he's you know
may not have the frame for he's more of
like a taller slimmer kind of guy but
>> he filled out a little bit in his year
at Houston. He
>> he's one of the tougher players I think
at the position in this draft. I think
somebody's going to get a steal there
within at the very least on special
teams.
>> I was surprised And Henry was still
there from Texas. I mean, I thought he
was better than some of the tight ends
that went yesterday.
>> Yeah, that was an interesting one just
because Steve Sarkeesian of Texas has
used tight ends so well. You think about
Gunnar Helm, Javian Sanders in years
past and injuries just kind of never
clicked that way in the offense this
year. Um, granted I don't think it was a
down receiving year I think for them
which is why they went out and got Cam
Coleman in the portal, but injuries tape
at Cal was really good. He was one of
the better tight ends in the transfer
portal when he did come out and and and
enter. So, uh I think there might be
some untapped potential there with Jack
Indries.
>> I think the interesting part about tight
end is even though it may not be as high
up the list in terms of needs for
Dallas. Dallas kind of needs to come
away with a a corner, a linebacker maybe
even though they traded for D Winters
yesterday. And you could possibly say a
tackle there too. So, you could still
add talent. mostly on the defensive side
of the ball, but where the value is
right now, it feels like tight end is
lining up. Nick,
>> about these running backs, though, and I
I know you just threw it to Nick there.
I'm sorry, but
>> tell me about the running backs, too.
>> There's same kind of thing.
>> None of them really went like all of
them kind of stayed on the board and and
they current they definitely had people
at Nebraska to watch Emtt Johnson. Uh
Claybourne from Wake Forest. You still
have both Penn State runners. I like
Phil Mafa a lot. I loved what Phil Mafa
showed us in preseason. Uh Jaden Blues
got some question marks. You guys might
insight there. Yeah, absolutely. But I
mean, behind Javvante Williams, to me,
there's still a lot of competition
there.
>> Here's the Raiders selection to kick off
the fourth round.
>> It's an interesting one right here.
>> The Las Vegas Raiders select Jam McCoy,
defensive back, Tennessee.
>> All right. He was the best player left,
I think, for all of us. Right.
>> Yeah.
>> This is a fascinating development with
the top picks in the fourth round
because everyone has a night to sleep on
their board and they can the top 10 in
the fourth round. you kind of see it
treated like the top 10 in the first
round in a way of like positional value,
who's there? And I think this is a
perfect example of that in the sense of
like, hey, okay, Jeremiah McCoy very
clearly the best player on the board.
And in the Raiders instance, they like
to make these kind of gamles. They go
out there and get it. U best 2024 tape
in the defensive back class, hands down.
He's a White House native, so he knows
the Patrick Mahomes family really well.
Grew up with his uh um one of his
cousins, actually. Uh but nevertheless,
Jeremiah McCoy, he went to uh Oregon
State originally, balled out at Oregon
State, then made the transfer over to
Tennessee. The big concern around him is
going to be that knee, and it's does he
have to sit out his rookie season? And
it sounds like he's going to need a
procedure that requires that. It's not
necessarily the ACL tear that he
suffered in January of 2025. It's kind
of h how the more that they've looked at
that knee, the more that they've seen
other issues already present with that
knee. Now, he could go into the league
and have a 10-year career if things work
out uh with what he needs to get done to
that knee or he can never get anything
done on that knee at all and potentially
play 10 years or he can never play a
snap in the NFL. Wow. So, that is the
risk where you see I I think teams
really pause and based on how contracts
are structured in the NFL. You get to
this fourth round, the guarantees aren't
as strong as they are in the first three
rounds. And it makes sense that Jermaine
McCoy is the first player off the board
in the fourth round because of that
specifically. The contract guarantees it
finally gets to a stomach reason a
stomached reasonable uh position. And
Jerry Jones was talking about it
yesterday. Hey, you know, like I'll pull
the red shirt thing at some point today.
It's not going to be in the fourth round
for us. Uh but we we will look and and
see what it looks like fifth, sixth,
seventh round. The Raiders obviously
feel differently and they go ahead and
take this guy.
>> His tape against Ryan Williams was so
good. the the Alabama freshman sensation
that year. But as an athlete, he he's
tremendous. I mean, the physicality he
plays with, the ability to locate the
football, he models his game after
Jaylen Ramsay, you can see it a little
bit with the play temperament that he
has. He can set the edge in the run
game. I I hope that that knee ends up
checking out because he can be an
absolutely phenomenal football player.
It is scary and I understand why teams
have said, "Hey, we're holding off until
now." To me, I I think the talent is
worth the gamble here in the fourth
round, pick 101. I'm happy he's finally
been selected and I hope it works out
for him. I think he's also got the
ability to even kick inside and play
some slide. I thought he had that more
so than his teammate Colton Hood did.
Could be wrong about that, but I just
think the way that he moves. Now, that
could change because of the knee, but
the way that he did move previously
prior to the injury, I loved it.
>> If he put out the same kind of kind of
tape in 2025 as he did in 2024, I would
have used a top five pick on him. Yeah.
>> Um I really hope it works out for this
kid cuz he is uber uber uber talented.
um whether it means he has to sit out
his rookie year and uh just take the
time, I I really do hope it works out.
He is a very talented player.
>> I feel for him, man. I really do. I
mean, he could have been a top 10 pick.
Instead, he's he's down here in the the
beginning of the fourth round. At least
he gets a shot,
>> which I think is great. And and
hopefully he does take advantage of it
and he works out there with the Raiders.
But they felt like there was value
there. They traded up one spot just to
make sure nobody else could do that.
They had the first pick of the fourth
round and they felt like it was
important for them to go from 102 to 101
and make the pick and and bring up uh
Jerma McCoy to Las Vegas. All right, the
Bills did make their selection. Jude
Bowie, the offensive tackle from Boston
College is off the board. The pick is in
at 103 for the New York Jets. Was this
an offensive tackle possibility for
Dallas whatsoever there, Nick?
>> I'm sure. um you know, especially with
the connection with Steve Shimco, the
quarterback's coach for the Cowboys. He
came from Boston College a couple years
back. So, familiarity with that program,
but yeah, mostly a left tackle guy who u
um you see that big body and I don't
think it necessarily moves so well.
We've talked a lot about these guys, how
their feet are kind of planted in. I
think this is a good example of one and
it's why you see him in the fourth
round. But he has a a really intriguing
physical profile, a lot of length. He's
more of a grabber rather than a pusher
if that makes sense. I like guys that
want to get their hands um you know
horizontal with their chest and he's
more of an outside the the arms and grab
around the arms. It's kind of like what
you saw from Tyler Gayton early in his
career uh at least in the NFL. Um but
overall it makes sense why he's one of
the first tackles off the board.
>> Here is the Jets pick at 103 as we are
moving quickly here on day three.
Just going to START BY SAYING THANK YOU
TO COMMISSIONER GOODELL, THE NFL, THE
NEW YORK JETS, WOODY JOHNSON, my amazing
reps, Nad and Jason, for giving US THIS
OPPORTUNITY. ALL THE INTERNATIONAL FANS
OF THE YEAR. YOU GUYS ARE AMAZING,
>> MAN. The accent's different in the Bronx
these days.
>> 103 pick in THE NFL DRAFT. THE NEW YORK
GL JETS ELECT Dell Jackson Jr. defensive
title Florida State.
>> Almost said Giants. Yeah, that would
have been interesting. The Daryl Jackson
Jr. pick it. I mean, that's the second
one in three rounds. And I would I would
throw Bowie in there, too, as terms of
value picks. It's kind of like what Nick
and I were talking about earlier. The
day the day three, first couple of
picks, the 15 picks are all rattling off
in terms of that value. And Jackson's
one of those guys. I I He was one of my
favorite defensive linemen in the class.
He made 25 straight starts at Florida
State, transferred from Miami where he
played his first two years. the quick
step that he's got to fire off the
football. I love his anchor. He gets
instant leverage. You'll see him get
blocked a little wide and pushed out of
running double teams. He can be a havoc
type player. Stunts, loop around as a
rusher, good feel and timing. He can
maintain his ground at the point of
attack. He's a difficult blocking
assignment one-on-one. I mean, you might
need to get multiple people on him.
Strong hands, consistent play strength.
I think he sees the run game really well
to meet ball carriers in the hole. If he
gets his hands working consistently,
this dude can be an absolute problem. He
has the potential to be a fourth round
star. I think you look at him, TJ Parker
now, they have added a ton of
athleticism along that defensive line in
Buffalo.
>> Uh that one's uh the Jets.
>> The Jets. The Jets.
>> Different different New York upstate.
>> I know. I've actually never even been to
>> New Jersey. Oh well, I don't know the
geography.
>> We'll get you there one day. It'll
happen. All right. Pick is in for the
Arizona Cardinals at 104. We are three
picks in today three. You're listening
to the 2026 NFL draft on the Dallas
Cowboys radio network and
dallascowboys.com.
>> Hello internet side of things.
>> Hello
>> Nick. How did you feel about Daryl
Jackson Jr.?
>> Yeah, I had him as my number 100 player
on my board. He was uh my last graded uh
third rounder. It actually worked out
where I had 100 on the dot for my top
three rounds. Um yeah, I I put him
there. Um I I thought he just, you know,
crossed that threshold just because I
really like the physical profile. Um at
6'5, what is it? 315. I I think that's
just going to be really intriguing at
the NFL level if he can get low and use
all of that size to drive in. Uh man, he
could be a three down player in the NFL.
Um so I'm I'm excited to see what that
looks like under the Aaron Glenn system
and how that develops for him. But yeah,
the physical profile is so intriguing
here. And he's got some burst, he's got
some lateral movement. I I I just would
like to see more consistency from him.
There were just games where he just
completely disappeared last year.
>> Jamal McCoy, Jude Bowie, Daryl Jackson
Jr., Raiders, Bills, and Jets
respectively with the Cardinals pick
being in at 104. Means we're 10 picks
away from the Cowboys at 112 and then
they pick again just two selections
later. How does that kind of work in a
war room, Nick? I know that would be a
question I would normally reserve for
Bratis, but you've been around uh and
had a ton of connections in there.
>> You've been running drafts, bro. you've
been running drafts at one point in
time, right? Uh what what does that look
like in a war room when you do have two
picks so close together like that?
>> Yeah, you got to have multiple targets
ready to go and um you know, hope that
that team in between you doesn't take
one of them. Um but I'm sure there's
communication probably about what that
looks like for everybody involved. But
uh I I would say with um with this,
yeah, they they've been talking targets
since the third round ended last night,
and they have a good range of, you know,
who they feel comfortable with going
into this one. If Nick Harris is the
general manager right now, all right,
I'm not talking to who the Cowboys like,
oh, we got to pick. We got to pick with
Arizona.
>> And with the 104th PICK IN THE 2026 NFL
DRAFT, the Arizona Cardinal select Caleb
Proctor, defensive tackle, Southeastern
Louisiana.
>> This is one of your guys.
>> Oh, yeah. You like to watch.
>> Yeah, man. He um Southeast Louisiana, so
the competition may vary. And he was
beating the hell out of most of the
competition, but watch LSU, watch Latte.
He belonged in those games. He whooped
dudes in those games. Got two uh two
sacks in LSU. Big uh powerful physical.
Probably going to be a three tech of
some sort. If uh teams want to like
develop them and be like a like a two
gapping type guy, I guess you can, but
he's really going to win upfield pass
rush and being strong and quick and
powerful.
>> Big fan. I had I had a a high for grade
on him.
>> They're showing the the LSU tape right
now.
>> They have to. Yeah.
>> You ain't going to notice.
>> Well, again, that's like, hey, smaller
school, who who'd you play? And there
there you go. Boom. You can turn on the
tape against LSU and watch him dominate.
>> Yeah.
>> Latte should be next. Well, or they just
pan to the crowd.
>> Latte game.
>> He was just a guy that like
>> they didn't get that film.
>> He he tilts the line of scrimmage. I
mean, he was constantly playing in the
back field of the opposing team. I mean,
he he was a really really fun player to
watch.
>> All right. You were about to set up our
Nick Harris with a scenario.
>> So, I just want to know like you're
running the draft here. who who who are
kind of give me your three players that
you'd be looking at right now and hope
okay this is this is the pocket of three
guys I'm hoping I can land.
>> Oh that's fascinating. Um I would look
I'd be looking at deny Dennis Sutton
personally um as a fourey type uh down
lineman. Um I I I love what he brings in
the run game. I think he's got pass rush
to him as well.
>> I've talked about Jimmy Rder a million
times with Jimmy Roler a lot. Uh, and
hey man, if if you're trying to get
better um in the secondary and you just
want to continue to add, uh, I love
Jaden Kennedy. I know you have your
nickel now on Caleb DS. I get that. Um,
and yeah, I think that's a better nickel
option for him.
>> It's over, Nick. It's over.
>> Yeah, it might be over there. So, if I'm
looking if I'm looking at my top
offensive guys and Mike Washington um,
and then, uh, potentially with Deont
Clayborn as well.
>> Did uh, did Kee Scott go back to college
or something? I I love Kennedy, too, but
>> over Scott.
>> Cowboys fans, while the team is making
big picks, make the smart pick at home.
Call Onime Experts, official AC,
heating, and plumbing partner of the
Dallas Cowboys. Fast, reliable, always
on time. That's on timeexperts. Visit
ontimeexperts.com
and click book now. Rolling into day
three of the 2026 NFL draft. The
Chargers pick is in at 105. We have four
picks officially announced. Jerma McCoy,
corner from Tennessee to the Raiders at
101. Bills take Jude Bowie, offensive
tackle from Boston College at 102. The
Jets take Daryl Jackson Jr., interior
defensive lineman from Florida State at
103. 104, the Cardinals take Caleb
Proctor, interior defensive line again
from Southwestern Louisiana. And then
the Chargers, like I said, pick is in.
Cowboys picking at 112, about eight
selections away. Nick, on the the
internet side of things, we were talking
about possible options in the secondary
despite Dallas already taking Caleb DS.
Keonte Scott's a name that's been on the
table for a little bit that I know all
of us like to hear. What is it? The age
that's possibly a conversation. He's
going to be 25 in his first NFL season.
>> Age. I think teams aren't really
confident in what position he's going to
play. Again, I don't feel this way, but
um that that that's at least what could
make sense here. And then um uh didn't
interview particularly well. So, um you
know, probably just something to keep an
eye on as the day moves on, but man, I
thought he was a potential, hey, I could
sneak into the back end of the first
round. And I'm very surprised he's still
looking here. Um very surprised.
>> I'd be fighting for Chandler Rivers, the
corner from Duke.
>> I I
>> over Kilgore. Yeah, absolutely. I mean,
and I like Kilgore and Kilgore is I
mean, but to me, I think Chandler Rivers
can play outside corner. I I get that
he's small, but he did that at Duke and
I do think that he has the ability to
kick in and the play temperament there
with the awareness, the quick feet, the
tackling and space, but I think he's
good enough to be able to play outside.
I get it. 510 185 uh is what I had on
him, but 52 games over his college
career, he's seen a lot of football. And
now, especially since you've got better
safety help over the top. I think that
did help him in terms of having Trey
Moore his safety cuz he was a guy that
could gamble a little bit because he
knew, hey, my buddy's going to protect
me on the backside. But I loved Chandler
Rivers. I mean, I had a second round
grade on him. For him to still be here
today, I think this is going to be a
steal. No, no one in this entire draft
class at the corner position gave up
more receptions last year than Chandler
Rivers and he was second in yards
allowed behind Will Lee. So like I I
just worry about what the the bad tape
being so bad. If you want an example of
that, go watch Cal. Um but he does have
the ball production. 29 pass breakups
over 45 games. And I like the
intelligence, but I just I think the
size has really caught up to him and
teams are really worried about that at
the NFL level.
>> Here's the Chargers at 105.
>> 105th selection. Los Angeles Chargers
select Brennan Thompson right here.
Mississippi State.
>> That's a fun.
>> Let's go Chargers.
>> Tell me about him, Zack. He's just
lightning in a bottle.
>> Yeah, he is. Uh he is lightning in a
bottle, baby. He at Mississippi State
there. You're you're that to me
playmaker. I mean, you're talking can
take the roof off the defense here.
You've got to be able to respect his
speed. A guy that you can throw the
football to in space. Uh, I I do think
that his yak ability is something that
is pretty darn impressive with him. I
thought maybe he'd go a little bit
higher than this when it came to like
where could Brennon Thompson go, but
he's also tiny. He's tiny guy. So, we're
here we are. We're talking Chandler
Rivers. Now, we're talking Brennan
Thompson. We're talking the small
people. But, he ran a 426 at the
combine. Spearmman, Texas. 23 starts
over 40 career games. He set that
Mississippi State single season record
this past season with over,54
receiving yards. first Mississippi State
player to lead the SEC in receiving
yards in a single season. He's a house
call waiting to happen. He can work back
to the football, make plays after the
catch. He's not a guy that's going to
break a ton of tackles, though, and that
happens to do with the size limitations
for him. And the concentration drops can
be a problem, but he just gets so easily
downfield. Also, as a special teams
player, can be a kick returner. What I
remember about Brandon Thompson was Nick
Harris was all over his recruitment in
high school in out of what was it?
Spearman.
>> Spearman.
>> Yeah. Spearman, Texas.
>> Go links. I made uh trying to count five
trips.
>> How old are you? How how
>> was I talking about him and you're like
you're like, "Dude, this guy,
>> this guy was he was 12.
>> Let me cook on him."
>> He uh I made five trips to the panhandle
to go see this kid. Uh phenomenal
family. Shout out to his mom, Bonnie.
even though she's an Eagles fan, she uh
she's going to be happy to be wearing
that Chargers blue today. Um yeah,
Brendan Thompson comes from a really
strong family and it's uh the first time
I saw him was in a game against Sanford
Frri High School. This was in 2020. Uh
and it was around the time of CO, but
like they allowed small schools to still
play. And these small school programs,
they don't have turf, right? Like they
just throw them out in the pasture. And
they were playing at Sanford Frri. And
uh Sanford Fridge kept their grass high
that that week because they were they
wanted to slow down. Brennan Thompson.
>> I love high school football, man.
>> Didn't work. He had four touchdowns in
the first half. They won by like
>> he needs a route. I will say that.
>> Oh, green.
>> Okay, listen.
>> Let's go.
>> Listen.
>> Come on.
>> This is an incredible selection for the
Houston Texans. Probably the nicest guy,
and I have no problem saying that.
nicest guy in the NFL draft.
>> His name is Fabeti Wiiwoo is how you say
that name. NW AI WU is how you spell it.
But it's Fabi Wiiwoo. Awesome dude. He
was a transfer walk-on at North Texas
initially. Was an all-American as a
freshman. Played center, played right
guard, played a little bit of tackle at
North Texas, caught the eye of Oklahoma,
went to Oklahoma for a couple seasons
and ended up being an allse uh offensive
lineman this past year. just an
incredible backstory. You talk about
work ethic and strength. You He's got
all of that and he's going to really be
a good player for the Texans. That's a
that's the best guard pick they've made
and they've made guard picks this
weekend, I believe, at the spot. I think
they took Rutled in the first round.
>> That's a better pick than Keen Rutled.
And I am not afraid to say that on the
airway.
>> Well, I look, he's North Texas Green and
I love him.
>> He's a little raw, though. I
>> I don't know that he's better than Keen
Rutled. I will say for as nice as he is
off the field, he can he can play mean
on the field. I he he will finish you.
And I like his ability to swap plays,
left and right guard. What are we doing?
>> Really? What?
>> I don't think we I mean, it's just
football talk, you know. We're just
here, guys. We're talking football. Hey,
listen. You
>> What you talked about Malik Muhammed
blocks like way too long
>> on the ground,
>> huh?
>> Rolling around.
>> Yeah.
>> Talking about No, that's great.
>> We We
Fabeti Wiiwoo is his name.
>> Pick is in, by the way, for the San
Francisco 49ers at 107.
>> I've completely lost. Yeah, I'm lost.
>> I don't know what happened with W check.
>> I don't know neither, dog.
>> I thought you were uh
>> normally it's me like laughing, making
jokes. I I missed it all.
>> No, I was looking up and listening to
your tape.
>> I I thought you were making fun of
Woolchuck for talking about a North
Texas. I got
>> What did you say? Say it. Just say
>> I don't even remember anymore.
>> Your ass remember. Say again what you
said.
>> No, I really don't.
>> I was about to get mad at you cuz I
thought you were saying it was a Homer
thing.
>> No, I got no problem with North.
>> I'm sorry he went to U.
>> No. Okay. I'm I love North Texas.
>> Are there any draft classes that you
guys really like coming out of day two?
>> I actually kind of was looking at the
Jets and the Jets have kind of had a
nice day. Nice two days.
>> If you call Metife Stadium home, you've
had a
>> which is weird because typically I feel
like if you're going to the Jets, you're
it's probably not going to go well and
that might still be the case, but their
draft class is not looking bad. When you
have David Bailey, you headline that.
Kenyan Sadi, Omar Cooper Jr., D'Angelo
Ponds.
>> Pretty solid.
>> How about the Giants though?
>> Daryl Jackson. Yeah, the Giants. Arll
Reese, Francis Malinoa, Colton Hood.
Those are three of the better players on
my board across
>> any position. And they they have
>> Did you like the Malachi Fields pick?
>> Not as much.
>> I thought that they got great value on
the other three. Yeah,
>> Fields was a little rich, but at the
same time, they need a they need a big
bodied receiver.
>> Yeah, go get your guy at that point. I
don't know. I don't really need uh
anything else outside of those three
players if you're the Giants to have a
good class. You know, I think the
Buccaneers have had a solid class so
far. I like some of their picks.
>> No. Who really let me down?
>> Who's that?
>> Like I thought the Dolphins were were
like gonna be really fun to watch
because they got all the picks in their
team bed.
>> H they they they just haven't really
maximized in a way that I thought they
>> Their offensive picks have been
>> Who was the receiver that they took
Douglas? That's right.
>> I I didn't think Caleb Douglas was the
best receiver on his own team in the
draft.
>> I loved him as like a sixround value
guy,
>> but I mean him going over Reggie Virgil
was a bit of a surprise. Now, they did
circle back and get Chris Bell to end
the day yesterday, which if he wasn't
hurty,
>> I mean, he could have been a first round
player, but I I I like what they did
with their first three picks. Now, we'll
see what happens to Kaden Proctor. To
me, he was probably the biggest boomer
bust offensive lineman in the class.
There's times when he's on, he's
absolutely dominant. There's other times
where he's getting beat and he's not
even out of his stance yet. But the
Chris Johnson, Jacob Rodriguez picks for
me as a homer. Those are two of my
favorite players in the class. I had
them at 14 and 21 on my board. They go
27 and then what was it? Pick 41 in the
second round. So that was great value.
But the rest of the picks, Caleb
Douglas, and then C Merrick. Uh oo I
didn't know. Not not for me.
>> Shouts out to them though. That's their
business.
>> I think Kansas City's gone three for
three. Mansour Delane, Peter Woods, and
Armason Thomas.
>> Yeah.
>> I think they have absolutely good value.
>> They have absolutely nailed every one of
those picks.
>> The Cowboys going crazy right now.
>> Yeah, the Cowboys. Cowboys have done
really well too. Yeah, I would agree
with that.
>> Got George P and Quinnon Williams
you winners and we him in the fifth
round.
>> That is how they view it is that you
know the Quinnon Williams is their
second round pick this year and George
Pickkins is their third.
>> You add that to Caleb DS. I mean if you
were with us in the first hour of the
show you listen how excited everybody
that came in here was about getting
Caleb DS and then they're really high on
Jan Barum and what he can do. And
obviously Malachi Lawrence was,
you know, somebody that rose for them
pretty quickly and they it was kept
under their radar, but they feel like he
can make an impact.
>> Just to recap some of the most recent
picks that have come off the board. The
Cardinals at 104, Caleb Proctor,
defensive tackle, Southwestern
Louisiana. The Chargers at 105 take
Brennan Thompson, the speedster, wide
receiver from Mississippi State. And
then the Texans at 106 take their second
guard of the draft. Fabeti Wiiwoo out of
Oklahoma, but originally from the North
Texas mean Green. We are at pick number
107. The San Francisco 49ers are on the
clock. The Cowboys coming up over the
next couple of picks. Let's go ahead and
take an early break just to make sure
that we get the window because there are
two picks coming up for Dallas over the
next few selections. This is where
things are going to get exciting. and
you're listening to the 2026 NFL draft
on the Dallas Cowboys radio network and
dallascowboys.com.
Just in time for the 49ers selection
here at 107.
I'm David. I'm representing the Niner
Empire Germany, the Niner Empire organ
from all around the world. And I have a
special message to all the other 31
franchises here in front of me. Uh-huh.
>> See you on the road in your stadiums AT
OUR 49ERS INVASIONS. LET'S go
>> with the 107 pick in the 2026 NFL draft.
The San Francisco 49ers select Grayson
Halton defensive tackle Oklahoma.
Welcome to the echo Oklahoma Sooners
going.
>> Yo, what's fascinating about him?
>> What's that? He's a upfield bursty dude,
pass rushy guy. But Oklahoma try to make
him two gap a little bit and I don't
like it. Like let that dude fly out
field. Let him let him, you know, pass
rush as a three tech guy. But then
they'll move him around and they'll like
put him at zero sometimes. Let teams
double team. I'm like Oklahoma stop.
>> You know what's kind of hilarious? I was
watching him. I was like, he kind of
looks like Osa.
>> He look like Osa. Yeah. And now he's in
San Francisco.
>> You know, he should play three I mean
team captain all SEC second team. It
seemed like he dominated the senior
bowl.
>> He he had a big week really. That's
where he kind of burst onto the scene
for me and strong week of practices.
You're right though, they had him play
the one and the three and he's so much
better at the three tech when he can
just work his athleticism, get up field.
Uh he's a guy that to me will
overpursue. He'll leave his gaps in the
running game some, but he's a disruptive
player. The quickness difficult for
interior linemen to hold on to him.
Strong bull rush, twist, stunts, strong
rotational player to me. Uh he's a guy's
a third down pass rusher. Definitely
third down long down in distance. You
can put him in there and let him go get
the quarterback.
>> Oh, here's 108 for the Broncos, meaning
the Cowboys are now within four picks.
>> On him, pardon me.
There you go. 2026 NFL draft. The Denver
Broncos select Jonah Coleman, running
back Washington.
>> I get it. I just have injury concerns.
>> What are the injury concerns? uh just
could never stay healthy throughout his
entire career and he's got a lot of
carries, a lot of mileage already, but I
I love Yeah, I I loved what he did in 23
and 24, man. Uh yeah, he was scratched
from the Senior Bowl as you see right
there. I mean, there was just always
something popping up with him, but um I
I think there's uh I I think there's
good stuff with him. Um as far as 23
when they made that run to the national
championship, you can see him be a big
part of that. He missed the national
championship game because of injury. And
then uh in 24, I think you saw some
stuff as well, but he was in and out of
the lineup all year and all year last
year as well. It's just tough. I I don't
know if you can get um 17 games out of
him, much less 12. And I didn't see
really any receiving ability from him. A
ton, at least at Washington, maybe when
he uh you know, before he was at another
school, he spent his first two seasons
at Arizona. They used him more there.
But him as a contact balance running
back, really elusive juke, can dart,
strong balance, bounces off defenders,
he can be a weapon as a checkdown guy,
but I don't know as a guy that really
has much of a route tree at all as a
wide receiver. They needed running back
depth.
>> Last
that city is 109 for the Kansas City.
>> Such a great time here. Thank you so
much on behalf of everybody from the
international fans of the year because
this city has given us everything. Thank
you.
>> It's cool seeing the international
>> give a quick shout out to our heads of
>> shout out to the UK
Tom as well who couldn't be here but
thank you so much for everything man and
just literally the whole international
fans of the year my brothers and sisters
down there. Thank you so much.
So, let's get on with it.
>> Yes, please.
>> With the 109th pick in the 2026 NFL
draft, the Kansas City Chiefs select
Jaden Kennedy defensive. Gosh, him and
Delane.
>> That's a great combo.
>> I love it.
>> That's a perfect
>> Perfect McDuffy replacement.
>> Damn.
>> Oh, wow. Yeah, let me let me go if I
could. Yeah, let me pull up my notes
here. I had I had a MB9, one of my
favorite nickels in the draft. Allowed
just 104 yards last year. He only
allowed one reception over 10 yards in
the entire damn season. Smooth and fluid
in the slot. Never gives up the big
play. His instincts are credit for that.
Uh I think he has some of the best
technical footwork in the class. He can
hold it down on the outside, but that
type of footwork in the slot is just so
valuable. Kind of a ehtacular. Uh he'll
need to improve in that area and in the
run game to play in the slot in the NFL.
But I am going to bet on this guy. so
much. I had so much fun watching Jaden
Kennedy. I ended up watching like two
more games than I probably should have
just cuz I I was like, man, I'm having a
lot of fun here. Got some versatility to
play on the back end, too.
>> All right, we are closing in on a busy
time for the Dallas Cowboys as they
await their pick at 112 overall. The
Jets just traded into the 110th pick.
They are on the clock here. here the
fourth round of the 2026 NFL draft
alongside Tommy Yarish, Nick Harris,
Zack Walchuk, FC Lombardi of Kyle
Yman's. Let's go to the Jets pick here
at 110 and I'll catch you up as we get
to really close opportunities here for
the Cowboys.
>> Oh, they they just went away from it.
Okay, hold on for one second. I'll I'll
run down those five picks. Brennan
Thompson, wide receiver from Mississippi
State, goes 105 to the Chargers. 106.
The Texans take Fabi Wiiwoo, offensive
lineman from Oklahoma. The 49ers take
Grayson Halton, defensive tackle from
Oklahoma as well. Jonah Coleman, the
running back from Washington, goes to
the Broncos at 108. 109. The Chiefs take
Jaden Kennedy, corner from Oregon. And
then, as I mentioned, the Jets pick is
in at 110. Then it's the Broncos and
then the Cowboys, followed by the Colts.
And then the Cowboys again, 112 and 114
for Dallas. Let's take a look inside the
war room here for a moment. Lots of
conversation happening. I know last
night there were a lot of talk about the
defensive players remaining on the
board. They liked some of these
offensive linemen that were remaining
and it looks like there's a bit of uh
jubilation in the war room. Everybody
clapping. No call or anything made yet,
but everybody's happy about the
conversation that's going on here. Nick,
do you have any insight?
>> Yeah. Um I think Shotti's uh standing up
here. Maybe they're taking an offensive
guy finally. He's like, "Yes, we got
some action."
>> Bumps around the room. It looks like uh
the pick has been uh made, at least in
their eyes. Um Will is now on the phone
as well. Will Mccclelay Steven has
shaken Jerry's hand. Uh I don't see a
position coach in the room just yet. Um
but I I would have to think that this is
uh offense just based on Shotti's
reaction here. It looks a little
humorous. It's a little tongue and
cheek.
>> It's a little tongue and cheek. Yeah. If
that's the case, it would be the first
offensive player after Dallas of course
took Caleb DS early, followed by Mai
Lawrence with the 23rd pick and then
yesterday Jan Barum now the edge rusher.
So they have the player on the line. Of
course we'll hear this secret audio
coming up in a little bit. Still two
more picks to be announced prior to
Dallas actually having their pick
announced on the television side of
things, but everybody's happy. There's
Clayton Adams. So, looks like it is an
offensive player. Oh, offensive
coordinator for your Dallas Cowboys.
>> Who would be your top offensive lineman
remaining?
>> Mine
>> Josh Farmer for me.
>> Yeah, I got Hecton Farmer.
>> I've got Drew Shelton, Penn State.
>> Yeah, Shelton would be third for me.
>> He's the first fourth round grade I have
on my board. Shelton is. And then after
that, it's Isaiah World. But I know
there's a lot of questions there.
There's a lot of
>> I think enough of Hecton Farmer that
they could compete to start right away.
I I think Shelton's more of a
>> Shelton to me compete.
>> I I think he will compete. And one thing
for Shelton is he's he's one of those
guys that can pull and he can move. He
can go laterally. Very good athlete.
>> With Farmer I see him more as brute
strength straight down the middle. He's
not going to move left to right a whole
lot. He's going to run you over. I don't
see the same kind of Mer mentality from
Drew Shelton, which is why I had him in
the fourth.
>> Well, yeah. And I guess do you want a
tackle or a guard, too?
tackle, right? So then Shelton would be
your guy.
>> Yeah, he would he would and he's higher
on my stack regardless, but I do like
Shelton over over Farmer in that
scenario. Farmer's a good player, but
that's that's ultimately where I'm at in
that one.
>> Got Nick Sorenson in the room.
>> Mitch Le Point. There's Adams again.
>> Uh Connor Riley's on the phone. This is
an offensive lineman.
>> There you go. Now, which offensive
lineman is it? That's going to be the
next question. We just brought up a
couple names. Nick, do you have any that
you're looking at?
>> Uh, I I know it and I don't I'm really
bad at lying.
>> Okay, I'm sorry. It's okay. I haven't
looked at it yet, so I'm
>> Yeah, and I don't want to spoil the
pick.
>> Who are some of your top offensive
linemen?
>> Uh, running to the board real quick. Uh,
center Connor Lou, uh, he's up there in
the MD2s for me. Josh Farm, I'm a big
fan of Josh Farm. I just like tough,
physical, uh, Molly guys. Um, JC Davis,
I like him a lot. He's probably more of
a guard for me. He he played tackle. Um,
Kag Casey from Boys of State or is it K
Case Cage Casey? Cool. Uh, if they want
to go that route, fine. Brian Parker
from uh Duke is a left tackle, but a lot
but he might project as an interior guy.
>> He looks like a center.
>> Sure. Sure.
>> Physically.
>> Uh, he big as hell, too. Uh, uh, you
know, tough, good feet and all that. Um,
there there's a bunch of offensive line
that I like here.
>> Jets at 110.
>> Jets select Cade Club.
>> Wow. Hey, overnight.
>> I tell you what, he can step in and
start day one. I I confident about that.
I am. I He just needs to be in the right
system and I hope that they have the
offensive development.
>> He just went to the Jets, Nick.
>> Yeah,
>> this dude's going to putter out,
unfortunately.
>> I I like I like Kade Clubick a whole
lot. And I I I think he kind of got
wronged by a bad system at Clemson over
the course of the last couple of years.
Uh but he has I think he has the
mentals. I think he has the leadership
capabilities. I I like this as a
quarterback competition and I think the
Cowboys just maybe have fallen on their
second pick. There's another celebration
here.
>> That's the thing. They got to turn right
back around and then make a selection.
And the TV side of things
>> lagging behind because of the last
commercial break. I think we're going to
rattle these off pretty quick, I would
assume. Uh Denver is on the clock now on
the TV side of things. Then it's Dallas,
Indianapolis, Dallas again. So what if
they're taking offensive linemen first?
What are they looking at going into the
second pick? Could they go back to back
offensive line?
>> Give me a linebacker, man. That's me.
>> I would want to
>> Or one of these corners. Yeah, there's
so many gooders.
>> There's so many good mics, too. Like I
think Bird, Ralder, Bcher, I love those
guys.
>> Yeah, there's tons.
>> And then Kyle Lewis,
>> Scott,
>> just a fun player.
>> I I I still love Keont Scott. I know
said he didn't interview well from
>> I like VJ Payne from Kansas State.
>> Devin Moore interest you out of Florida
at all?
>> Sure. I mean, there's a couple guys
there. Yeah. You talk about lengthy
rangy
>> could possibly come in and control.
Yeah.
>> Oh, give me Chucky D.
>> Chuck D.
>> I would be Chucky D.
>> I would cry.
>> Imagine that. Secret audio.
>> That would be
>> That would be That would be spiritual.
>> We would win an NBA.
>> All right, the pick is in for the
Broncos. Here's the announcement on the
NFL stage in Pittsburgh and then we'll
hear about the Cowboys momentarily.
I'm so honored to be here representing
the AFC West champion, the greatest team
on THE WEST, BUT ALSO MY COUNTRY,
MEXICO, to make the next announcement,
which the 111 pick in the 2026 NFL
draft, the Denver Broncos select, Cage
Casey. There's Cage Casey,
>> Boise State.
>> You were just talking about him for a
little bit there. Votch, tell me about
him.
>> Yeah, man. Um, cool little athlete, you
know, can uh move around, reach a little
bit. Uh, second level climber. I I I
thought he had a bit of a power issue,
but that's kind of all of these tackles
in that range a little bit. Uh, some
teams may want to move the guard or
something like that. And I thought he
had decent hands as well. But shouts out
to KS.
>> So, the last few picks, Jonah Coleman,
what running back Washington goes to the
Broncos. Jaden Kennedy, corner from
Oregon, goes to the Chiefs. Kate
Clubnick, former Texas High School
football star and Clemson quarterback,
goes to the New York Jets at 110. 111,
Cage Casey, the Boise State offensive
tackle. And now it's the Cowboys that
are at least on the television side on
the clock. Of course, we've already seen
Connor Riley come into the room. It's
just a matter of which offensive lineman
would they talk about. But I know Farmer
was in that conversation with CP
defensive player for the second pick.
That would be at 114 for Dallas.
>> The pick is in for Dallas at 112. It
looks like they're getting ready to go
to the stage here once again alongside
Tommy Yarish, Nick Harris, Zack Walchuk,
Bot Lombardi, Brian Bratis, Bobby Belt.
I'm Kyleman. Here's the pick for the
Cowboys at 112.
>> For a fifth round selection today
>> with the 112th pick in the 2026 NFL
draft, the Dallas Cowboys select Drew
Shelton, tackle Penn State.
>> Annual offensive lineman.
>> Every year since 2020, in day three of
the NFL draft, Drew Shelton uh becomes
another offensive lineman taken on day
three. Talk about experience. He had 28
starts at left tackle over the last two
seasons for a really good Penn State
offensive line. He's a guy that's going
to move. He's going to go lateral. He
was an honorable mention all Big 12. But
tell me a little bit about what you saw
from him on film.
>> Yeah, he has shoulder surgery in 2023,
but he's a tremendous athlete. He climbs
to the second level with ease. I mean,
he's a guy that you just see him pulling
right around now. You can get that crack
back on the pole. He can get caught off
balance sometimes, but I think he's got
good recovery. He's just a really
reliable type of player. He's steady.
You can tell he works really hard. You
kind of know what you're going to get
from him. Uh, but I do like the
athleticism that he's able to bring to
the table here. He's got a basketball
background in high school. Good bend for
his size as well. He's a guy that can
really sink his hips. Drew Shelton in
the in the fourth round to be able to to
put some pressure. I think a true left
tackle on Gayton. I like the pick a lot.
I think he's a guy that can come in and
compete.
>> Is he going to play left tackle
throughout his career or does he have
any
>> He could swing. I think he could swing,
but I think
>> he played right in 24. He's a good
enough athlete, I think, to stay at
left, but absolutely that could be your
your swing guy.
>> What did you like about Drew Shelton?
>> Yeah, I like the versatility. I like the
uh the uh experience that he brought
from specifically the run game at Penn
State, zone stuff, gap stuff. So, he's
going to come in here and Clayton Adams
is going to have a clay tool that he can
mold to his likening and it's going to
have a high floor. I think the Cowboys
really wanted to come into this draft
and put some pressure on the tackle
spots,
>> Tyler Gayton, Terrence Steel. And I
think more so Gayton than Steel. Uh and
I think I I would love to see Drew
Shelton thrown into a starting
competition with Tyler Gton. Tyler
Gayton might win that handily.
>> Sure.
>> But I I would love if Brian
Shottenheimimer came out today and said,
"Yeah, yeah, this is going to be a
competition for the starting left tackle
spot, and Tyler Gton better be ready."
>> By the way, looking at the corner of the
war room here, not to to take away from
Drew Drew Shelton's moment as the 112th
pick, but Ryan Smith and a couple of the
other defensive back coaches are now in
the room. So, if we're looking at a
possible corner, maybe could be a safety
if one of these guys uh that stick out
enough, even though they did take Caleb
DS, but this is the interesting side of
having two picks within three selections
here in the fourth round. Cowboys pick
Drew Shelton at 112. They turn around
and they pick again at 114. We'll hear
who they select here in a couple of
moments. Votch, you've always loved
watching the trenches.
>> Penn State's a team that can maul some
people up front and Shelton was a big
part of that.
>> Yeah, man. Sheldon did a bunch of cool
things in the run game with his
athleticism. You know, he could reach
and climb and all this kind of stuff.
You can you can grade an offensive
lineman on how how far they can reach or
how far they can down block. So, if he's
a tackle, he can comes in two eyes and
things like that. So, that's that's
really good for the outside zone stuff.
Uh only thing I want him to work on
hands and weight room. Hands and weight
room and and we'll be we'll be good to
go. Uh knee band is cool. Like the
athleticism and all this kind of stuff,
the the lateral movement, I'm I'm fine
with all that. But, uh, technical stuff
that that really gets him in a little
bit of trouble, but if he can handle
that, he's he's good to go.
>> When you look at, uh, what he did from
an experience level, too. How about back
in 2022 as a freshman, Olu Fosanu, who
of course went pretty high in the draft
a couple years back, uh, was injured.
They they counted on Shelton to come in
and and fill his role.
>> Yeah. And he did well
>> as a true freshman. And he, like you
said, he did well. And then he started
29 straight games at the end of his
career at one of the two tackle spots.
34 games total at tackle. Two-time
honorable mention all Big 10. And now a
Dallas Cowboy. We're going to hear from
him. We'll hear the secret audio here in
a matter of moments for the most point.
Uh we did see for a moment there, Nick.
It looked like Mitch Le Point did a
gator chomp
>> in the middle of the uh
>> Could that be Deon Moore?
>> Is that is that a tell here? Uh
>> oh. Yeah, very well could be. And tell
you what, Brian Shinheimer is going to
be a happy man. There's going to be
backtoback drafts. He will take a
Florida man.
>> He's starting to set a He's starting to
set a standard here.
>> Yeah, you don't want to take too many
Florida.
>> I don't know if that's the standard
recently that you want.
>> I saw Bigfoot
>> Florida man.
>> Maybe maybe what like the standard that
Brian had when he was playing there, but
>> we'll we'll wait if it and see if it is
Devin Moore, but I I think the Gator
Chop might have given it away there for
uh for Mitch Le Point. That's okay.
Mitch is just excited. They're
celebrating. The pick's already in. They
don't know we're watching. Actually,
they 10,00% know that we're watching.
I don't know if I want to tell that
story quite yet, but we'll we'll tell it
at some point in time. Maybe later in
the draft weekend. But two picks there
and they got to get back to work pretty
quickly with 137 coming up right around
the corner. Here's the Colts at 113.
donated before last year's Berlin game
with the with the sorry with the 113th
pick in the 2026 NFL draft the
Indianapolis Colts select
>> Jaylen Farmer
>> got Kentucky.
>> Oh, nice pick. So,
>> I've always heavily considered this one.
>> This was the other selection possibly
for an offensive lineman for Dallas and
he goes one pick in between Dallas.
>> I would have been doing back if it was
>> Jay. He's our kind of lineman. Botch.
He's my kind of guy. I
>> if you if you like if Tyler Booker
hadn't been in this draft and it's much
like we did the if you can't get this
guy, can I get this guy?
>> He he would have been if I can't have
Tyler Booker, I'll get Jaylen Farmer
Tate.
>> Similar type of player. He's going to
get knocked for not being a great
athlete, but this dude can get to the
second level and he will absolutely put
you on your ass. I mean, I I I love how
mean he plays.
>> Physical finishes, dudes, and just
competition. Like, they didn't show the
highlights and that's cool. Washington
vers Georgia. Christian Miller, I think
he won the third round this year. Second
round. I believe violating all the
Georgia D lineman. Super powerful dude.
Ah, that's my kind of guy right there.
But hey man, shouts out to to the Colts.
They got one. Do y'all do y'all think
they really got Colts fans in Berlin or
like they just they're just throwing on
a jersey and
>> just pulled up pass out some jerseys?
You know what I'm saying? I think it's
real.
>> They took an edge rusher from Florida
State.
>> Here is the pick for the Dallas Cowboys.
114 their second pick here in the 2026
fourth round. They got a bunch of capes.
Is that on purpose? I don't know. I see.
>> Let's go Dallasos.
>> Yeah.
>> Don't forget Super
World train. Hello people. How are you
doing? I am Maril from Mexico City. It's
a really special for moment for me and
to have the honor of mentioning our next
Hall of Fame player that will join this
season with the 114 pick in the 2026 NFL
draft to Dallas Cowboy select Deon Mo
Florida.
>> Second straight year that Brian
Shottenheimimer has snagged one of his
Gators. Devin Moore the corner from
Florida. You talk about size, he brings
it to the secondary. 6'3 and change, 198
pounds. He's good in press coverage. He
plays the ball well. But when you look
at the injury history, that's the one
thing that I do have a knock on. I had
him a little bit further down my board.
But if they feel good about it and
they're their training staff has checked
off on it, this could really be a steal
in the in the fourth round here.
>> They felt good about uh Jordan Tyson's
injury history, it seemed like. So if
you if you're okay with that one, you
you might be okay with this. Yeah, he's
missed a game, at least one game in
every year that he's played in Florida.
His freshman year it was eight games
with a left shoulder, five games his
second year with a back and a
concussion. Six games in his third year
with an AC joint and a right shoulder.
And then last year, one game
undisclosed. But, uh, if he is healthy,
he's tall, lengthy, a little bit lighter
for the position, but he can run. And
so, it's just a matter of whether or
not, again, he can stay healthy. We'll
see if this is one that um you know, you
look at the quarterback room across the
board right now and and there are a lot
of question marks about who plays on the
outside. If Devin Moore can have a fully
healthy offseason, fully healthy in
training camp, it wouldn't shock me at
all if he's competing for for a starting
job or a rotational role there.
>> And by the way, when we're talking about
missing those games, most of that is
minor stuff. He's never had a real major
injury as uh they they end up looking at
all of that type of stuff, Fox. But when
you look at the tape and the player,
what are they getting with this guy?
>> I I tell you what, man. Long arms
pressed man. But I liked him in zone,
too. I kind of disagree with the network
there. I think he was he was fine in
zone. I thought I thought because he was
so tall and lengthy that even if he was
like
>> out of the right spot a little bit, he
could then react and then ball skills
come into play. I thought that's where
he was really good, finding the ball in
the air, being long, lengthy, and
playing on the football. So, I kind of I
kind of disagree with the idea that he's
only a pressed man guy. I thought he was
uh I thought he could turn decently to
be that that that tall and he was kind
of like physical stacking and shed and
coming down tackling people. So I I I
had a third round he was my best third
round corner on my board and he was like
70s something on on my board. So it's
great value for me.
>> I think these were two of the eight
third rounders that yeah Mitch Leo said
they had left.
>> And I I think you're right VC I mean in
ter I I thought he was good in zone too.
I thought he has good zone awareness. He
can play man. The the range is there.
He's also a guy that the brain work
stuff that we've heard is the buzz term.
He's constantly communicating on the
back end and he runs really well. The
recovery speeds there. Uh he's a guy
that can turn, flip his hips, the back
pedal is super smooth. He's a true
boundary type of player and he uses his
size really well. He can play the ball
in the air, high point it, tracks it. Uh
but you're right about the injuries and
I question some of the tackling with him
sometimes, but I I love this pick in the
fourth round. I mean, this is a guy that
I think could end up being a starter in
the league.
>> No doubt about it. And there's a lot of
opportunity to watch him play on the
defensive side of the ball, maybe even
in year number one. Fourth round, couple
picks already in the books here for the
Dallas Cowboys. They take Drew Shelton,
the offensive tackle from Penn State at
112. They take Devin Moore, the corner
from Florida at 114. We'll continue our
coverage going into hour number three of
our coverage of day three of the 2026
NFL draft in a matter of moments. You're
listening on the Dallas Cowboys radio
network and dallascowboys.com.
>> All right, back here on the the internet
side of things alongside Bobby Belt,
Zach Walchuk, Vot Lombardi, Brian Bratis
in studio. What's up, Brian?
>> How we doing, guys?
>> First time today.
>> How about that?
>> It is the first time.
>> Done a great job. I've enjoyed the
conversation the last couple of hours.
>> He was telling me in the hall he needed
an extra two hours to cool off from
being on the air with me last night.
Bobby Bobby told me a little Yeah, Bobby
told me uh just a moment ago they goes,
"Oh, we're going to play that audio for
you."
>> Already clipped it.
>> Already clipped last night. That's
getting played Monday morning on the
fan.
>> So,
>> are you going to uh put a AI video with
it or
>> Although I don't I don't know. It seemed
like uh it seemed Brian's intensity, I
think, was high enough that AI doesn't
need to do it there.
>> I'm just not happy with uh
>> Don't bring it back.
>> No, no, no.
>> Don't bring it back. Deon Moore, bro.
Like Moore. I'm just I'm just not to me
to me there's just you guys have talked
about this. There's a lot of really good
players on this board that are being
taken
>> and I think yesterday I think some of
the teams lost their way.
>> I do
>> on the back half of the the
>> I think some teams lost their way and
you know we we talked about the tight
ends and stuff like that. There are
better players that are being taken in
my opinion today far with what we've
seen here in the fourth round than what
we're taking into the into the third
round and stuff. So
>> what do you think about Deon Moore is
one of those guys taken? You like him?
>> You know what? I'm a fan. And I had Deon
Moore in the third round.
>> Oh wow.
>> Believe it or not,
>> I think the Cowboys did, too.
>> Tell me about him.
>> Yeah. Well, let me tell you about him as
I get my notes pulled up. Kyle, you got
to know these things about me. He just
needs a minute.
>> I just I always have to pull up my
notes, Kyle.
>> I just get excited. I can't do it off
the
>> I'll tell you one thing about I'll tell
you one thing about Deon Moore.
>> What's that?
>> Size.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Really great size.
>> Not one Not one of those little guys.
>> No, he's he's got some
>> little guys can play. Bobby,
>> the minute you start to realize that,
the better evaluator you'll be.
I'm teasing you. I'm teasing you. Uh, by
the way, if while you're pulling it up,
115, the Ravens take Elijah Sherro, the
wide receiver.
>> See, there you go. Better pick today
with Sirat than what was going on
yesterday with some of that nonsense.
>> I would agree with the sec the pick that
came after that, too. 116. The
Buccaneers take Keonte Scott, corner
from Miami.
>> There you go. More more more nonsense
for some of these teams back.
>> And the Cowboys made a good pick with
this Devin Moore, by the way. Uh this
guy was uh this guy's he mainly will
play as a boundary corner which means
that play into the sidelines a little
bit. He's an outstanding athletic
ability for his size. He's very fluid
his move. He doesn't take much for him
to get out of his pedal and turn. There
are zone snaps where you see him open
quickly and he moves sideways in
coverage. I think that's a positive
thing for him. He does a nice job
playing with his eyes. He's aware what's
happening in the route and reacting to
it. He'll fall off coverage in order to
help one of his teammates. has a feel
how to play around the receiver on the
goal line. He was able to play the slant
that way. Uh I was watching LSU, Texas,
Georgia games with those. He's got some
versatility and he can line up in the
slot in order to carry tight ends in
routes. He's a smooth mover,
>> really good backpedal for the position,
comfortable player when it comes to
playing man and zone. I think you can
line him up tight and jam receivers off
the line and then you can also have him
make up some ground when he needs to.
He's a physical presence at the catch
point. You guys mentioned it. He's had
some injury history. Shoulder in 22 and
24, back in concussion in 23, but he did
start all 11 games in 25. If he's
healthy, he could be a big-time player
with his length and football IQ. Third
round player for Brian Brus.
>> Brian, when you look at guys like that
that have a couple games missed here,
couple games missed there, but it's
consistent over the course of their
career.
>> Is that less concerning?
>> It's it's always concerning. You don't
want to be hurt guy. But if that's the
case, where does that compare to a major
injury where they maybe didn't miss time
and but late they got into a major
injury? Jeremiah McCoy being
>> McCoy was the McCoy is the is just a is
a is tragic in that way that the fact
that his procedure didn't take and the
fact that they're going to have to go in
there and probably redo and he's
probably not going to play this season.
We'll see how it all plays out. But
that's tragic. That guy is a you watch
his tape, you know, the guy that gets
nicked up, misses games, gets banged up,
you know, football's a tough sport and
if you're playing football, you're a
tough guy. But you hate the fact that if
a guy's, you know, you count you're
trying to count on a guy for 17 weeks
and if you can only count on for 12
weeks, that that's a problem with how
you how you uh how you construct your
team.
>> You want to a draft fun fact about Jer
McCoy?
>> Please do. I was always throwing out the
the note that you can find Cowboys
Ezekiel Elliott tape that's newer than
the last Germad McCoy tape, but you can
find two interceptions from Germad McCoy
more recently than you can find two
interceptions from New York Jets
cornerbacks.
>> Wow, that's hopefully the Angela Ponds
can change that for them.
>> And that one was S Gardner who does not
play there anymore.
>> It's even on the team anymore.
>> Nope.
>> Oh man, that's that's sad for the Jets.
I love Aaron Glenn. I hope he The Jets
have one quarterback interception since
our last presidential election.
>> Crazy. Stop it. Poor Jets.
>> I don't even know if they're any Jets.
>> No, not poor Jets. They they
>> And they are the Jets and it's fair.
>> Kyle, I actually got a got a chance to
correspond with my
>> Rolling past noon central time here on
day three of the 2026 NFL draft. Our
coverage rolls on through the entire 257
picks. The Cowboys have made a couple of
selections already here in the fourth
round. At 112, they take Drew Shelton,
offensive tackle from Penn State. 114,
they take Devin Moore, the corner from
Florida. One offense, one defense here
in day three after they've taken three
defensive guys in day one and two
alongside Bobby Belt, Brian Bratis, Zack
Walchuk, all from 1053 the fan. We've
got from Crown Global Media and YouTube
superstardom. Mr. Vot Lombardi. I'm Kyle
Yman of DallasCowboys.com leading you
through this day three coverage. Steps
away from AT&T Stadium. The National
Medal of Honor Museum showcases the
stories of the ordinary Americans who
took extraordinary action in the service
of others. Real people, real courage,
real close. Plan your visit at mo
museum.org.
On the internet side of things, Brian,
we just got done talking about Devin
Moore and his breakdown. For those that
were listening on the radio, can you
give me a synopsis of your scouting
report of a corner that you really like?
>> Yeah, this guy, he plays as a boundary
corner and and when you watch a boundary
corner, usually plays to the sidelines,
he's got really good length. When you
watch him play around guys, not through
guys. Uh I think he's got the ability to
play the man to play the zone. He can be
physical with his length. He can get up
on you. the zone stuff. He bails. He
gets in position. He's able to drive on
the ball. I think he's a very aware
player. When you watch him play in games
sometimes is maybe his uh there's he
needs to come off a man to help a
teammate. He absolutely does that. I
think the length I think the uh the the
physicality plays with and then the
football intelligence I think are
something that you can't be a dumb guy
and play defense for these guys. I'm
learning that. I'm listening to their
coaches talk. If you're a dumb guy,
you're not going to be on the field for
these guys. They're not going to take
dumb guys. I mean, dumb football guys.
So dumb guys. This guy is a smart,
intelligent player the way he goes about
his job. And I can see why they draft
him. I had a third round grade on him.
>> We just had a run of some quality
players.
>> You want to run through some of those?
Here, I'll run them down. That's what
I'm saying. Teams are teams are doing a
better job of drafting right now.
>> The fourth round is really a money round
here.
>> And and remember, we talked about that
when it resets, sleeping on your board
going from day two to day three. This is
where
>> you're sleeping in the third round
>> uh to happen. And so after the Devin
Moore pick at 114 here to the Cowboys,
Elijah Sherat, the wide receiver from
Indiana, goes to the Baltimore Ravens.
Good pick by Baltimore. The sun came up
this morning as well. Uh Keonte Scott,
corner from Miami, goes to the Tampa Bay
Buccaneers.
>> Good pick.
>> Good pick by Tampa there. He stays in
the Sunshine State. Travis Burke,
Memphis offensive tackle, goes to the
Chargers at 117. Jimmy Ralder, the
linebacker from Michigan, who I know was
in conversation for Dallas at different
times throughout the weekend. Great.
>> 118 to the Detroit Lions.
>> That's a the Lions know how to draft
linebackers, by the way.
>> Yeah, Jimmy Rder. Gosh.
>> And then Wesley Williams, the edge
rusher from Duke, goes to the
Jacksonville Jaguars. Y'all want to talk
about Jimmy Rder a little bit here?
Linebacker from Michigan.
>> Yeah, I I got to give Jonah Tols a lot
of credit. I know we had an episode of
Love of the Star, Brian and I, and and
he brought up Jimmy Roler. He's like,
man, some of the best tape in the class.
You watch him play Michigan State.
That's Michigan linebacker 63 238 all
big 10 selection. He had to wait and and
to wait is time to start. I mean, he was
playing behind, I think it was
Coloulston, who was the linebacker that
was taken last year. Tackles, seven
tackles for loss. His dad is Scott Kho,
who played for the Miami Dolphins.
Interesting.
>> Just uh a throwback name there. But this
dude is a guy that the aggression, the
physicality, he can take on blocks well.
His ability to navigate through trash
and avoid blockers is outstanding. He's
getting everybody aligned. The blitzing,
the timing, the closing speed. He can
trigger and react really well. You see
the processing pre- snap with him. I
think he can play any linebacker spot.
Personally, I think the coverage is
solid, strong as a run defender,
understands leverage, high motor player
that's always around the football. I I I
was searching for negative qualities
about him. And really, it's just he got
one year of production as a starter.
maybe change of direction a little bit,
but I thought he would be a late round
gem. I I think the Lions got themselves
a starter for many years to come.
>> Any of those other players you'd like to
break down? FCH, Brian, Bobby, Elijah
Sherrod, Keonte Scott, Travis Burke,
Wesley Williams?
>> No, but I will say that Deon Moore was
65 on my board and Jan Barn was 70.
>> There you go.
>> I value I was just looking that a moment
ago. I I tell you what, let me talk
about Scott real quick. Yeah, I know. I
heard Nick Harris talk about that he
didn't feel like that he had a position
or maybe teams. This is what coaching is
all about. This is the way you kind of
evaluate. This guy played in the slot.
He's got length. He's physical. He could
blitz. This is what coaching is all
about. It's taking guys like this. I
mean, he's a guy that could play you you
could play maybe as a a safety. You
could play him as a corner. A lot of
different things you can do with him.
And and maybe that's why Nick kind of
felt like that. Well, maybe teams don't
know what that by the way. I don't I
don't know if Nick did, but I I think
Did you say that?
>> I I know. I said that. Nick may have
too, but I didn't I've not heard Nick
say
>> that.
>> I think he's a safety that you can play
as a as a nickel.
>> Yeah. So, you're telling me that that
watching him play there's there's no
Yeah. about Scott there's there's you
don't see a path for him.
>> I had somebody tell me he was bigger
Jabril Peppers
>> who
Peppers was positionless generally.
Peppers was more like box guy.
>> Yeah.
>> But he but but he was a but a productive
player no less.
>> Um stuck around. I don't know that he
was ever the guy that he was drafted to
be.
He did not.
>> This is again the issues that I have
good enough to where he got drafted.
>> This is the issues I have with this
again. It you know they do pay these
guys half a million dollars to coach
football teams.
>> Yeah. No, I'm not. And I think there's
there's I think there's plenty of things
when you watch M Miami was a national
championship team last year.
>> I 100% agree. Watch. It's the whole
Yeah. I mean, we I think we give these
coaches too much of a too much of a pass
when it comes to these players. You
know, how can how can Miami, a national
championship program who's had several
players picked, find ways to use these
players, but we get to the NFL and they
can't.
Yeah, that can I get an answer from
there on that one, Bobby?
>> I was I just was not going to derail us
any further, but if you'd like to go
ahead uh because it's
>> I'm just asking you a question.
>> Level. It's the college level. It is it
is
>> where are they getting their players
from? Where are they getting their
players from?
>> Do you think they're getting their
players?
>> They're even drafting 10% of starters at
at the G.
>> I'm just asking where they're getting
their players from, Bob. College level.
>> Edge rusher goes 110.
>> I just don't I mean I don't understand
why you have this.
>> I don't BRIAN. I'M JUST TELLING YOU what
the LEAGUES I I DON'T I'M NOT arguing
from the league perspective. I'm
probably just giving you the the
opposite perspective.
>> The opposite. I'm just telling you why
you you ask why do the teams do it. I'm
telling you why the teams do it.
>> I think I think the fact I think you
believe it. That's why that's why I
think that when I've said I don't
>> I think you believe it.
>> But when I've said I don't
>> and I had Kyle Lewis as the second best
linebacker. Why? Why is that? Or third
behind Allen.
>> Yeah.
>> I just think you believe it. 120.
>> You can believe the earth is flat.
>> Packers take denied Dennis Sutton edge
rusher from Penn State.
>> That's a really good pick.
>> That's a good pick for the Packers.
>> Yeah, we're drafting better now, Bob.
You think we are? I love it.
>> He follows that Wesley Williams pick to
the Jags at 119. And then the Steelers
are on the clock here at 121. This might
drag out a little bit, but it's the
hometown. Let's hand it over to
Pittsburgh, PA.
And the pick for the Steelers. Stewart
have done all right draft
121st pick in the 2026 NFL draft. The
Pittsburgh Steelers select Kaden Oen
wide receiver.
>> Did they draft?
>> Kayen Wetchin.
>> Ouijen.
>> I I didn't watch him.
>> Really?
>> I ain't watching. I know who the hell he
is though.
>> He's a fun player. He was at the East
West. Yeah. If you're a wide receiver
from Iowa, I'm probably not paying too
much attention.
>> Oh, this is the one guy you probably
should have paid attention to. This is
>> Brian and I talked about him on the uh
on the tribul.
You talk about route runner. He's a
short guy. He's a little guy. 5'9, 185
pounds.
>> We like that
>> at some points.
>> He's going to be hell of a kick
returner.
>> He was one of the top return in all of
the the league. He was uh he led the FPS
in return yards. You talk about over a
thousand kick and punt returning yards
in 2025. He can't go. This guy has some
jets. I know Nick Harris was high on him
as well. Maybe not. I don't know if he
was third, fourth round where he had him
graded, but he talked about him a couple
times on our draft show podcast, but he
is a he's a dude and you're going to use
him in a number of different ways. Just
a weapon that you're going to put on
your
>> He looks like a good kick returner for
sure.
>> Kind of reminds me of of what
>> Ryan Switzer
>> maybe.
>> He's bigger than
>> he's he's a little bit bigger than him.
He wasn't as electrifying in in college
as Switzer was either at at North
>> and Switzer receiver.
>> That dude was insane.
>> I'm not seeing a single receiving
highlight. Uh yeah, they're showing a
lot of return highlights.
>> I mean, they've seen Iowa's offense.
They don't
>> Well, exactly.
If you're a tight end or an offensive
lineman, hey, I'm going to give you
attention. I'm not really going to pay
attention to a wide receiver at Iowa.
I'm
>> Hey, we have seen here Mike McCarthy is
not afraid of using Mr. Weapon guy. A
little bit undersized. They're going to
get
>> Here we go. Here we go. There's a drag.
Boom. Catches it. Nice. Boom. Out of
bounds.
>> Woo. 12 yards. He did get 12 yards. Hey,
really quick. Move the change.
>> Got it. Got him. Get it done.
>> Explosive. So there's Kaden Wetchin, the
121st pick in this year's NFL draft.
It's the Raiders, the Texans, the Bears,
the Bills twice, the next five
selections, and then the Cowboys on the
clock toward the back half of the fourth
round. They've already drafted an
offensive tackle. They've already
drafted a corner. Where do you look next
if you're trying to look ahead for
Dallas? Is it is it tight end? Is it
>> Kyle?
>> They're they're going to
>> go get Kyle Lewis. They'll draft.
They'll just draft the top of their
board. I would guess what. So, however
that ends up falling. If if if it falls
down to where I I don't think there's a
position they wouldn't take right here.
As long as it's like, "All right, that's
that's the top. That's the best guy
left. Just go get him."
>> How do you guys feel about running back
here at the Cowboys? I'd love Mike
Washington Jr.
>> I think that,
>> you know, they you know, they would
always love Emit Johnson. I'd love
>> Yeah, I would I would take I would
either one of those guys. Singleton. I
would go I would go uh I'd go Johnson
over over Washington, but I think both
of them would be outstanding picks if
you're looking for a running back.
>> Yeah, I've got Johnson, Washington Jr.,
Nicholas Singleton. Those would be the
top three guys right now. And I'd be
happy with any of them.
>> I have Singleton higher than Johnson and
Washington. The the explosiveness and
the way that I mean he carried that
offense for a little bit of time. He is
coming off of a foot injury though
like that was a that was a backfield
that I mean him and Allen they they both
were kind of doubleheaded. I there was
there was a clear separation in my eyes.
>> Yeah, I agree with you.
>> Yeah, I Singleton was first for sure.
>> I might consider Wheatley the safety
from Penn State. Tell Hooker to go hit
the bricks.
>> He's the number one player left on my
board at the moment. Uh we do have Devin
Moore on the line, one of the the newest
Dallas Cowboys, the corner from Florida.
Devin, congratulations. You you had a
Florida guy, Brian Shenheimer, go and
get a Gator. What is this moment like
for you?
Oh, it's everything and more, you know,
to be able to get picked by such a
prestigious organization and uh, you
know, it's America's team. So, you know,
just being able to join that
organization and bring help and get back
to winning games and help them win games
and create a better organization.
>> You met with Dallas at the the NFL
combine there in Indianapolis. What was
that part of the process like for you
and what were some of the conversations
that you had throughout the process with
the Cowboys?
Yeah, when I met with them at the
combine, uh, you know, we went over some
of my good plays and plays I could clean
up and, uh, they just picked my brain,
uh, see if I knew what I was talking
about, uh, talk scheme wise, coverage
wise, you know, even Dline, I showed
them I could get on the board and drop
the Dline, too. And uh yeah, they were
impressed and you know, it was just a
blessing to be able to showcase all the
things that my coaches at the University
of Florida and my coaches before then,
you know, instilled into me and poured
into me and be able to showcase it.
>> Devin, congratulations. Welcome to the
Dallas Cowboys, man. Awesome day for
you. For for Cowboy fans that maybe
didn't get to watch you a ton at
Florida, how would you describe yourself
as a player? And then also maybe some
self scouting areas that you want to
improve upon.
>> For sure. Yeah. If I had to describe
myself as a player, I'd say a tall,
long, and uh strong DB. You know,
versatile. I could move back and play
some safety. I can also play on the
outside of corner, even move inside in
some cases. And uh you know, I got a lot
of physical features that uh help me on
the field a lot. you know, being long,
fast, big, and then also I pair that
with my mental, but the process is
extremely fast. And also recognize what
the offense is trying to do to attack
us. And, you know, some areas I can
improve on for sure would be, uh, just
off man. You know, at the University of
Florida, we are a press heavy team. So,
I didn't get a lot of reps at off. So, I
could definitely improve in that area.
And, uh, you know, technique. you know,
whether that's tackling, uh, press man,
off man, you know, your technique will
never be perfect. So, you know, that's
always an area of improvement no matter
how good you are at it.
>> Devin, welcome. Welcome. You just
mentioned the the mentals. So, is that
film or is that more so you just get on
the field and you just feel it and just
see what kind of comes to you.
Yeah, that's everything, you know,
that's film, that's also, you know, just
knowing basic football knowledge, that's
knowing concepts, that's knowing, you
know, receiver splits, uh, that's
knowing what type of formation, you
know, most plays are ran out of, if the
running back and tight end are on the
same side, if they're on opposite sides.
You know, it's a whole bunch of, you
know, different variables that, you
know, you need in your arsenal to pull
out when you see those things. And just
cuz you have it in your arsenal, you
also have to be confident enough and,
you know, aware enough to recognize it
when that opportunity does present
itself.
>> Yeah, man. Not going to lie, I was just
looking at the monitors and they kind of
had you labeled as a press man, dude.
And hey, look, man. I watch your film,
dog. You are fantastic in in in zone
also. And you also got some ball hawk
ability as well, bro. So, uh, don't let
them lie to you, man. Keep being great.
>> For sure. I appreciate that.
>> For sure. When you look at your growth,
Devin, and how you you've continued to
get better during your college career,
where do you feel like one element of
your game took the biggest step?
>> Yeah, definitely. Uh just technique and
and confidence. you know, the the more
reps you put in, the more reps, live
reps you get in the game, and uh you
know, just the more game experience you
get as a whole, you know, the more
confident you'll play, the more you
recognize certain things that uh has
happened before, and the more mistakes
you make to improve on those and, you
know, not make the same mistakes again.
>> Devin, uh not only is your head coach a
Florida Gator, you now get to reunite
with Sheamar James as well at
linebacker. Uh does that excite you? I
mean, were you guys tight? It'd be kind
of awkward if maybe you weren't, but
hopefully you are.
>> Oh yeah. No, that was my dog. You know,
he uh he came in the same recruiting
class as me. You know, me and Shamar,
you know, we very close. You know, I
still reach out to him, make sure he
good. He does the same. You know, I
can't wait to, you know, finally be on
the same team as him again.
>> Incredible stuff, Devin. Congratulations
on this moment. We're excited to have
you here in Dallas. Can't wait to see
what you can do uh and and see what uh
what you got in store for Cowboys
Nation.
Oh,
>> can you repeat that? It cut out a little
bit.
>> Well, I was saying we're saying goodbye
to you here. Appreciate you.
Congratulations on the moment.
>> Oh, yeah. Thank you so much. I
appreciate you for having me on.
>> Absolutely. Devin Moore, newest Dallas
Cowboy, pick number 114 in the 2026 NFL
draft. We've got to step aside. Cowboys
coming up quickly again about 12 picks
away from their third selection in the
fourth round of this year's draft.
You're listening to the 2026 NFL draft
on the Dallas Cowboys radio network and
on dallascowboys.com.
>> Wade Wood.
>> Hey,
>> what?
>> That's a I know. I know you were
laughing at that that name. Good
>> pick the other day.
>> I ended up watching him. I
>> I think I think they liked him.
>> They like wait he's there at 137. I
think he's the
>> Well, did he he just went, didn't he?
>> Yeah, he just got hit.
>> That's what I'm saying. Like if he was
there
>> Yeah, if he was there at 137, he would
have been part of their
>> He would have been in the conference. I
I asked Bobby, I'm like, "I wonder who's
the player that gets picked today that I
haven't seen." He's like, "What about
Wade Wood?" I'm like, "Are you trying to
get
>> I thought you were butt cracking."
>> He's like He's like, "No, no, no. It's
the linebacker from Clemson." So, during
a break yesterday, I watched the hole
and he's actually really good. Where'd
you put him at?
>> I put him in the fifth.
>> Yeah.
>> He's He's a good player. Like he he
checks all the boxes. When When Scott
Simons came in here and was talking
about linebackers and, you know, the
physicality, he's he's not the biggest
guy. He doesn't always like, you know,
he sometimes gets ate up, but he's walk
he's willing to go in there and fight
for it, but he's physical. He's long,
he's he checks a lot of the boxes that
Scott Simon talked about.
>> He played both safety and linebacker was
a team captain. I I thought he just ran
really well. He covers a ton of ground.
>> Yeah. How about these last couple of
picks? So, we talked about Kayen Wet in
a little bit there. 121 of the
Pittsburgh Steelers. After that, 122,
Mike Washington Jr., running back from
Arkansas.
>> Large man, excellent straight line
speed. Good player. Yeah, this guy is
like, you know, when you meet him at the
line, they defensive backs kind of turn
it down a little bit. We talked about
this guy a little bit earlier.
>> There's snaps where he appears a little
hesitant, but you know, but there's also
there's times you watch him, he will
read it, plant, and go. Uh he led the
SEC with 16 plays of 20 plus yards in
2025. He catches the ball well out of
the backfield. He got soft hands. He
grabs the swings, the checkdowns, gets
up the field. He's a positive player in
a lot of of ways. If you're a arm or
shoulder tackler with this guy, you're
going to get destroyed. Uh the ball
security has been a problem for him in a
little bit. I think he's got 10 career
fumbles the last
>> the last last three seasons with him and
the way he could play, but man, you talk
about, you know, at 61, 223 pounds, he
is a load to deal with. The Raiders got
him a guy I think hand him the football,
he's going to wear some people out. And
then at 123, the Texans take Wade Wood
as we talked about, a linebacker from
Clemson. Then 124, the Bears. Malik
Muhammad, corner from Texas. I'd love to
I don't know if Tommy's in the control
room or not. This was one of his
favorite players. Not only Not only
because he went south, but the the fit
there. We talked to him a little bit at
the uh the Senior Bowl. If Tommy wanted
to come in and he's listening, he can
come in and talk about him if he wants,
but he goes to Chicago there 124. And
then Skyler Bell 125 to the Buffalo
Bills, wide receiver out of Yukon. Good
player as well. And another one that I
think uh Dallas would have uh maybe
taken a look at at one point in time.
>> Yeah, we're looking at some of Malik
Muhammad here. And he is really to me I
thought he had first round talent. Uh if
it all came together. I was a little
surprised that he lasted this long. I
mean he started 29 of 41 games there at
Texas. I think the zones there, the
man's there. I think he he flips his
hips with ease. He's usually in really
good position. I think he's versatile.
He can play inside and out. Good for him
going to Chicago. He he can team up with
Al Harris there who's been a tremendous
defensive backs coach throughout his
entire NFL career. Obviously had success
here in Dallas. Uh he's a guy that'll
come up physical, will tackle. He he
just at times
it's a little cheeto if you like the
receiver. Great catch against him. Yeah.
It's like he's always in position, but
sometimes I want to see a little bit
more plays on the ball. Well, Malik
Mohamd in the fourth round's a
tremendous pick.
>> Tell me a little bit about Skyler Bell
as well going to the Bills wide receiver
out of Yukon. Botch
>> caught a bunch of passes, lined up
everywhere. I believe like 1,200 yards
andund and some odd catches last year.
Crazy. I thought that the offense put
him in most of those spots, but uh but
still good route runner. He had guy. He
was able to work the middle of the field
crossing routes pretty good. Ran a bunch
of different routes, so shouts out to
him for that. And uh probably going to
have to work on the um vertical stuff.
We're continuing our coverage of day
three of the 2026 NFL draft here on
dallascowboys.com and the Dallas Cowboys
radio network. Votch, you were just
breaking down the most recent selection.
We'll talk about him in a moment, but
122 Mike Washington running back from
Arkansas goes to the Raiders. Wade
Woodazz goes to the Houston Texans,
linebacker from Clemson. Malik Muhammad,
the corner from Texas, goes to the Bears
at 124. And then Skyler Bell is who you
were talking about. 125th overall to
Skyler or uh to the Bills. Skyler Bell
wide receiver from Yukon. Continue your
breakdown there.
>> Caught a bunch of passes. Short, medium,
deep, lines up in the slot maybe outside
a little bit, but mostly scheme kind of
got him open. I would I would love to
know like what he's like in those
one-on-one situations by himself, but he
was a guy that Yukon trusted a bunch.
So, um, shouts out to him. Good player.
I had a high fourth round grade on. And
then the Bills just took another player
that I know Dallas had their eyes on
maybe later. Caleb Alarmzour,
>> linebacker from TCU.
>> Yep.
>> 126. Back-to-back picks there. Skyler
Bell, Caleb Alarmzor. Tell me a little
bit about the
>> if they had not taken if they had not
taken Barum yesterday, if they had not
been able to make the trade for winners,
like if they were entering day three and
they're like, "We still have not
addressed linebacker," then Caleb
Alarmor, I think, could have been one of
the names they were discussing in this
round. Um, that was somebody that
I think they they liked a lot of the
skill set. I think they liked a lot of
the traits. I think at times they wanted
to see a little bit more like all right
let's we want to see you see it quicker
>> yeah read and react
>> yeah we we want to see that you're that
whole brain works line that that
Christian Parker has brought into the
scouting department of just like his
brain works when he's talking about that
and basically they're just talking about
fast mental processor I I think they
they wanted to see a little bit quicker
mental processing he probably goes a
little earlier second third round if he
does have some of that because I think
that's honestly what pushed him down to
this point is just some teams felt like
we'd like to see you process a little
better, but other than that, I mean,
like skill set's really nice with him.
>> He has all the the skill set. He has all
the the measurables. He he looks the
part. He could play middle linebacker in
the league and be totally fine.
>> I think Bobby I think Bobby's got this
guy right and and the the thing about
him is though, he does have some problem
with his instincts.
>> You know, we've we've seen that and and
we've kind of seen, you know, guys come
through here and have problem with their
instincts and not be good good enough
players. uh the play action stuff tends
to give him a little bit of a problems
when he's dealing with that. But he had
four sacks during the season. So maybe
that might be something that you think
about him more with that as a you know
get him incorporated uh rushing the
passer because I I I'm thought he
reminded me a little bit of Shamar James
coming out of Florida. Remember we were
talking about the lack of instincts but
remember he was a good pass rusher.
Yeah.
>> So maybe they were seeing the same
things with him and Shamar James. just
want to get him going downhill a little
bit.
>> Yeah, that that's the thing about it is
that there's it's just it's all about
the mental stuff with him because
there's the burst, there's some twitchy
elements to his game. Uh he could close
on the ball in a hurry, but that yeah,
when he he just doesn't always seen it
see it as cleanly as he needs to see it.
>> Who are your y'all's top players left?
Cuz I'm I've just been texting around
trying to figure out
>> who's still left. Yeah, I'm just trying
to figure out who people around the NFL
think.
>> I was just gonna ask you uh uh Wheatley
and and uh Lewis. Kyle Lewis from
Pittsburgh.
>> So I have seen Kyle Lewis also Jaylen
Kilgore.
>> Yep.
>> Zaki Wheatley Conor
apparently has medical.
>> Okay. Yeah. He he he was heard coming
after last year.
>> Uh Crownover, Nusmeer, Kendrick Law.
>> Let me ask you this about Nusmart,
Bobby. You do
>> and LT Overton was the last one I heard.
You do a great job with the getting
around the
>> league,
>> but
>> I imagine here they might go ahead.
>> Did Nusm is the is the is his attitude
the thing that was the biggest problem
here? Did he just turn people off?
>> I think I think the guy I think the I
don't even know. I think the last couple
years at LSU were hard clearly.
>> Yeah.
>> And I I don't know that I don't know if
teams loved him through the interview
process. Um I I think he probably didn't
check enough of the boxes there. Um but
that was
I know you talk to people around LSU,
that was a a hard few years for him
under Brian Kelly.
>> That was
>> it was a hard hard few years for all of
us with Brian Kelly.
>> Yeah, I I think Brian Kelly really, for
lack of a better term, I think he really
wore his spirit down.
>> Yeah, that's tough. He wore my spirit
down against it.
>> Bob, if you don't mind, I got five more
names if you don't mind.
>> Okay,
>> I do. Um, Fitzgerald, the safety from
USC.
>> Um, Luwellyn, the pass rusher from Iowa.
>> Perkins, the uh, linebacker from LSU.
>> Yep.
>> Uh, Rager, the pass rusher from
Wisconsin. And I also have uh, wide
receiver Bryce Lance from North.
>> Rager would go much higher if not for
his medical.
>> He has a bad one, apparently.
>> Okay, well, that's good. But I mean,
he's he's one who
>> I think I think this team would like
potentially take a shot on him today if
he he was in the right spot. But but I
the medical the medical history is
really really bad for him. Teams that's
like the one that the way we've all
talked about McCoy of like man this is
sad. What a missed opportunity. A lot of
teams will talk about Rager that way.
I've just like of like they're like that
dude is relentless and he is such a just
like the I've heard from two different
people that he would be the top guy when
it comes to like the skill set of just
like working your ass off and like the
motor and the play style that he would
be way high up at the top. So, um, Rager
I think is is one who definitely checks
the box there. Um, who are some of the
others you said?
>> Uh, Llewellyn Perkins. Uh,
>> most people I talked to had Perkins in
the fourth
>> in this round.
>> How about Daniel's the wide receiver
from Miami.
>> Uh, let me see if I've got character
maybe.
>> And Kyle Lewis,
>> I think there was a character thing on.
This is the real disadvantage. I don't
think CJ Daniels was that high. I had
him as like a sixth round guy.
>> Did you really?
>> What about these running backs? Some of
these running backs.
>> Emit Johnson. I'm surprised.
>> Nicholas Singleton.
>> I think they're looking at Emit Johnson,
Nebraska, because he probably has too
many carries. One team had said PFA on
Daniels
>> Kyle Lewis
>> and I think that's
>> Kyle Lewis Kyle Lewis is the name that's
come up a couple times of like that's
the best guy left but I mean I think
it's just the size stuff
>> at Arizona State Kansas State
>> offensive tackle out of Washington
Carver Willis goes 127 to the San
Francisco 49ers.
>> Hey Mr. Carver,
>> we've got about 10 picks remaining until
the Cowboys are back on the clock at
137. I want to listen to the uh the
secret audio, gentlemen. We've got Deon
Moore's secret audio.
>> Deon Jerry Jones, Dallas Cowboys.
>> And there it is. You are now Dallas
Cowboy.
>> Cowboy, man. Thank you so much. I
appreciate the opportunity.
>> Well, uh it is a great opportunity for
you, but you've uh really worked hard.
You've earned it. I'm proud for you. I
envy you.
>> I wish I was shoes had all that uphill
that's in front of you.
>> Yes, sir. I get the best corner in the
draft.
>> Okay, buddy. He's got We got the best
corner in the draft. He said, "All
right,
>> here's here's your head coach, Brian
Shot."
>> All right.
>> Hey, Devin. Coach Sha from one Gator to
another. Hey, you bring fired up for
you, man. Congrats.
>> Yes, sir. I appreciate it, coach.
>> Yeah, man. So excited. And uh just uh
can't wait to get you in here, man. But
uh uh what a great day for for you and
the Cowboys, man. I want you to say
hello to Christian Parker, our DC. All
right. Congrats again, man. Here's
Christian Parker.
>> All right, Deon.
What's going on, coach?
>> How you doing, man?
>> Yes, sir.
>> How you feeling?
>> Feeling good.
>> Good. I'm excited. I'm ready to get to
work.
>> No doubt, man. Congratulations, bro.
We're glad to to welcome you in, man.
Back to the formal interview we had with
you at the combine, man. Did a hell of a
job, you know, your brains, you know,
and the way you play the game, the
range, that that speed turn interception
you had. Um, was one of my favorite
plays I've seen of you. So, excited to
get you in here and
sir.
So there's Devin Moore's secret audio as
he was the 114th pick here in the fourth
round of the 2026 NFL draft. We have the
112th pick on the line right now. Drew
Shelton, offensive tackle from Penn
State. Drew, congratulations on the
moment. Welcome to being a part of the
Dallas Cowboys organization. Just tell
us what's going through your head at the
moment.
>> I'm just so thankful and so excited to
get, you know, be a part of the Cowboys.
you know, such a hor a storied program
and um just ready to get a part be a
part of it.
>> This is a an organization that has
always taken the offensive line very
very seriously going back to the five
Super Bowls that they've won. What does
it mean to you to to be a part of that?
And what are Cowboys fans going to get
in your offensive line play?
>> You know, you're going to get a guy
that's going to come to work every
single day trying to get better. um do
everything I can, you know, help our
quarterbacks, help our running backs,
and do whatever this team needs me to do
to succeed.
>> When you were having conversations with
the the Cowboys staff, Clayton Adams or
Connor Riley, Brian Shottimer, uh one,
who were some of the guys that you were
talking to, uh but what were those
conversations about and how they'll use
you moving forward?
>> Yeah, I have to talk to Coach Riley. Um,
you know, he recruited me out of high
school actually at Kansas State and
then, you know, got the chance to sit
down with him at Penn State. Um, and
then just, you know, I'm I'm excited to
play for him. Um, he's a great coach and
he's going to get the best out of me
every single day.
>> You uh played at IMG Academy. Did Did
you Were you there were you team meets
with Tyler Booker? Are you guys
reuniting?
>> Yeah, I was there in the spring semester
with Book.
>> That's awesome. And what was that
relationship like?
>> You know, he he's the main reason I went
down there. Uh
>> nice
>> TB's a great dude. He's a competitor.
>> You know, he's he's a great ball player,
too. So, I'm excited to get back down
there with him.
>> We've got the offensive tackle out of
Penn State on the line. Uh Drew Shelton,
the 112th overall pick here in this
year's NFL draft. Uh lots of really good
Penn State offensive linemen have come
out recently. Who are some of the guys
that helped mentor you once you arrived
on on campus up there in PA?
>> Yeah, I think it guys like Drew Scrugs
who's now with the Lions and Olu Fashion
um with the Jets. They both kind of took
me under their wing and you know, really
good football players in college and
turning into that in the pros as well.
>> The draft process in its entirety does
kind of seem like a bit of a grind,
Drew, for you. How's it been? And
really, how much contact did you have
with Dallas leading up to this pick
today?
Yeah, it's it's been uh it's been a long
process. It's been fun. Um I put my
hamstring into the combine. It's just
not ideal. So, limited me a little bit,
but um I had a private workout with the
Cowboys and you know, really went from
there. That was about it.
>> And one thing that we've seen on your
tape is you do have some some swing
opportunity, left tackle, right tackle.
How comfortable are you in either one of
those situations and what do you expect
going forward based off of the
conversations you've had?
>> Yeah, I'm I'm pretty comfortable doing
both. Um, you know, I I played mainly
left tackle at Penn State, but I've been
training to do both ever since the uh
last game of my last season. So, I'm I'm
ready. I'm excited for the opportunity
and just looking forward to it.
>> Now, you are coming into this, you are
now going to be teammates with the top
pick, Caleb DS. You obviously went up
against Ohio State several times. Was
there uh do you remember how difficult
he was to the game plans that you guys
were trying to do on offense? Was Caleb
DS just wrecking shop for you guys?
>> Yeah, he can do a lot. Um really good
player, really instinctual, really fast.
Uh I remember some screen plays he would
just blow him up just because, you know,
he read it before anyone else and he was
able to use his speed and get there. So
really good player, really excited to
get to play with him.
>> Same thing you could say for for Jan
Baram. How did you ever get the chance
to go up against Baram who was picked in
the third round?
>> Yeah, we played against him when he was
at Maryland a couple years ago. Um,
another really good player. Really good
player.
>> There you go. Well, we appreciate you
taking some time. Congratulations again
being the 112th pick. It's I know it's a
great day for you and your family. Drew,
uh, take care. We'll see you soon down
here in Fris.
>> Yes, sir. Thank you.
>> There he goes. Drew Shelton, offensive
tackle from Penn State, where the
Cowboys took him in the fourth round at
pick number 112. We got to step aside
for a minute. The Cowboys are getting
closer and closer to their final
selection of the fourth round at pick
number 137. You're listening to the 2026
NFL draft on the Dallas Cowboys radio
network and on dallascowboys.com.
Couple of picks to catch you up on here.
Connor Lou, center from Auburn goes 128
to the Bengals. just mentioned him.
Yeah,
>> he was one of the guys Vachu said, "If
he's there, why not take him and he the
Bengals heard you?"
>> Yeah, man. Connor Lewis is nice. He's
another player that you can go watch.
Georgia uh plays with with a really good
base, good leverage, hands and all that.
Smooth pass blocker, anchors really
well. And I really like centers if if
you know if they lean more powerful
because teams try to isolate centers or
some teams would be comfortable with
your center being like a less powerful
character. uh Connor Lou actually being
able to anchor and you know move guys
around a little bit. I was actually a
big fan of that. Not really a people
pusher in that way. It depends on like
competition, you know what I mean? If
it's a top tier competition, like he may
not push those guys around too much. Uh
he'll he'll he'll lean on combos and
things of that nature, but if it's
somebody that like a regular civilian
defensive tackle, he can get some good
movement on those guys. I was a big fan
of them. I liked him. I had him in the
second round.
>> So he goes 128 here in the fourth to
Cincinnati. The Carolina Panthers take
Will Lee the third. corner from Texas
A&M at 129. And then across the uh the
Lonear Shootout or Showdown or whatever
they call it now, Trey Moore, edge
rusher from Texas, goes to Miami at 130.
Uh Genesis Smith, the safety from
Arizona, goes to the Los Angeles
Chargers.
>> Cover safety, good range.
>> Very good. Yeah, he goes at 121. Tell me
about him a little bit. Genesis
>> Genesis Smith is making his exodus to uh
to the NFL, I guess, is what it would
be. That's a That's a Bible verse.
>> I was about to say, is that the first
and last book of the Bible?
>> Yeah, that's Well No, no, not first and
last. It's first and second. It's just
that I don't think I've ever like like
>> Yeah, it's not Revel.
>> No, no, no, no. Yeah, Revelation would
would be the last one. Yeah,
>> there's some Bible names in this draft.
>> There are a couple of them.
>> Tell me about Genesis Smith then.
>> Yeah, man. Um, good range uh uh good
range uh free safety. Uh took away
crossers really well. I thought he was a
really really good cover guy. Smart.
Just had a really good feel for it. move
uh pedal in transition, all that. I just
thought for his size, I wanted him to
tackle and be a little more physical.
>> He kind of he was kind of bull fighting
a little bit. Olay a little bit, but as
a cover dude, if you work on the
tackling stuff, he'll be good to go.
>> He's kind of got like a linebacker build
in his lower half. Uh so I was a little
bit nervous like when the ball went over
the top of him, but as long as he's able
to see it and it's in front of him, I
thought he was really good. I think he'd
be a good strong safety. Uh and then
shout out to Trey Morris, Miss Smith and
Valley, Texas Longhorn strut at UC UTSA,
super twitchy kind of guy. I think he'll
definitely have a role as a rotational
type of player uh immediately.
>> Now, Kyle, I was listening to the uh to
the audio there, Devin Moore talking to
coach CP and CP was like, "Boy, that
interception you had, man. Speed turn."
I was obsessing for him, man. So, I
ain't really had nothing to say to, you
know, looking for it.
>> I've been looking for it.
>> It's incredibly
>> find his first career interception was
off of Joe Milton.
>> I'd be down.
>> He picked off Joe Milton when uh Milton
was at Tennessee in 23. Do that in
training. Well, come on. you. You know
what I'm saying? This is uh this is Trey
Moore. Trey Moore up here. You know what
I'm saying? You got him up there and he
said speed turn intercept. Speed turn is
right there and he's he's going to ball
hog his way and to go find the football
to go get it. So, um CP, I feel you,
player.
>> I got you.
>> One of the favorite plays.
>> Yeah,
>> I like to go find plays. Coach is
talking about when uh
>> was that the Texas interception?
>> This was Give me two sec. Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah.
>> Yeah. So, I mean that was Arch. It
doesn't count.
>> Gotcha. So, when um going to be good,
man.
>> When uh Shotti was like, "Oh yeah, man.
With Lawrence was chasing around that
one quarterback. I had to go find that
play. I had I think that was Kansas
State or something and he was and you
know I just obsess over finding plays
that coaches talk about.
>> Yeah. If it stood out to them enough
that hey I'm going to mention this when
I pick I want to go see it
>> and so and that and that may give you a
feel about what Christian Parker feels
about the player. And on this play you
saw good hips, ball skills and I'm tall
and long as hell. So makes sense.
>> So we're now at pick 133 with the Ray or
excuse me the 40 Falcons on the clock.
It says it says Ravens. Maybe the
Falcons traded up here. Uh 134. The
Falcons are on the clock. The uh
Jeremiah Wright uh guard out of Auburn
just goes to the
>> Cowboy connections, didn't he?
>> Did he?
>> Yeah.
>> Uh he had a visit with him.
>> Okay. Uh but yeah, the Saints take
Jeremiah right guard from Auburn now.
And now it is the Ravens. They did flip
it. Ravens at 133 are on the clock now.
followed by the Falcons, Colts, Saints,
and then your Dallas Cowboys at pick
137. Any names that we can take a look
at here, gentlemen, that are still on
your board that make sense for Dallas?
>> Um, are we just talking about like just
who would be highest left or or you want
to know about a certain position?
>> I know there was a there was talk going
into the day out of the three picks,
they wanted an offensive lineman, a
quarterback, a linebacker, maybe tight
end.
>> I think there's been chatter that they
could take a tight end. There's that
conversation, but okay. So, if that's
the case, best linebackers, best tight
ends, when we come back,
>> I I don't know if they
>> they would take him. I don't know. Um,
nobody else has at this point. Um, you
still got Harold Perkins out there. Um,
>> Keshan Elliott, Arizona State.
>> Uh, yeah, he's still out there. I
>> York a little small for them.
>> I'd love Red Murdoch from Buffalo.
>> Murdoch's got medical. Um, York. Yeah,
>> that's such a bummer.
>> I know cuz he's a thumper.
I kind of wonder if
Jack is is Andre still on the board, the
Texas tight end.
>> He is.
>> Yeah, he is.
>> That I think that could be the pick
potentially.
>> Who was the name you brought up a minute
ago? Vot uh was it LT Overton?
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Overton here I don't think is a like
like if you're talking about it in the
fourth round. I know a lot of people
didn't want to like when there was some
chatter when people like he could go in
the second that would seemed a bit much.
But Overton in the late fourth
>> to play like head up on the tackle. I
don't I don't think that's awful.
>> I don't think it's awful. I
>> I mean, I'd be in on the board for me,
you know,
>> at the end of the fourth. I'm I'm I'm
down with that.
>> He's my highest.
>> If Christian Parker looks at that and
says I can use him to do that, then I'm
going to be fine with it.
>> He's my highest remaining outside
linebacker and I've had 17 players at
Overton.
>> I think Overton I think Overton would be
like I think he'd be on the ground here.
Okay. If that's the case, then I'm cool
with that, too.
>> And he he's
strong as hell.
>> He's he's strong. Yeah,
>> he is.
>> Would that solidify Baram being inside,
>> which is what? Yeah, which is what they
I mean, they they said that yesterday.
>> They're trying to decide inside outside
where he does fit.
>> I I think he's going to be a guy who's
just like whether he's inside or
outside, he's going to do the other some
too.
>> I actually got a lot of outside
linebackers left. Uh Llewellyn Perkins,
uh Joseph. Um
>> I love Joshua Joseph from Tennessee.
Another pass rusher. Reie, Wisconsin.
Nadami Tucker also got you in there.
Like it's it's still some names on on my
board as outside linebacker pass rush
guys.
>> And I would be hurt if they took a tight
end right here.
>> Justin Jolly.
>> Uh the I would take Jolly over the Texas
kid myself.
>> Jolly is a better pass catcher.
>> Much better blocker, too.
>> Yeah, I like Jolly a lot. I had him in
the third round. If you want a hand in
the ground defensive lineman, I kind of
like Rashawn Benny from Michigan.
>> It's a good call. And I know it's a
Michigan defensive lineman
>> named Rashan.
>> He can kind of play all over the place.
>> I will say this again,
>> you can only have one Rashawn Michigan
defensive lineman. Fair.
>> Should we be thinking about noses at all
like Ben Cleveland or Tim Keenan from
Alabama? Like just a bigger body.
>> Big fan of Tim Keenan there.
>> Compete with uh Toya or something.
Possibly.
>> You could always use rotational guys
behind your your three techs even if
they if you
>> they've got they've still got Aonia
>> like they've got a Tito Aonia, they've
got Toya, they've got Clark who will
play it in the mint front. So
>> I I also think they find value in terms
of these three techs that can get up the
field quickly. The the the high
explosion three tech guys. It might not
in this point of the draft you're
looking for guys that have certain
things that you can use and that's
something that I know Christian Parker's
talked about in the past. I'm not saying
they would use that in the pick here,
but just keep that in mind going into
>> I would say
>> if you're going to talk if you're just
talking positions here,
>> if we're going to say interior offensive
line,
>> Bo Stevens or Brian Parker,
>> okay,
>> I think would make sense. If you're
talking about playing, you know, along
the defensive line, LT Overton would
make sense. And then I think if you're
you're talking about, you know, tight
end potentially for them, I think it
would be Jack Andrews from Texas.
>> I had the the is it Sarra from Notre
Dame better than Stevens at guard
>> myself? Parker. Parker I moved to
center. Heck is my my best.
>> Parker's Parker's a guy who I think
checks a lot of boxes for them because
he's like
>> play a lot of spots.
>> Yeah. He's he's he's very like when you
watch him he's like technically sound.
He's he's not a big guy, but I mean he's
like he's tall, but he's just he's he's
not like a a hulking guy,
>> but he's technically sound. He I think a
lot of teams feel like he could play all
five spots or be trained to play all
five spots. And so, yeah, I think that
he he's somebody who I think they would
like along with Stevens.
>> Bobby, what does the league not not not
Cowboys really, but like what does the
league think about Landon Robinson from
Navy? Kind of small, but he whoop ass.
>> Oh, he does. Yeah, he's Yeah, Robinson,
I think I want to say somebody told me
he was going to be he was in the fifth.
>> Uh Nick Harris doesn't like him
apparently.
>> Jack Kelly said he's small from BYU.
>> No, he's just he's an army guy. He's an
army guy. That's what it is.
>> The uh he's a Navy guy, right?
>> Navy.
>> No, I'm saying Nick is Nick is an army
guy. That's why he doesn't like him.
>> That's fair. They've been good the last
couple years. They won an an American
Conference Championship two years ago.
>> I I like Landon Robinson.
Yeah, he's really fun.
>> By the way, last couple picks uh off the
board, Matthew Hibner, tight end from
SMU, who was a uh Dallas guy for for uh
the SMU Mustangs and and had his visit
here with the Cowboys. He goes 133
overall to the Baltimore Ravens. Kendall
Daniels, linebacker from Oklahoma, goes
to the Falcons at 134. Here's the Colts
selection at 135. Cowboys now two picks
away.
>> You are such A GREAT COUNTRY, SUCH GREAT
PEOPLE. Thank you for everything you
have given to me.
>> You guys here in Pennsylvania.
So, how about WE DO THIS ONE IN
PENNSYLVANIA DUTCH
Indianapolis Colts right
linebacker
pick for the Colts.
>> Yeah, these are backto-back F. Kendall
Daniels from Oklahoma going to the
Falcons the pick before is a really
intriguing player to me. He he
transferred from Oklahoma State. He
played that cheetah position at OU which
is essentially like a third box safety.
He was a converted safety to linebacker
at 6'4 242. But he is so good around the
line of scrimmage. He can make plays in
space. He'll creep towards the line of
scrimmage then boom he'll fire off the
ball. He's super tall. So the pad
leverage for him was an issue. Great
length though. Uh he's a guy that you
got to have a plan for. But I love this
pick of Bryce Bcher. We actually talked
about him, Brian, yesterday uh on the
stack. Betcher is a guy that had to work
his ass off. Really, really good athlete
overall. He was drafted to play Major
League Baseball by the Houston Astros in
2024.
>> I don't like him anymore.
>> And then two sport athlete. So he
decides, you know, I'm going to walk on
at Oregon. I I he ended up leading all
of the Big 10 in tackles with 136. Super
aggressive player. the he had to choose
between baseball and football. At one
point they they revoked his scholarship
and he went walk-on in both sports just
to make sure that he was able to play
both and then he ultimately
>> Did he ever report to play baseball?
>> No,
>> I don't think so. I don't believe so.
>> All right. We just got a bad track
record of the guys that actually show up
to play baseball and then they go, I
think I'll go back to football
>> at this place. Yeah.
>> Well, I mean just in general anywhere
it's a bad track record. real bad if if
you failed at baseball then I guess
football the football has not worked
out.
>> We were idiots.
>> Who's the best who's the best
>> baseball player converted like like John
>> who went okay but like did he ever end
up in that major league? He did end up
with the Yankees with the Cowboys are
making a pick here. We The pick is in
for the New Orleans Saints at 136. The
TV has caught up to the uh the actual
draft. So we're live. Yeah, they
>> What have we been doing the last two
days?
>> Yeah, I don't know. They're they're back
in we're we're kind of in real time now
on the television side. We just went to
commercial break on the television side
though, so we'll see if that that stays
the same. But at least for the Cowboys,
they just made their selection and now
we get the chance to scout the war room.
Ross Wy comes over. Christian Parker
again.
>> It's been a big draft for him. He's got
all the resources, man.
>> Hey, they don't have a coming right now.
The offensive coaches are sitting in
there in their room and they're talking
about it.
>> There's just so many good defensive
players still left. I mean to have
Wheatley sitting there at
>> I I think we might like Wheatley more
than anybody. I mean probably
>> in there.
>> Who's that?
>> Sornson's in there.
>> Any and all the times he's always
>> not I mean I think generally he's in
there for anybody that would potentially
do some special teams stuff too.
>> Linebacker safety. Corner.
>> Yeah. Mhm.
>> But they just took a corner. So
linebacker and safety.
>> Kyle Lewis and Wheelie make
>> I take that if you're taking another
linebacker I take that Elliot kid out of
Arizona State myself.
>> Okay.
>> Ean Elliot's nice.
>> Yeah. this point. Elliott would be my
top.
>> I have him just I have
>> Murdoch. If Murdoch's dean for medical,
I would take Elliot, too.
>> Yeah, I have. But I have Kyle Lewis. I
have Kyle Lewis as that safety. I mean,
if you want to play him at linebacker,
I'd play him at I mean, I'd play him as
>> Hey, if you're talking about multiple
Kyle Lewis, it fits that
>> because if they need a linebacker and a
safety,
>> yeah, size, the dude can just fly around
and make all kinds of plays on the
football field.
>> Yeah, man. 425, you're going to need two
guys kind of like that. Yeah. But Kan
Elliott was super productive and he also
does have some blitz rush ability. I
think I think he looks bigger.
>> I think what he played
>> I think linebacker or hand in the dirt
defensive lineman makes sense here.
>> Why why hand in the dirt?
>> Because I think what you've got right
now is that there's
>> you feel comfortable with Quinn and
Kenny,
>> but there's a lot of guessing that
you're doing there. I mean, you got to
remember they didn't have a a starting
four technique until they signed Bullard
really. Um or they were going to have to
run out there with Abonia. So I mean I I
wouldn't be surprised if they tried to
address that here or they went
linebacker. Either one.
>> Abney Wheatley Rivers. I mean yeah I can
understand it. The league hates good
football players.
>> Ain't going to be the game Mr. Brothers.
>> I mean Perkins I still think would be
>> I'm not directing that at you. I'm
directing at the league.
>> No I know Perkins would be
>> even though I'm gonna get clipped for it
on Monday.
>> Which 56 player would you take here
Brian?
>> Which 56 player?
>> Yeah. Which which uh 5'6 player would
you take here?
>> Is there a 5'6 player?
>> If there is, I'm sure you'd take him.
>> You would take rivers.
>> I am all about I'm just I'm just all
about All I know is Bobby, listen. This
>> messing with you.
>> No, no, I know you are. But all I know
and let's as a group and we all look at
these players. Do you feel like the
players that drafted in than today have
been better on your board?
>> Oh, that's defensive line.
>> Okay. Okay.
>> That's defensive because that's Marcus
Dixon. So
>> Dixon just walked in the room.
>> I would guess
>> D lineman I lineman.
>> I would guess I would love for them to
take uh I would love for them to take
Llewellen. I don't think would be fun.
>> I mean it would be fun for me because I
think he's I think he's when you watch
him the measurables are I mean he's not
going to run the fastest. He's not going
to you know test the best but you again
you watch just an outstanding football
player. I I Iowa's defense is good and
you watch those guys play and they play
well as a unit.
>> Votch, I know you really liked him too.
>> Who's that?
>> Llewellyn.
>> Llewellen.
>> M's a big fan of Llewellyn. He can uh
play with his hands in dirt and he can
stand up and be outside linebacker and
rush. If it's him or Rager or one of
those kind of guys, I'm I'm probably
>> I would take Perkins and playing back at
edge.
>> Llewellyn Joseph Overton Lucas USC.
>> Yeah,
>> possibly Curry from Ohio State.
>> Here's the sink selection at 136.
Cowboys announc damn good pick by them.
I'm sorry.
>> Uh maybe no audio on the Saints
selection here.
>> Poor kid.
>> The new Saints select Ryan SL wide
receiver brother
>> from North Dakota State University.
>> Great pick.
>> He's a really good player.
>> Bryce Lance wide receiver.
>> Probably better quarterback
>> state.
He needed a quarterback. I don't really
get the the love for his quarterback in
this draft cuz Bryce Lance is left
waiting on the football a ton.
>> Yeah.
>> Um
so if it's defensive line,
uh I don't I mean the only one who seems
to make sense to me there's like two of
them and that'd be Zayn Durant and LT
Overton.
>> I mentioned Overton a little bit. What
about Harris from Miss the defensive
tackle? Didn't they visit with him?
>> I I don't know that that makes sense
here.
There's some off the- field stuff,
right, that you have to there's some big
time off the- field stuff that you have
to deal with him.
>> When you look at the war room, we've
already saw seen Marcus Dixon come in
and now it's a a little bit of a waiting
game. Josh,
>> you don't pick again until the seventh
round and you got a little bit of time
to wait from the fifth and the sixth
here.
>> Wondering where where that time could go
for Dallas. Could you Could you use
future capital to get back in or is that
something you don't even have any worry
of doing now that you've
>> I I probably wouldn't. I I mean, look,
there's nobody that like right now just
looks to me like got to go get him. Um
>> I don't know. I think that they are
they've got one pick left.
Outside of that, if they don't, I would
expect that that last pick is either
going to be a receiver or I think they
are going to be heavy on receiver and
undrafted free agency.
>> Usually off their board, too.
>> There's a couple receivers I know they
would love to take either late or in
undrafted free agency.
>> Well, and taking the one taking the one
late a lot of times, Brian's mentioned
this, taking one with your last pick
sometimes is just like I don't want to
fight for him.
>> I don't want to fight. Yeah, I don't
want to fight you. And if that's the
case, remember the weekend started the
big breaking news was George Pickkins
anticipating to play on the trans or the
the franchise tag. If he's playing on
the franchise tag, you feel pretty set
at wide receiver except for your death.
>> Right now, your wide receiver five is
Jonathan Mingo. I mean, that's kind of
TP fifth guy. Yeah, maybe it's Cavonte
Turpin.
>> I don't think that worked out really
well for him last year.
>> You think it's because he's little? I
think I would just like him to focus on
the
>> I think I I think that you know with the
I think the thing about him though is
though I think it took away from him and
his role that he really has.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> I think that I think that
>> Turpin Turpin just did not have a good
year. Tur Turpin was not finishing
catches. Turpin was
>> I mean what how many did he end up with
more like false fair catches than
touchdowns last year?
>> I think I think trying to be that guy.
>> He had a touchdown did he? He had a
specific
>> he had two of the false fair catches. So
then yeah,
>> what were you saying, Brian?
>> I think I think the fact that they tried
to play him more on the offense hurt him
with I I think to me with, you know, it
took away from him being, you know,
focusing on where he's really can help
this team and that's as a returner, you
know,
>> man, he's already almost 30.
>> Yeah.
>> Entered the league late
>> uh two touchdowns last year.
>> Okay. So he had the same number. Yeah,
he had that big touching against
>> but that should never receiver.
>> It's like the my favorite Sam Williams
stat.
>> We'll talk about that later. We're
streaming on a lot of different
platforms and we're waiting for the
happy things of the
>> Cowboys pick at 137. We'll wait on those
types of standing on
>> It's a fun one.
>> It is a bet.
>> I bet it is.
>> Looks like the war room I I jinxed it,
guys. I I said that the national
broadcasts have caught up. They've gone
to two commercial breaks in two picks.
>> We've been waiting for all of this to
happen.
>> Put money in Jerry's pocket.
>> Yeah, that's part of it.
>> Get your money. Just get your money.
>> It's gotten to the point where I I think
we've already had kind of a uh a good
idea of the names that are on the short
list to be
>> once you pick selection.
>> I mean, they're going to pick somebody
the seventh, but this is really kind of
the
>> the last one. This is the summation of
what your draft class is going to end up
looking like. And if they come away with
any of the names we've been talking
about here, I think you generally feel
pretty good about what you've done.
>> You know, you know, you uh had a pretty
good first uh first couple of goals at
it. You know what I'm saying? And that
kind of set the tone for the rest of it.
You know, if you would have hated your
first pick, then I would have really
wanted my fours to like carry the load
for it. But if you get Caleb Downs, man,
the rest of these guys can just be like
traits dudes, and I wouldn't care too
much. While we're waiting here, roll
into your next tailgate in style with
your own Club Car, the official golf car
of the Dallas Cowboys. Club Car
low-speed vehicles deliver the
performance and quality that Cowboys
fans expect with features and comfort
you command. Visit clubcar.com
today. Of course, we are the draft show
with Bobby Belt, Brian Brad, Zack
Walchuk, Vot Lombardi. I'm Kyle Yman's
brought to you by Miller Light, the only
beer the Dallas Cowboys. It is Miller
time. It's also draft time for Dallas.
Their pick is in and they're having some
conversation. Looks like the room is
cleared out a little bit outside of the
uh the the main figures at the end of
the table there uh for Dallas.
>> Everyone go to lunch. We'll circle back.
>> And that might be the case with no picks
in the fifth or the sixth round.
>> Go start working on that free agency.
Get on those phones and say
>> got that much of a leeway. It's
>> when Shawn Payeyton did his did his
magic with Tony Roman. We started in the
fifth round and then carried that thing
through. So maybe you know every it used
to be every scout had a a coach that
they worked with and they tried to kind
of Stephen Jones had a plan laid it out
the numbers they would need and then
everybody would go to work on that. So
maybe you're going to have to do a
little bit of recruiting. I know we've
got a we've got a long time still left.
It's only one o'clock. What we got about
five more hours of this thing?
>> Yeah.
>> So I'd get on the phone and say, "Hey,
listen. I'm I know we got five hours
left, but if you don't get picked, man,
you know I love you.
>> Yeah.
>> You know I love you, man. And I know I
can I can maybe get you some money.
Funny. You're going to be the first one
on the
>> Maybe maybe not as much money as you
were getting NIL, but I'll get you some
money.
>> Yeah. You know,
>> big bra. Big bre.
>> Lots of excitement in Pittsburgh.
They're showing off all the Cowboys
fans. Shout out to all those Cowboys
fans that made the trek to Pittsburgh,
by the way, for the actual NFL draft.
Here is the selection after long await.
It's 137 overall, the Dallas Cowboys.
>> Wow. All right.
>> With the 137th pick in the 2026 NFL
draft, the Dallas Cowboys select LT
Overton defensive end Alabama.
>> We were just talking about him, Bobby,
as a possibility. Hand in the ground,
6'3", 274 lbs. He is versatile. He can
play along that defensive line. And the
Cowboys go get another member of the
front seven with their final pick here
in the fourth round of the 2026 NFL
draft. We're going to step aside. When
we come back, we're going to break down
this pick even further and we're going
to in including getting him on the phone
and having some secret audio. Plus, Zack
Walchuk is going to drive the bus for a
little bit here on the uh the stream
side of things. You're listening to the
2026 NFL draft on the Dallas Cowboys
Radio Network and on dallascowboys.com.
All right, LT Overton. Brian, while we
switch out some spots, would you mind
breaking?
>> Yeah, I'll do my best here with uh Let
me get to my notes if I right Brian.
>> Yeah. Well, he gets four guy.
>> Yeah. This is This is the thing that I
was kind of with Overton. I was a little
I couldn't figure out where to play him
and and I'm usually I I pride myself on
being able to have an understanding of
where to play him, but the fact that you
you said the four eye stuff I think
makes a lot of sense as well. He is a
transfer from Texas A&M. He's played up
and down the line during his career.
He's got some strength. He's got some
power to his game. He's 6'5, 278 is what
we're dealing with here. I thought he
played pretty well at the point of
attack. The wide base, thick lower half,
kind of taking on blocks, holding his
gap. I'd like to see him come off the
ball a little quicker. And maybe this is
a Alabama thing. And you know, his
usually when you watch a Georgia player,
you're thinking like, okay, they're two
gap and they're they're playing, you
know, they're they're they're they're
playing a little slow. Uh they're
reading more. But his body type is
somewhere between an edge and a three
technique. Voti is what I think. And but
he's just not that explosive. It's like
you're waiting for him to get going once
the ball snapped. I didn't see a lot of
pass rush moves to stress blockers out
unless he was using power. Uh there's
just not a lot of hand use after
contact. I don't think he has a real
pass rush plan. Uh the the lack of
counter moves, especially when he got
stopped along the line of scrimmage was
a little bit of a problem. His
production is not that great, but when
he wants to come off the ball, he could
be a problem. But you don't always see
that in his play. So
>> traits, right, Mr. Bronze? This is a lot
of traits. I just like I say, yeah, I
was I I kind of maybe I maybe I was
falling in love with the with Iowa a
little bit with Llewellyn just because
he doesn't have any of the the the uh
the the type of like oh the broad jumps
well he vertical
>> does have the measurables but he but
like he knows how to play. He's using
his hands. He's getting off blocks. Uh
this one to me though if if you could
find a way to reach him. Now he went to
school at Alabama. They got good coaches
at Alabama. So hopefully uh you know the
defensive line coaches here can kind of
kind of build a build him up to be a
little bit better of a pass rusher
because he's got some power to him.
>> He's not a big time pass rusher, but I
don't know how much he's going to be
asked to do that here.
>> This is a four eye guy. Is that what
he's going to he's going to play with
they want him to play with power. They
want him to set the edge. They want him
to play against the run. They want him
to keep linebackers clean. I think
that's going to be a big thing for him.
>> Tommy, what do you think about LT
Overton? I
>> I completely agree with everybody else
that it's it's a fourey thing. I think
he's a much better run defender than he
is a pass rusher. Uh long arms are going
to be the key there. If this staff can
get him to utilize those in the right
way and uh figure out what to do with
his frame, it's it's a really awkward
frame. And I know there's been some talk
about is he a tweener uh with that
build. If they can figure out, you know,
what kind of role he can carve out in
that for spot or if they feel like maybe
it's somewhere else, um then you can
maybe see this being beneficial. But a
big part of it is going to be able to
make sure that he has time on task doing
what they feel like he can do to execute
in this defense.
>> I will say something about I know uh
Mitch Le Point referenced it a little
bit earlier today about how they've
picked in the fourth round. This is the
first time in since what uh this 26 or
23 was the last time they had a fourth
round pick.
>> Yeah.
>> So it's been a while since they've had
one under Will Mcclelay. They've had one
of the better track records of sleeping
on their board and then coming out in
the fourth round and knowing who to
pick. They if you look at their their
run since Will's been here, they have
picked and these guys are all either
have had Pro Bowl seasons or were
consistent starters in the NFL for
several years. Damen Wilson, Anthony
Hitchens, Dak Prescott, Dorance
Armstrong, Dalton Schultz, Tyler Bottis,
Jake Ferguson, they've had a hell of a
run on fourth round picks. And so
getting three of them today after
they've had a chance to kind of sit back
and look at things and knowing that
those first two at least maybe Overton
as well, I don't know. Those first two
at least, I think were still one of, you
know, part of their third round grades.
>> Okay. So, uh, just to update on the
other picks since LT Overton, your
newest Dallas Cowboy, we got Kyle Lewis
did finally get selected to the Miami
Dolphins. Uh, pick 138 out of
Pittsburgh. And then Ephesians
Pricerback
from Washington going and Ephesians have
gone.
>> I know. How about this? Uh I know Kyle
Lewis was one of your favorites, Brian.
>> Yeah, he was. And and and and when you
watch him play this, he is a smaller
guy, which the league doesn't really
appreciate, I guess, anymore. But I Hey,
the the Green Bay Packers, you know,
John Eric Sullivan's now down there in
Miami. You know, I think there's some
picks that he's made. I think that've
been really really good. I think this is
one of his better picks. Uh, when you
start to talk about Kyle Lewis, he plays
at pit, as we mentioned. He can he's a
linebacker. He's undersized, but he you
could watch him cover, you can watch him
carry routes, you could watch him blitz,
you could watch him finish. He tackles
extremely well. He's very smart. Uh,
this is the type of guy that I'd love to
have because there's a lot of different
things you could do with him as a
football player.
>> Absolutely.
All
right, welcome on back here on 1053, the
fan of the Dallas Cowboys radio network,
dallascowboys.com.
We are still rolling through the fourth
round of the 2026 NFL draft. If you
missed it, your newest Dallas Cowboy, LT
Overton, the edge out of Alabama, 63 274
could play more of that hand in the
ground, fourey position here uh with the
Dallas Cowboys. as we've been breaking
him down. If you missed it during the
break, I think we we all are kind of
agree probably not your elite sack
production guy, but certainly uh a dude
that can do a lot for you in terms of
the run defense uh in in the bull rush
that he's got, the penetration in the
back field. I think he is a guy that
fits what they're wanting to do here. Uh
Nick, did you have anything you wanted
to add on LT Overton as you're rejoining
the show?
>> Uh it looks like we have a guest here.
>> We do.
>> Oh my gosh. Hey, how are you?
>> No one wants to hear my thoughts. This
is this I I don't know if anybody's had
more picks so far than than Southeast
Eric Ellenworth here.
>> How are you doing?
>> I'm doing great.
>> Eric Elling joining the show here on the
fan. Eric, how are you?
>> Awesome.
>> Everything's good.
>> Yeah. I mean, shoot, today is has been a
dream with kind of the the value I feel
like we got, you know, with those with
those picks.
>> So, run us uh run us through how today
has gone so far with these three picks
that you've had here in the fourth
round. Was there a plan? Were these kind
of the players that you had earmarked or
did you kind of have to adjust based on
the board?
>> Yeah, so um these were guys like kind of
at the end of last night, you know, you
kind of approach the fourth round as
like the first round of Saturday, right?
You kind of get a time to game plan what
you're going to do the next day and look
at your board and try to I don't know,
play out different scenarios of who you
think's going to be there and and you
know, we had starter grades on so many
guys um entering today and uh yeah, we
we drafted three of them. So, uh, we all
we all feel feel really good and and
there really wasn't a ton of discussion
up there about like, you know, should
we, shouldn't we? Like there was a lot
of heck yes, heck yes, heck yes. You
know, like just a lot of lot of guys
that we felt conviction from, whether
it's coaches, position coach, scouts,
over the top guys, like it was green
light across the boards.
>> The the one you just took, LT over to,
what what's the vision for him?
>> I love LT. He's so one, it's like don't
pigeon hole him. He's like he's so
versatile. I mean everywhere across the
defensive line you've seen him line up
at at Bama.
>> Um and you know he's a guy wrote a year
ago because he flirted with flirted with
coming out early and uh so to me it's
like he could he could play your big
end. Uh he could play you know five on
sub he can come inside and play three
technique and rush the passer. But this
dude like line one is just how strong he
is. Yeah.
>> And then with that his contact balance.
This is a player you're not going to see
on the ground um at all. So like he's
and then he's got that twitch and
athleticism on sub to really, you know,
kind of has that inside penetration
ability to to play three technique and
shoot even a shade in in some certain,
you know, pass rush packages. So he is
so versatile and just a and I mean
really good run defender with that
strength.
>> Yeah. And speaking of shade, talk about
your palm tree corner that you just got
out of Florida 63. I I love Is that
Chomp for you?
>> Yeah. Uh, you know, I I looked at Shotty
and Shotti's a gator and uh I had to
give him a little gator chomp chomp
there, too. But Devin can do it all. You
know, he's tall, he's long. I think he I
think his play speeds faster than his 40
time.
>> Um, his the the Achilles heel for Devon
over his career is he's just had a lot
of soft tissue injuries.
>> Um, you know, but really like through
our medical checks, there wasn't
anything that we felt was a risk from
like a long-term, you know, career
projection. it was just like kind of had
some bad luck along the way. Um, but he
is a tough guy through those injuries
and he's battled to get back on the
field and and he's kind of been the buzz
around Gainesville for a couple years
now. Like, hey, if we can just keep this
guy on the field like he's got some
tools and uh he had a great year this
year and was really a staple uh for the
Gator and kind of had his coming out
party last year against Georgia
mid-season. So, uh, um, yeah, he's he's
been one that I mean, shoot, you look at
the height, length, speed, and, uh, you
start drooling a little bit and balls
throw ball skills on on onto it, too.
And
>> yeah, there's a lot to excite with that.
>> See, I loved his run tape. I I thought
him stepping up as a run defender,
really physical on the outside. I know
he's 6'3, but he talked about some
versatility. Would you ever put a 6-3
guy in slot?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I I mean, you're seeing a lot of
uh a lot of teams put those bigger kind
of Yeah. uh whether it's an F tight end
or uh that you know a lot of teams will
play subdefense to quote unquote 12
personnel if they're that you know that
tall long um passcatching type tight end
but like also you'll see a lot of those
those tall long guys move into the slot
too and like a guy like uh Devonte Smith
you know for how long he is like he
plays so much bigger that I think Devin
Devin Moore can match something like
that so I'm not sure the the exact
vision there but like I I
>> I think He's got versatility to do that
and like you guys said he's willing to
play physical. Um so when you move him
closer to the ball like he can handle it
from
>> What was the first time you watched
Malcoly Lawrence?
>> Oh man. So this he was another guy last
year that you going into UCF you heard a
lot about from a testing standpoint.
Like they're like hey just wait till
this guy goes to the combine or proday.
They're like we don't think he's going
to come out but these guys that test
really well like sometimes they get some
guys in their ear that encourage them
too. And I was really glad that he
stayed and developed another year. Um,
and then shoot, you turn on that Baylor
game and it's like a highlight reel.
It's uh it's uh it's pretty cool what he
can do. And obviously everyone comments
on his first step and his ability to to,
you know, shave the corner and turn his
foot and flatten, but like when once he
clears, his ability to accelerate is
just different and it pops off the tape.
And yeah, he's he's got some he's got
such a high ceiling, too, that he's
going to continue to get better and
better each and every year. And yeah,
he's he's exciting, too.
>> Eric Arenssworth with this year on on
the fan of Dallas Cowboys.com. Take it
away, tell me.
>> Eric, some of your colleagues were in
here earlier saying that when Caleb DS
is a true freshman at Alabama, you were
already telling him, "Hey, you're going
to have to keep an eye on this guy." How
often do you do that with true freshman?
And what was it about the film in his
first year that made you want to tell
everybody about him early? It actually
went a year prior. His dad, Gary DS, was
the running back coach at East Tennessee
State and he was the prisonazison. They
had a guy, Jacob Sailors, who I think he
he's had some success in the UFFL, but I
was there to see Jacob and we started
talking about Josh and Caleb DS um a ton
his senior year of high school and he
was already going through Bama installs
um you know, his senior year. And so
like I'm like, okay, there not many
seniors in high school that are already
mastering Nick Sabin's defense as a
senior. And then boom, we I got to see
him as a freshman there and he was in a
very talented defensive back room. He
stood out like and like I was ready to
write that report right then and there
and then drooling at the opportunity to
do it. And then in today's era of NIL
and and and Portal and all that and
obviously with coach Sabin retiring, he
left my area and that happens sometimes.
I was I was telling Bobby it's that's my
Cam Coleman. I remember seeing him as a
17year-old at Auburn in August. I'm
like, "This guy looks like Julio Jones."
And now he's he's off to Texas. I
probably won't even get to write the
email. So,
>> so I'm I'm curious. You know, Will
Mccclelay talked with us at uh Combine
and he was saying that one of the
phrases he really loves that Christian
Parker's brought in has been the
description of his brain works that that
basically like for mental processing and
things like that. When you guys have
gone through that evaluation, how have
you you used that term or tried to use
that lens to evaluate some of these guys
and and their mental processing?
>> Yeah. Well, for Caleb specifically, you
hear things like smartest Dback that
coach Saven has ever coached.
Incredible.
>> And you think of the number of not just
really talented players, but really
smart guys that I mean, that's that's a
difficult defense to master.
>> Um, you know, just the verbiage, the
calls, the pattern match, the the pre-
snap recognition off splits and things.
And Caleb has everything down. And one
thing specific to him that like just you
talk about CB talking about hey I need
his brain to work that like his brain
works so well because he loves football
so much and prepares at a different
rate. Like this is a guy that you know
digging on character at Alabama this
year about Caleb DS. said like one of
the reasons he left for Ohio State is
there was that week to week and a half
of transition from coach Sabin to
whoever the next coach was going to be
and he couldn't sit still and like I I
need a new defense to learn. I need to
get in my offseason training program.
And he just was like, I can't wait any
longer. And then boom, went to Ohio
State because he, you know, could not
sit still for a week uh to figure out
even who's who the next head coach is
going to be. But like he prepares at
such a different level and uh he he's
going to come in day one like a vet. um
like an advanced vet. You know, he's
going to be doing calculus when uh some
guys who are still year three and four
in the league are, you know,
>> they're still doing algebra. Um but he's
he's different and his brain works. It's
it's nuts.
>> Everyone was just glowing about him
being selected and and that process of
watching the board and how it fell and
then seeing him at 11 like, "All right,
we're going to make sure we go up and
get this guy." for you sitting back
having evaluated him. What was going
through your mind during night one?
>> I was I went into it going, "All right,
there's no way he's coming to 12, but
like I am I'm praying hard for it." You
know, like he I was drooling at every
pick. And kind of how those first five
six played out, I'm like there's there's
a chance here. And then I got to
thinking, I was like, there's no way
Harbaugh passes on a guy like this
twice.
>> And the same thing I said. It's like he
took Kyle Hamilton. He's going to take
down.
>> Yes. Exactly. And then uh and then shoot
it got closer and closer and I'm like no
way this is happening. And then just you
start like I got chills. I think a lot
of people did like even with the picks
leading up to it when we saw the Saints
didn't take him to like
>> it was like everybody just erupted like
we're going to get Caleb down. It's it's
it was pretty cool.
>> Well congratulations man. Thank you so
much for giving us some time and uh I we
got still one pick left. Yeah.
>> Maybe maybe more. Who knows? We'll see
how the rest of the day
>> go. Are you going to get greedy? Do you
already have somebody in mind you're
going to go have on the table for train
up for anybody?
>> Get another one of your guys.
>> Oh, that the haze is in the barn
already. We We've spoken our beast.
We'll see how see how it all uh ends up.
But then shoot, hopefully we're able to
sign a great free agency class after the
draft. We We've had a lot of success
doing that in the past, so hopefully
this year's no different.
>> Well, congratulations on an awesome
weekend, man. Thank you so much, your
hard work. We appreciate you.
>> Appreciate you guys. Eric Ellingsworth
with us here on the fan and
Dallascowboys.com
as we are now already in round five as
the fourth round is complete. Just a
couple of picks coming off the board
there. Kyle Lewis uh from Pittsburgh
going to the Dolphins. Ephesians Price
Sock from Washington going to the Ners.
And the final pick of the fourth round
it was Kobby Young the wide receiver
from Georgia going to Cincinnati. any
players that stand out to you that you
want to run through, Brian, between
those three before we move and lap over
to the
>> Yeah, I tell you what, it's great to get
insight like that by the way of just,
you know, what was going on in the room.
I'm sure I wanted I should have asked
him, you know, Eric, I should asked him
if like when you see the player that
close to you scream trade up, you know,
you just like trade up, you know, trade
up. So, BUT
>> GO GO GO GET HIM.
>> Got to go get him.
>> I mentioned about Kyle Lewis. We've
talked about Overton, uh, Bryce Lance,
what you know, from the Saints. I
thought that was a really, really nice
pick for them. As you mentioned, we're
now into the into the, uh, the fifth
round, and I think it started off pretty
good. Kamari Ramsey, the safety from uh
USC, um is a guy like USC, it's kind of
funny there when you were looking at
their uh their defensive players and uh
and you know, you're just like, man, how
does this team, you know, they've always
had they've always had really talented
players at USC defensively. I mean,
we've seen a lot of their offensive
players here recently, but their
defensive guys. This is when I talk
about him. He's a transfer uh from uh
from UCLA, so it's kind of one of those
things he he goes uh you know, from one
place to the other. But if I could talk
about him, a lot of two deep look there
at USC. And he also lines up in the
slot. And I really like this guy a lot
because his ability to play in space and
make tackles. It's it's not too often
you see him missing a tackle. I mean, he
is a physical player. You'll see him
wrap up when he gets a chance. I've seen
him make tackles in the open field which
has saved touchdowns. He had one in a
Notre Dame game against Love where he he
did down.
>> He fetched him in that game. Um playing
with his eyes, the processing, all that.
You could see he does a good job of
closing on routes underneath the
transition from the back pedal to
downhill player. It happens very
quickly. He's a good blitzer. I listen
for for the uh for the Houston Texans to
get this guy in the top of the fifth
round at pick 141. I I think that there
that's that's that's great great value.
You're going to hear us probably say
that a lot with some of the guys we have
left, but man, I'll tell you what, I
have a lot of respect for his toughness
and the way he finishes.
>> All right, let's step aside. We'll come
back. We'll hear from some secret audio
when it comes to Drew Shelton on your
newest Dallas Cowboys. will continue to
update you on all of the picks as you're
rolling here listening to the 2026 NFL
draft on 1053 the fan in
DallasCowboys.com.
All right, back here on the.com side as
you broke down Kamari Ramsey, the safety
from USC. We also had Arkansas get
another player selected, their guard
Fernando Carmona, Reggie Virgil, Texas
Tech Red Raider, the wide receiver going
to Arizona. Sam Heck goes all the way
Kansas State Wildcat. I gotta find a K
State guy that I like every single year.
Him and VJ Payne were pretty darn good.
The center going to Carolina. Then Nick
Barrett just being selected the
defensive tackle out of South Carolina
to the Chargers. Uh did you have any
anything you wanted to highlight of any
of those players there, Tommy, before I
break down Sam Heck?
>> Um I I'll go back to to Ramsay real
quick if that's okay, please. you know,
I wasn't the the biggest fan of last
year's tape, and I think it's because uh
USC kind of moved him a little bit to
some spots that he wasn't exactly
familiar with, but I don't know if he
could have found a much better landing
spot than Houston. I mean, I I I
struggle to see how anybody's going to
score against this defense. Um, so
consider me a fan of the the Ramsay fit
there. Reggie Virgil, the wide receiver
from Texas Tech, we were talking about
him yesterday when Caleb Douglas went. I
think that's incredible value for
Arizona. And I I'll step aside. I know
Sam Hec is your guy. So I'm I'm curious
to see what you think there.
>> Well, Sam Heck, I thought was the best
center in in this class. He He's one of
these guys that I mean I I love how well
he moves laterally. He has the natural
ability to shift his weight. He can
climb to the second level with ease. He
can pull. The stretch game's really good
with him. The footwork, the technique,
the base, the ability to redirect, and
he just keeps his legs moving to drive
defenders off the football. He's got
really good base and and and the anchors
there. He'll kind of keep his arms low,
then he just fires them up into the
chest. So, he's very difficult to fight
off his hands. He wins one v1's
consistently. You could just see he's a
smart football player and he knows what
he needs to do to open up rush lanes and
push defenders wide of the ball carrier.
Like, he just has a good feel for what
he needs to do. He can get beat by
quicker defensive tackles. You know,
that was something that I did think was
a weakness for him. But overall, I I
really loved his game. Watching him
against Baylor, Utah, and Iowa State.
Uh, watching him there against the big
Citrus was fun, but Sam Heck to me,
getting him in the fifth round, I think
that's a dude that can end up starting
for you.
>> Man, I am surprised by some of these DBs
that are still available.
>> I don't know what's going on with
Kilgore.
>> Kilgore, Wheatley, and Keith Abney.
>> Yeah,
>> Abney shocks me. I I think he's a really
good player.
>> We just had Parker Braillesford, the
center from Alabama, go
>> 61, 289 offensive lineman. Brian, that
sounds like your kind of guy.
>> One of the smallest centers. Yeah, guy
plays well.
>> Transferred for one.
>> That's the last one, Brian. That's Don't
let him do it, Brian. Don't let him do
it.
>> Bobb's never drafted in the NFL, so I I
understand where he's coming from.
>> Always been a board op. Always like
>> 62 289.
>> That's the only board I create.
>> Railsford played in a lot of big games
though. National Championship game there
at Washington.
>> Sure has.
>> Anything you wanted to add there, Nick?
>> Anything to add, Nick?
>> I'm good.
>> Anything to add there, Bob?
No, I to circle back on Kilgore, my 30
my number 34 overall player. I I loved
Jaylen Kilgore. I think he could play
anywhere in the secondary. Um just
really love what he brought to the
table. There's also a a safety Robert
Spears Jennings out of Oklahoma that I
was really high on. Um I I literally see
him as like a Donovan Wilson clone. Um
surprised he hasn't gone yet. Um yeah,
Hezekiah Masses out of Cow, I liked him
as well. Chandler Rivers obviously we've
talked about a couple times. He's at the
bottom of my top 100, but still um
surprised by some of these DBs.
>> I have no character or injury notes on
Kilgore, so I don't know what that is.
>> That's so strange,
>> especially with Nick Mori having so much
success and he took his spot and also
was good.
>> I guess Well, I wonder how much of this
is just getting your offensive player
while you can.
It's a day three party as the Cowboys
have made three picks in the fourth
round. They now wait until the seventh
round for their next selection. Or will
they? We'll find out as day three
continues here on 1053 the fan and
DallasCowboys.com. Zack Walchuk
alongside the Super Bowl winning scout
Brian Bratis. We've got Nick Harris.
It's an impressive thing. It's
impressive. We've got Tommy Yish, the
award winner from DallasCowboys.com. And
then there's Bobby Belt uh from 1053 the
fan and Bobby the
>> Bordop fame,
>> the master of all things AI. Uh as we
got our guy Shotty who's joining the NFL
Network right now uh giving some insight
there.
>> Can we play that? Are we allowed to
Brian?
>> Can we
>> are we allowed to play that beam?
>> Nope. All right. Uh but what we can play
>> what we can play bring him in here.
>> Let's just get Let's just get Shotty
down here. We do have the secret.
>> Drew Shelton, offensive tackle, Penn
State, one of your newest Dallas
Cowboys. Here's the secret audio with
Drew.
>> Hey, Drew. It's proud to make you a
Dallas Cowboy.
>> Let's go. Let's go.
>> Well, I'm telling you, I'm sitting right
here beside your coach and head coach
and uh he's been talking about you all
last night and this morning and your uh
your offensive coordinator standing
here. So, we are proud you putting that
star on your helmet. Congratul by the
way. Congratulations for uh way you've
handled yourself and getting a shot at
this and I envy you getting to play
these for next part of your life in the
NFL.
>> Yes sir. I appreciate it.
>> I appreciate you.
>> Here's Brian Shot.
>> Hey Drew, congrats man.
>> Thank you coach.
>> Hey, man. Yeah, absolutely. We uh just
uh we've been watching this track and
we've been hoping it fell this way but
uh you're a Dallas Cowboy man.
Congratulations.
>> Let's go. Let's go.
Hey, uh, the offense coordinator. I want
to say hello to you real quick. Hold on
one sec.
>> Drew, what's up? It's Clayton Adams. How
you doing, brother?
>> Doing great, coach. I'm doing great.
>> You ready to go on this journey
together?
>> Hell yeah.
>> We got big things happening here, man.
I'm very, very excited for you to be
part of this. I'm going to let you talk
to our offensive line coach, Connor
Riley. Okay.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Let's talk later today, brother.
Congratulations.
>> No doubt. I appreciate you,
>> Drew.
>> Coach Riley, let's do it.
>> Let's do it, buddy. Right.
Congratulations to you, man.
Congratulations to your family. You make
sure you tell the mom I said hello.
Okay. Get you here, brother. Hey.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Finally got you, right?
>> Yeah.
>> It's awesome. Drew Shelton. Finally got
you. Have a call back to the recruiting
pro.
>> Yeah. Jerry Jones always says through
it.
>> I always admire He goes, "I admire you.
I admire and I would if I was to go, I
admire the fact that you're a
billionaire.
I admire I admire your billionaireism."
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Washington just took a player that
that I'm I'm very high on, Joshua
Joseph. But I I'm interested. Uh Tommy,
you were just going through the
recruiting there.
>> Yeah, like Nick pointed out, Kansas
State was an offer for for Drew Shelton
back in he was the class of 2022.
Ultimately did commit to Penn State, but
I remember that Connor Riley, Cowboys
offensive line coach, came from Kansas
State. So that might be one that uh he
drew back on from
>> Yeah, he um he mentioned that uh Shelton
when he when he came on during with us,
he had said that Riley had recruited him
and that they had a a relationship.
>> I think it's a good reset. It's okay.
>> And I was I was I wasn't being critical
of that, Tommy.
>> No, I was sorry. I wasn't on the show. I
didn't hear that part of it.
>> Tommy, take a number.
>> Take a number. Just at the end of it.
>> What else do I think you guys are doing
wrong?
>> Settle up here with him. Okay.
>> We're going to jump Bobby to end the
draft. I've got
>> Bobby ain't making out.
>> Bobby ain't making out of this facility.
>> I'm happy that Bobby for both of us
>> that Bobby is here for day three. The
bubble gut stay.
>> I'm here. I'm speaking
>> and so far he is speaking
>> and yeah and y'all are wishing I
wouldn't now. See see
>> look at look how the turns of table.
>> You're good. Absolutely. Don't worry
about it.
>> Uh all right seventh or the pick 147th
here in the fifth round. Joshua Joseph's
the edge out of Tennessee is now a
Washington commander. if anyone can pull
up that commander draft so we can kind
of see how this is going inside the
division. But Joshua Joseph's I I had
him I believe in the fourth edge out of
Tennessee. Played that Leo spot for
Tennessee. Had a guy that had 22 tackles
for loss, nine and a half sacks, 23
quarterback hurries. Top 15 edge rusher
in the country out of high school.
Freakish wingspan for this guy. I mean,
and he uses the long arm really well.
It's a weapon for him. The bend, the
quickness, the power. I I loved him as
an edge rusher. Now, does he have an
all-around game? He probably needs to
develop and get a little bit better to
be a three down player, but I think
certainly as a third done third down
pass rush specialist, this dude can come
in and contribute right away. And they
needed help in that area for Washington.
>> Yeah. Um the class so far for
Washington, Sunonny Styles and Antonio
Williams, and this was their third pick
in uh Joshua Joseph. I like
>> Yeah, that because that was the the
10-minute Mark Ripen speech last night
for Antonio Williams. That's right.
There there has been a trade here in the
draft. Tell us Tyrie Wilson is heading
to the New Orleans Saints for a day
three pick swap.
>> Wow. Former number seven overall pick.
>> What a disaster for the Raiders to have
to just kind of give in on a fifth for a
seventh swap there for a first round
pick from like two years ago. We're not
that far removed.
>> You know what?
>> It never really worked out for
>> that is a that is a guy with
prototypical NFL size who did not work
out. Brian,
>> I thought it
>> that's another that's another that's
another point in your favor. Is that a
team suck at drafting?
>> I
>> Well, no, he just said we we they're
passing up the little guys for guys like
Tyrie Wilson and then he's busting.
>> Well, especially with
>> Yeah. Listen,
>> when did this happen? Because you would
fight me on the little guys, Brian, and
now you're just you're you're with me.
You're riding with me.
>> I just to me the I just think that the
NFL is going in a different direction. I
I do I grew up I I I grew up in the era
where Bobby was talking about and I just
think that now
>> I think that we don't I don't think that
we do enough. We let history and I'm
just saying this, Bobby, we let history
get in the way sometimes here of guys
that are really I I guarantee you there
going to be guys selected today in the
fifth round and we're going to be
watching games on Sunday and we're and
and someone's going to tweet at us and
go, "God, you guys were right about him
>> or you guys were right about him." You
know, and maybe there'll be some guys
we're wrong about, too. I just it to me
I just feel like that and I I just don't
want to be paralyzed anymore by by you
like oh it has to be this way and and
I'm and I know I'm I'm it's all directed
at Bobby.
>> Yeah.
>> But I'm directing it because I think
Bobby's representing the league right
now and that's why I'm
>> I get what and I get what you're saying
and and I don't I don't think I did I
don't think I uh that's a guy the
Cowboys like Bo Stevens.
>> I wasn't going to bring it up last time
I I jumped in with a pick. It didn't go
well and then you went into mute mode.
>> That's true. Um, uh, I think when you
look at the fact that it's just I don't
disagree with you on a lot of these
guys. I'm just I would look at it as
like that's just it doesn't surprise me
that they're not taking them at that
point is all. It's just like okay well I
guess it doesn't surprise me that they
let that guy slide because they let
Desmond King slide and they let Quandre
Dig slide and they let Buddha Baker
slide.
>> Desmond King was a really good player at
Iowa. I mean you could watch him cover,
you could watch him, you know, high
point balls. You watch him
>> just a little under size. just ran he
ran four five, you know, he ran 458 and
and people didn't didn't like him for
that.
>> All right, let's welcome in LT Overton,
your newest Dallas Cowboy out of
Alabama. LT, how are you?
Congratulations. Welcome to the Dallas
Cowboys, my man.
>> I appreciate it. I'm good. I feel more
than blessed getting to go back home.
>> Yeah, this is this is awesome. It's
really exciting. We've been breaking you
down. We got to have one of the Cowboy
scouts, Eric Ellingsworth, come in here.
He was super excited to get you. H how
has this process been for you? How much
contact did you have with Dallas? Was
this a team that you were really hoping
to be drafted by?
>> Oh yeah, most definitely. Um the process
was definitely a long process, but a
process that I definitely needed to go
through. um me and anybody who didn't go
90 minutes in this 2026 draft. Um
from the from the combine to, you know,
pro day and the Senior Bowl, like I I've
always had a feeling that the Cowboys
had an eye on me and they've always they
they they have been keeping in contact
since the Senior Bowl after our play
after our little playoff run and since
then like it's it's just been constant
communication.
Alt, congratulations and and welcome to
Dallas. In those conversations or any
meetings that you've had with Dallas and
their staff up to this point, what has
their communication with you been as to
where they see you fitting into
Christian Parker's defense?
>> Um, they love me. They love how
versatile I am um as a as a deferment.
You know, being able to not just play
the edge and dropping coverage, but also
being able to move into that 32 and play
that four on the inside. They like they
like me. I've been hearing a lot about
the big end. Um been hearing big fit,
but yeah.
>> LT, you play with it looks like a lot of
power. Um and that just really seems to
stand out the way that you know you you
play against the run. Do you take pride
in just, you know, doing those little
things and and playing in in those
spaces that are or maybe not the
flashes, but you just come in there with
relentless effort, lot of power, and and
looking to stop the run.
without a doubt. Ever since I ever since
I stepped on to campus in Alabama, you
know, that power that power aspect of
the game and not just that, but that
runs stop has really been my bread and
butter. Um, something I really take
pride in is being able to, you know, you
got to stop the run before they start
throwing passes, especially how it was
in the SEC. But, you know, just being
able to open up, you know, open up the
opportunity for it to be more pass play.
That's That's why I love him.
>> Hey LT, congrats. Uh you're reuniting
with Tyler Booker. How cool is that
going to be for you?
>> Man, that's going to be amazing. I I
missed him. So I missed him so much.
Like I know how great great of a leader
he is and just being being able to be
under his wing knowing how how he is and
he already got a little bit of a feel in
the NFL. I thought it would be good to
do.
How great is it just for you LT the
opportunity to come in here play along a
defensive line that already has such
like really established big time, you
know, players like uh Quinnon Williams,
former Alabama guy. Um you know, Kenny
Clark. How significant is that for you
just to be able to play alongside them
and learn from them?
>> I mean, it means a lot to me. Like the
these NFLs, these guys been these guys
been in the league really probably as
long as I've been playing football. Um,
and just that information that just that
knowledge alone can tell you how much
how much knowledge and you know skill
they could they could pour into me since
I step on you know step into the
facility. Like guys like that I've
always I've always poured into
especially um transman had guys like DV
2 TK they they helped me through the
they help me through the way show me the
ropes. You know, you got guys like like
you were sending Dex to Mox. I know he's
been showing me ropes while I get there,
too. So, all props to them.
>> We're talking with newest Cowboy
defensive lineman LT Overton here on
1053 the fan in Dallascowboys.com. So,
LT, outside of football,
what what's something about you? What
What do you like to do to unwind?
>> Man, I love going bowling. Um, I
actually want do want to end up joining
a bowling league when I'm done with it.
>> There we go. Cool. I I picked up I
picked up you know saying Alabama you
know I started hunting fishing too.
>> Here we go
ATV ride you know being out in the
countryside.
>> Now are you more of like you want to
find a bowling alley that's like new up
and done or you want to f find like the
old like rundown smells like cigarette
smoke. I just want to find my bowl and
roll that thing.
>> I I like it original.
>> Okay. All right.
>> The old school Yeah. You know the slick
you know the slick on the on the lane is
going to be going to be right at the old
>> might slip on a Marlboro red or
something.
>> Yeah.
>> Well LT thank you so much man.
Congratulations. We're so happy to have
you here in Dallas. Have a great rest of
the day and we'll see you here soon.
>> Appreciate you.
>> There he goes. LT Overton your newest
Cowboy defensive line.
>> That's the college station in them.
There's there's not a lot to do out
there. I've heard.
>> Yeah. I mean, I would assume you've been
through there before and seen there's
not a lot to down there.
>> Yeah, I've been there a few times.
>> At least Tech has chimneys, you know.
So,
>> all right, let's hear uh the secret
audio from LT Overton.
>> So, excited. You are now a Dallas
Cowboy.
>> Let's do it, coach. You know it.
>> All right. We've got a spot. I can't
tell you what a consensus it is to get
you in here and the way you fit with
your skills and you of course you're
just a puppy and I'm smiling when I say
that but you're young I got you
>> that's got a lot
>> got a lot ahead of you here and so uh
but it's it's great I really believe
with your experience here at Alabama
that you'll come in here and you'll be
making some serious plays for us right
from the beginning
>> appreciate you coach
>> we're glad to have And here's our head
coach here, LT. What's up, babe?
>> What's up, coach? How you doing?
>> Hey, man. I'm so excited, man. I hope
you're fired up to be a Dallas Cowboy,
brother.
>> Yes, sir. You know it. You know I am.
>> Well, good. Hey. Damn right. Damn right.
And uh just starting your journey, but
we can't wait to get you here and have
you put in that work and you're going to
be a great player for us.
>> But appreciate it, coach.
>> Hold on. I want you talk to our uh our
defense coordinator,
>> CP.
Here you Christian Parker, our defense
coordinator.
>> What's up, coach? How you doing,
>> man? How you feeling?
>> Good. I'm feeling good, man. You know
it.
>> You ready to get to work?
>> No way. Me out yet. Tomorrow ready.
>> You ready to get
You know it,
>> man. We're really excited to get you,
bro.
>> I appreciate that.
>> There is LT over audio.
>> This is I have a tendency to overthink
things like not small players are not
the only thing that I overthink. I
overthink other things, too. Um, maybe
maybe I'm just like like seeing what I
want to see here, but I have noticed on
the calls when it gets to to Christian
Parker and many of these guys have like
gotten to know him a little bit. They
definitely do just seem to kind of like
it's like loosen up like, "Oh yeah, this
is this is my buddy. This is the guy
that I met on the road or what like
there have been a couple of these calls
where they immediately it's it's a
little less formal and it's like, oh
yeah, there there's CP again." And so,
and that's something that he got rave
reviews about when he ended up here in
Dallas was they were talking about one
of his biggest traits is cuz people had
wondered like a young defensive
coordinator. How is he going to be able
to coach veterans and different things
like that? And one of the rave reviews
you got about Christian Parker coming
over here was like, his ability to
connect with players is so strong and
and and guys really gravitate towards
him.
>> Yeah, they do.
>> All right, let's uh continue to run down
some of the latest pictures. The fifth
round is going fast and furious. We'll
step aside. Be right back as you are
listening to continued coverage of day
three the 2026 NFL draft on 1053 through
the fan and Dallas cowboys.com.
>> All right back here on the.com side. Uh
Nick, did something catch your eye?
>> Man, they were showing the Raiders draft
class on the uh telecast on NFL Network.
>> That could end up being a phenomenal
draft class. It could also end up being
a screaming disaster. Almost cussed a
screaming disaster. Um I I am very
fascinated by that draft class. Fernando
Mendoza, Traden Stuks, Jer McCoy, and
then they double back with another uh
versatile uh Arizona defensive back in
Daltton Johnson. Um there's a couple
more in there. They they took Mike
Washington Crawford. Absolutely. Mike
Washington to pair with Ashton Jensy.
Some fun there. Trey Zoom. There's some
fun in that draft class.
>> It's not just fun if if Germa McCoy does
bounce back. Yeah. if he does become the
player that he can be and if traden
Stukes can avoid some of the injury
stuff that that teams flagged with him
then like Stokes and McCoy can be
ridiculous in that secondary for them.
>> Stokes had the torn ACL in 24 but
bounced back really strong in 25. He is
going to be 25 years old when the season
starts but I I think he's he showed last
year that he's ready to roll.
>> Why don't why didn't people talk about
Stokes the same way as they did Meador
on the age?
>> Yeah, it's fascinating. there were a lot
of players. Is it because maybe maybe
the league thinks that older corners are
okay?
>> I I think it was more so about like the
age the age.
>> That's a good point. I didn't think
about that.
>> That's that's part of it also like I
think we were talking about Meador as
like a top 12 15 situation whereas we
never really talked about Stokes in that
type of light. Um but I I I think Stuks
he always kind of had that second round.
>> He's the one guy that you could watch
play in the slot that
>> then when they rotate the defense you
can see him play at safety. Well, and
that's that's the thing. It's not
unusual, I guess, for corners as they
age, they will flip to safety.
>> Yeah.
>> So, if they're looking at like, all
right, if he starts to lose a step, he
can move to safety. So, whereas with
Mezador, they may be looking at as like
when you're 31.
>> Butler, Charles Woodson. We've seen
guys, what about
>> was Laoy Butler a corner at first? I did
not realize that.
>> I'll tell you what, can I circle back on
a guy uh that What did you guys We've
talked about Wheatley. I had Wheatley
Penn State
>> corner or safety.
>> You talk about another guy that, you
know, 6'3, 2011 lbs. He doesn't lack for
confidence or courage when playing down
in the box.
>> I didn't think he was afraid of taking
on bigger blockers to make stops.
There's, you know, there's things times
where you can see him get rid of guys.
Needs to do maybe a little bit quicker,
but he could cover some ground. I I
think he did a really good job of
reading, reacting, pop as a tackler,
sharer plays around the line of
scrimmage, processing what's happened,
reacting to make a play, maybe some
snaps where he's a little sloppy as a
tackler, but some wrap up and then other
times where shoulder to the ball car
without wrapping up, but I I kind of
feel like he plays with some big time
range. I
>> Yeah,
>> I asked two teams about him. They said
third round for him. So, he he went
lower than people had talked about.
>> I I'm really I'm surprised. I I'm
surprised where he where he went.
>> Oh, he finally did go
>> in the fifth round. He went to Carolina
in the fifth round.
>> I'll reset all these picks when we get
back on the on the radio side. But yeah,
I was surprised that he was hanging
around as well. I had him as my 56 best
player, Tommy.
>> He was 54 for me. Big tall safety, good
range and speed, allows him to cover all
over the field. He's got good twitch to
react quick on plays in front or behind
him. Good technique in the open field to
keep ball carriers in front of him.
Sometimes he gets pushed back by those
bigger physical receivers. And like
Brian mentioned, I think he he relies
too much on those longer arms at times
to make some of those tackles, which is
why he misses some of them. Uh, and then
sometimes he gets his eyes caught in the
back field for too long. But yeah, I did
not see this guy being a fifth round
player at all.
>> Yeah, the Panthers drafted Will Lee in
the fourth round. So, Saki Wheatley is
going to have a lot of work to do on
making sure that that roof stays on top
because Will Lee, he's physical, he's
nice, but the second he has to turn
around and run, oh my god, you better
hold on to your breath. He gave up the
most yards of any corner that will be
drafted this weekend last season uh in
one-on-one coverage. Um that number
ended up being um 520. It was it was
tough for
>> And he he was number one over Chandler
Rivers.
>> Uh correct
>> at two and and Rivers still hasn't been
taken.
>> Correct.
>> He's he is still available right now.
George Gums Jr. from Florida. I wondered
if Dallas might take him on day when
they when we're heading to the weekend
at first and when they had a bunch of
like when they had the fifths and the
seventh and everything else. I had
wondered if he was going to be somebody
that they might consider in the fifth
round.
>> They've already got their annual Florida
player now.
>> That's true. Deon Moore.
>> We need Chucky D to come off the board.
>> I know. I was a little bit surprised.
>> Can we will Chucky D to 218?
>> I'm down. That can be the player that
we're we're watching and praying for.
>> Jaden.
>> Okay. Keith Abney just got selected.
All right, fifth round. It is rolling.
Zack Walchuk, Brian Bratis, Nick Harris,
Kyle Yman's will be stepping back into
in the next hour along with Vach
Lombardi. We've also got Tommy Yish and
Bobby Belt and a lot of picks to catch
you up on. Bose Stevens, the guard from
Iowa, going to the Seattle Seahawks.
Your buddy there, John Schneider, taking
an offensive lineman to block for
Jadarian Price, who he took in the first
round. Justin Jefferson, the linebacker
from Alabama. How many Justin Jeffersons
have there been in the NFL?
>> Two.
>> Just two.
>> Only one that matters.
>> Is there a bust in college at LSU at a
quarterback or am I thinking of a
totally wrong name person?
>> I'm not sure.
>> Maybe we'll do some homework on that.
>> I think you're thinking of Ryan Perilo.
Ryan Perley was not good either. Dalton
Johnson, Arizona safety going to Vegas.
>> How about this?
>> Zaki Wheatley, Penn State safety, going
to Carolina. Justin Jolly, NC State
tight end, going to Denver. That could
be a nice fit for him. Jagger Burton,
and it is Jagger. I went ahead and did
some research on that name.
>> Call him Joerger.
>> Yeah, Jagger Burton. We can call him
Joerger Burton. Uh Kentucky center going
to Green Bay. Jaden Duggar, Louisiana
linebacker going to San Francisco.
>> Oh, the Duggar family. Cowboys 30 visit
made a lot of sense for the Cowboys,
too.
>> Damonte Kapart from Clemson, the
defensive tackle, goes to San Francisco.
>> Dixon worked him out at his proday.
>> Okay, George Gums Jr. uh the edge from
Florida to the Colts at pick 156. Then
Keith Abney walks the Hatch own Arizona
State corner going to the Detroit Lions
at pick 157. I guess we can start at the
top there with Bo Stevens, Nick. Uh and
I believe there was some cowboy interest
there.
>> 30.
>> Bo Stevens, the guard from Iowa. Yeah,
he was a 30 visit guy. Um, somebody the
Cowboys were identifying. They didn't
bring many linemen in for 30 visits, but
he was one of them. Uh, overall it was
just really the connection there and he
ends up going around the range that I
would have expected.
>> Justin Jefferson, uh, the linebacker
from Alabama. Did anybody stand out in a
positive?
>> He was a formal meeting for the Cowboys
at the combine. Um, they they liked his
uh they like his leadership, but he was
really limited in in where where his
game was. I had him in the sixth round.
He's he was just kind of a mic option.
Agile and laterally quick, but doesn't
necessarily have the concept IQ to man
the middle of the field at the NFL
level. I thought his athleticism would
give him special teams on day one, but
that was really it.
>> That Keith Abney, I I tell you what,
Detroit with a nice pick there at 150
157.
>> He'll line up at left cornerback for
you. He's this guy's a championship he
has a championship roller speed skating
backer. So, you're talking about some
lower body power with this cat. Uh, but
his ability to turn to run with
receivers. I've seen him run down ball
carriers in the open field. He's got
he's got a physical competitive style in
the man coverage. He plays through the
stem down the field. The processing gets
him in the right position. His ability
to attack the catch point. His footwork,
his transitions, you can line him up
tight. You can play him off. He does a
really good job, a nice job of seeing
the play in front and reacting
accordingly. He did have a play against
TC where he came forward and then and
then uh they went right by him and so
he's got to be a little bit of of
careful about that. But you can see him
play with the depth, the mirror, the
match, the twitchy about him. I'm really
surprised he lasted with his tackle, the
way he tackles, the way he's able to
trigger and the way he's able to cover
fifth round Detroit. I think he got you
a good one right there in Keith Abney.
>> Tommy, tell me more about Jaden Duggar,
the that Louisiana linebacker that went
to San Francisco. He's got his uh Texas
guy just got
>> Yeah, that just got he just got
selected. Well, we'll I'll keep it there
with Tommy for Michael Taff, the safety
going Miami. Oh, not a fan.
>> You can talk to somebody else about
Michael.
>> Okay, I tell me about Duggar first, then
we'll talk Taff.
>> Yeah, Duggar was a really a tackling
machine for for Louis.
That's more of a bit than it is anything
else.
>> Please don't.
>> Yeah. No, Duggar was a tackling machine
for Louisiana Lafayette. Um you think
about the the just the last couple of
years. I'm trying to find the the
numbers here for Duggar. Yeah, he was a
Cowboys 30 visit reportedly. Um, and
this is this is a team that has usually
used these rounds. You saw with Shamar
James last year at these positions in
need to where you just try and fill it
in with guys that you feel like can uh
project for you. A bigger bigger bodied
kind of guy, 6'5, 239 pounds. A
Pittsburgh native too where the draft is
at. 125 tackles last year. That was kind
of his coming out party uh when he
finally stepped into a bigger role
there. He's going to be younger, too. So
that's that's enticing. Four sacks, a
forced fumble, and an interception last
year as well. So I think they viewed him
as a well-rounded player uh with a high
ceiling. You see there, 48 games played,
31 starts, all all sunb belt, fun belt,
whatever you want to call it. And then
he was a East West Shrine Bowl guy, too.
So they got another close look at him
here at the Star.
>> Yeah, he had the fourth most tackles of
anybody that I looked at on defense. Um
the versatility, I think, is probably
why the Cowboys took a strong look at
him along with his athletic profile. You
see the pass rush right there. I think
he had jack flexibility where he
probably could have come off the edge
and been an outside linebacker in this
scheme, but also could have been like a
Will or Mike, you know, similar to how
they've started to talk about Jan Barum.
I I think this probably would have been
a similar type of idea had they not come
away with that type of player earlier in
the draft, you know. Um, but I I I
didn't really know a whole lot about
Duggar. I knew he was on the East West
roster. Um, but I didn't really look at
him until I found out that he was a 30
for the Cowboys. watched him more and I
was like, man, this is this is a damn
good player. And I think he gives you
dam a day one special teams um and could
eventually be a defensive contributor.
>> Michael Taff, safety out of Texas from
Austin Westlake High School going to the
Miami Dolphins. Pick 158. Bobby, were
you a were you a Taff fan?
>> Yeah, I'll take this one for you, Tommy.
Uh he's bad. He is really bad. When
Christian Parker talks about brain
working, uh Michael Tap's brain does not
work. That's how that's when I watched
him play, his brain does not work. You
would think the opposite.
>> Bobby said, "You put his brain in a cow
and it'll start barking." That's what
Bobby said.
>> No, Taff was
>> he's a try works really hard.
>> I think I think Taff is one of the
players I probably screamed cuss words
at most last year.
>> Man,
>> he is a great story.
>> Think like he maybe it's mainly because
his arms are 29 in. Brian, just the
length I It bugs me.
>> He He's a great story. Former walk-on.
>> It's a nice story. Yeah,
>> I didn't think he was going to make it
to college to be honest with you, but he
he had a great career.
>> He had the physical and athletic profile
that I think, you know, allowed him to
succeed at times in the SEC, but it's
going to be tough to continue that at
the NFL level. Maybe as a special teams
guy, maybe. Um, and that's that's very
much a swing, but I don't know if he's
somebody you throw in if you want to
feel sa safe about your safety room.
>> I think he had the most busts in
coverage and the most busts against the
run of anybody on the defense.
>> Not good. kind of struggles to tackle,
too. We We were watching the Mike
Washington film earlier and Washington
just kind of ran him over. Taff had
everything right. Positioning was good
and then he just he just can't couldn't
make the tackle. Um yeah, I think look,
this is going to be best case scenario I
think for Miami is he's a great
specialteamer for you. He's going to be
a good locker room presence. Teammates
loved him. Um but I don't know if you
necessarily want him playing a lot of
defensive snaps.
>> Hey, him and uh Quinn yours were super
tight. So yeah, that's good out there
too. It's his buddy.
>> You got to think though a safety
>> if we're saying like he doesn't cover
very well, he has bad reads in the run
and then he can't tackle.
>> It's like I don't know what else he's
doing.
>> Special teams maybe. Maybe
>> if he gets his tackle in better.
>> That's rich in the fifth round to to
take a special team. You look at the
Dolphins draft overall. Kaden Proctor
from Alabama at tackle in the first
round. Chris Johnson, San Diego State
from the corner. Jacob Rodriguez the
linebacker from Tech. Their draft's been
nice over. Like I like their draft
overall.
>> I mean, it's not the the Proctor one's
not great, but Johnson at 27 is fine.
They got Rodriguez where they did. They
got Kyle Lewis in the fifth. Yeah, they
and then they've reached on Texas
College special teamers for some reason.
>> Two Texas players, two players.
>> They didn't reach on Jacob Rodri. That
is not a special teamer.
>> Yeah, he is.
>> You're going to be so wrong on that. I
will fight you.
>> No, go ahead. Go ahead. Why not?
>> Why? Why is he a special team?
>> Do you think he can play in coverage?
Yes, I think he absolutely can play in
coverage.
>> Why?
>> He's made plays in coverage. You see him
on tape get interceptions, get
deflections, he causes drops. Is it his
asset, his biggest attribute? No. But
he's I'm sick of people saying he can't
play in
>> Whoa. Whoa. Whoa. I'm sick of it.
>> He absolutely can play in coverage.
>> Yeah,
>> he is a solid cover linebacker. I Lewis,
no. Well, all right. Malachi Lawrence
played in the Big 12. Can he not rush
the passer?
>> Yeah, he can rush the passer. That's
different because he has a pass rush
plan. He has Arsenal. He has multiple
assets. Doesn't have a plan. That is his
game. Jacob Rodriguez as a downhill
player. Cool. Good. Fine.
>> If he's coming down and he's making a
play in the B gap, A gap, and you need
him to be in the right spot, he can do
that. But I can get that in the fourth
round.
>> Well, I mean, he went in the second
round. He could have been,
>> but he can't get the mustache.
>> He can't get the m the mustache. He
definitely can't get the turnovers that
he's able to force. And he does that in
coverage as well, not just forcing
fumbles, which he does better than
anybody in this entire draft class.
>> And the Big 12. What? What's up with you
and the hate for the Big 12?
>> I'm just saying it's the Big 12. Big 12
NFL, it's a little different.
>> You'll be just fine. All right, Nick,
we'll play this back in five years and
Nick can wear this as he was wrong that
Jacob Rodriguez was just a special teams
guy when he's making Pro Bowls for the
Miami Dolphins. Best pick of the draft
there. Miami taking Jacob Rodriguez.
>> Whose draft do you all like today so
far?
>> Kansas City.
>> Kansas City is so much fun.
>> I think Miami.
>> Kansas City is great. I think
>> got Chris Johnson, Rodriguez, Lewis,
>> Houston,
>> Chris Bell, great value picks there.
>> Houston's draft.
>> Houston's did a good job.
>> Yeah, Rutled with
>> I don't know how they're how
>> I mean Buffalo's depending on what
Freeling turns into. Buffalo could be
good. They got Freeline, they got Lee
Hunter, they got Chris Brazzle.
>> That's Carolina or uh Carolina. Yeah,
they got Freeline, Hunter, Brazle, Will
Lee, Sam Heck, Zaki Wheatley. Okay, we
had Vonach's guy, Billy Shrath, just go.
The guy who looks like a Billy Shrath,
Notre Dame guard, going to the Tampa Bay
Buccaneers. Pick one.
>> This guy is a starting left guard for
the Irish. He's a team captain. He's got
some mer elements to his game. I would
not call him that good of a foot
athlete, but he gets the job done. 65
310 is what I'm working with. He plays
with some upper body power and having to
take the defender right down the middle
as a pass rusher. the more movement he
has to deal with, the more likely he's
going to struggle in order to reirect
and stay in front. I think he's a good
run blocker when it comes to the double
teams, the combo blocks. He also shows
the ability to angle block uh and to
shield his man from the play. He'll work
hard to finish, but it's uh he also
he'll get held in place. Uh I don't
think he's the best player in space when
it comes to pulling or playing on the
second level. Could be a step slow late
arriving on screens involving pulls. uh
he doesn't have much sustain when on the
outside aware for games and twist. Uh
he's going to put himself position with
that awareness. Uh he's not going to
miss an opportunity to pick up uh the
right guy. Uh he didn't get fooled. He
hurt his ACL in the UC uh the USC game.
He missed the last five games of the
season. So you had to kind of catch him
early. Um and he hurt his ankle in 20
2024 which required surgery as well. But
I like his toughness. I don't like his
lack of athletic ability for the
position and we you know I think you're
asking him to play like a power gap
scheme if it was me.
>> Yeah, he he's a guy that his defenders
just get into his face on a regular
basis and I don't know if that is a a
trait. I don't know how that works for
him, but it feels like he draws a lot of
hands to the face penalties to Billy
Trout. I I wasn't a huge fan of his
game, but in the fifth round, why the
hell not?
>> Tell you what, the the Detroit Lions
have a couple of my pet cats. I really
liked Blake Blake Miller uh the tackle
out of Clemson. I liked his run game
stuff, not necessarily pass protection.
I don't know like
>> I Well, I say I say that for first round
perspective. Um I I do think he's a mer
though and he's uh didn't miss a game at
Clemson. Jimmy Ralder they got in the
fourth round. Uh had him as my
linebacker five. I loved Ralder a lot.
And then they got Keith Abney just
recently. And Derek Moore is a player
that I really like as well. Um that's in
that mix.
>> All right, let's go ahead uh take a
quick break. We'll be back. We'll recap
all of the rest of the fifth round.
Kansas City on the clock right now, pick
161, followed by Baltimore, Minnesota.
We can recap what the Cowboys have done
so far in day three as you are listening
to continuing coverage of the 2026 NFL
draft of 1053 the fan and
DallasCowboys.com.
>> And I like this Texans class, too.
>> There some teams
>> the Texans have had a good draft.
>> There are some teams that didn't like
Kilgore's medical, apparently. M okay.
So, okay. Who
>> I don't know if that was universal. It
took a while for me to get somebody to
say that.
>> Who's everyone still got as your best
player left?
>> Rivers. Rivers would be my number one
guy.
>> Rivers is mine as well.
>> Duke. Um
>> Gilgore.
>> Or well, actually.
>> Emit Johnson would be up there, too. The
Nebraska running back.
>> Uh Daniels, you guys told me he's got
medical or character. Which one? CJ
Daniels from Miami. What's his Didn't
someone tell me character? Medical
something.
>> Uh I think he was character. Okay.
Nusmeer would be probably being a bad
guy. LSU guy.
>> I don't think a bad guy. I think just
didn't
>> being a bad guy.
>> Teams didn't like the way he
interviewed. They they needed they
needed questions answered and they
didn't get them answered the way they
needed to.
>> Elliot from Arizona State, the
linebacker. I talked about Llewellyn a
bunch from Iowa.
>> Uh Kilgore, you just mentioned that the
medical might not be good for him.
>> Um Nate Nicholas Singleton, I'm
surprised a couple of these running
backs. Maybe we're going to get into the
sixth round like we did last
>> running back. All these running backs.
>> Oh, there goes EMTT Johnson. Him and
Kenneth Walker.
>> Kansas City. I feel I feel a little I
with I'm glad Kansas City took him. I
think Andy's got a good eye for these. I
Okay, he missed on that LSU kid.
>> Uh
>> oh, Clyde Edwards.
>> Yeah. And I And I thought Clyde Edwards
was going to be really good.
>> Yeah.
>> Jordan Jefferson. That's who I was
thinking.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Jordan Jefferson was the bust at LSU. Uh
did you want to talk about Emma Johnson?
Yeah, I I love Emtt Johnson and I just
continue to fall in love with this
Chief's class. Uh running back out of
Nebraska 5'11, 190. Great outside runner
who likes who runs like he's mad at the
ground and he really hurts defenses when
he turns that corner. Uh in space in
general, he's able to help out a lot
even just a quick receiving game. He's
got good startup speed that allows him
to fly through some holes at the line of
scrimmage at the beginning of plays with
one cut. But he doesn't have necessarily
the best top end speed. Kind of just
hits it and and glides from there. um
doesn't have the build for I think being
a between the tackles kind of thumper
guy but he's able to hold on through
contact just great effort to keep his
legs moving while he's being wrapped up
and get as much as he can. So consider
me a fan of Emtt Johnson.
>> I'm with you man. I Emtt Johnson is one
of the best all-around backs I thought
in the draft. I think the problem might
be the amount of carries.
>> Yeah.
>> So I mean he he was Nebraska's offense
for the most part but you talk about a
guy who runs really hard between
tackles.
>> It's the Ravens.
>> Oh you got to be kidding me. Brian's
about to give us it's uh one of his it's
the Ravens.
>> It's the Ravens. Chandler Rivers
cornerback from Duke going to Baltimore
at pick 162. Kansas City and the Ravens.
Just backtoback picks right there. I I I
to circle back on Emit Johnson. Tommy, I
think you got the player exactly right.
>> Uh I I do think that probably the number
of carries uh is probably playing in
here, but I I listen I I know that Bobby
and I have had some fun kind of going
by. It hadn't been fun. I mean it's it's
it's it's it it's it's tough for me just
because again growing up in an era where
size and all this stuff but I think
there comes a point in time and maybe
it's the fifth round maybe I thought too
much of a kid uh that uh that that plays
I think at a very very high level uh
when it comes to uh you know you could
watch him the tape was very very good uh
with with him and and the way that he
was able to to stay with people to stay
in fa phase I watched him play his
screens. I watched him react. I thought
this was super impressive by uh by the
way that he was able to to come downhill
to fly downhill. Him ponds, those are
the guys I really liked watching play.
But you see with Rivers, he'll line up
on the left side of the defense. He'll
play in the slot. He'll play at safety.
Uh just depending on the formation, he
reads the play, he makes the play, he
excels in zone coverage as a player.
>> Uh he'll open and move sideways as fast
as he can pedal. Uh you see him kind of
reading the quarterback's eyes. He's got
a natural feel for where the ball is
going. He puts himself in positions to
make plays. He's a master of creating
turnovers is with his aggressive style
of play. He plays with a great great
deal of flexibility and balance for the
position. I thought he triggered quickly
when the ball's thrown in front of him
or into the flat. He doesn't shy away
from contact. Um he remind me a lot of
what Maxwell Haristen from Kentucky was
in 2025.
>> Yeah,
>> he's smart, he's tough, and he's got
playmaking ability.
>> This is a tough one. Uh Charles and then
and then here's another one.
>> Charles Demings Austin.
>> Yeah, there's here's another going to
the Minnesota Vikings.
>> Doc D. Man,
>> we didn't make them,
>> man. The Vikings love their big tall
corners, man. I love it. That's going to
be that's that's a great pick for them.
>> Yeah, this they just won the draft.
>> This is a 30 visit for the Cowboys,
right?
>> About to be back on on the on the radio
side. We can talk about him there. Have
they taken a safety Minnesota?
>> They hadn't through like three picks.
>> I still don't know that they have. And
that was the one position we thought
that they would definitely address.
>> DT tackle, linebacker, DT tackle, O
tackle, safety, Jacobe Thomas, tight
end.
>> Okay. Okay. Jacobe Thomas. There we go.
>> Two defensive tackles though.
Back here on 1053, the fan the 2026 NFL
draft here on the fan and
DallasCowboys.com. Zack Walchuk
alongside Brian Bratis, the Jacob
Rodriguez, Hading, Nick Harris. We've
got the one and only Tommy Arsh got you
down. Woohoo. And then of course Bobby
Belt. Uh we will be joined again by
Kyleman's and Vaj Lombardi here very
very soon. A couple of really good picks
have just come off the board. We had
EMTT Johnson, the running back from
Nebraska. Go big red to the Chiefs. Gets
to uh you know continue to wear those
colors. Chandler Rivers, cornerback from
Duke going to the Ravens. Charles
Demings cornerback Stephen F. Austin
going to the Minnesota Vikings. Uh let's
go ahead. I know you broke down Chandler
Rivers on the dot side. Brian, but this
was one of our favorite players. Uh
Nick, you did bring up a great point
about the amount of plays that he does
allow in coverage and that's even with
having a pretty darn good safety. He is
a bit of a gambler, but he's just super
tough. He does make a lot of plays on
the ball. So, it's a little bit of give
and take there, but I think getting him
here at pick 162, another great pick for
the Ravens, Brian.
>> Yeah, I mean, we always talk about this.
We kind of laugh about the Ravens. They
sit there and good players seem to fall
in their lap. But this guy, I I, as I
mentioned on the.com site, I think he's
got a real feel for where the ball's
going to go and he puts himself in
position to make those plays. Um, that
that when he triggers out of zone, he
can play sideways when, you know,
playing in zone. I said he almost pedals
or he moves better even playing sideways
better than he and his back pedal, but
uh he doesn't shy away from contact.
He's more than willing to come and come
forward to make a play. He can knife
under blockers. I think he, you know,
you seem kind of keep his balance and
then trip up the ball here. You know,
his lack of height will cause him some
issues in the red zone and he can get
matched up that way. U but he has
similar traits. I I thought this was
what Maxwell Haristen, I believe. Where
did he end up? Buffalo Bills. Buffalo
Bills that got hurt, right? Correct.
>> And so, yeah, but this kid was smart.
He's tough, and I I think he's got some
playmaking ability. I think in the fifth
round,
>> uh, you know, if you're the Ravens, uh,
yeah, this is you're looking for some
traits, and the kid shows some
toughness.
>> All right, Charles Demings, Stephen F.
Austin. We were trying to hope for him
to maybe make it to the seventh. He
doesn't, and he goes 163 to the Vikings.
Tommy,
>> yeah, that was tough. Uh Chuck D was
probably one of the one of my favorite
prospects we've covered. Uh D is what
you called public enemy, man.
>> His nickname is Chuck D and Chuck D.
That's what everybody he says everybody
calls him that. Uh we talked to him at
the Senior Bowl and it was one of the
best interviews I think we've ever done.
Nick was there. He can he can attest to
that if he'd like to. But uh this is a
high character guy. He's going to really
make a positive impact in the locker
room. At the very least, I think he
gives you something on special teams.
You mentioned it being, you know, one of
those trees at corner. Uh I think he's
6'1 an eighth, 193 pounds, 32 inch arms.
So, at the very least, you're getting a
very positive presence in your locker
room. He can give you some stuff on
special teams. He had four picks last
year.
>> Yeah. Jacks.
>> Yeah, Tommy. Good job on that one as
well. The the the thing about him is he
he should be at one of these schools. He
should be at like Houston or one of
these. I mean, Stephen F. Also, nothing
against the the Jacks, but he this they
missed him. We we miss this kid in the
Southwest, you know, scouting him up.
He's got the frame. He's got the
movement skills. He could, you know, he
could play as a boundary corner. He
needs to be in a scheme where they let
him play press, let him play tight man
coverage on outside. He's got some hip
fluidity. He stays in phase and routes.
He could he has the speed to carry
routes. Um he's got coverage production.
And you know, when you watch him play,
he had nine interceptions in four years,
it tells you as a player who shows up
when the ball's in the air, you know,
it's off coverage reads maybe needs to
improve a little bit, but you put this
guy in a pressheavy system,
>> he can he could really he could do some
some some good stuff. His athletic
testing is always real good, but yeah, I
think some I think some schools missed
this guy uh when it came to recruiting
and maybe bringing him in.
>> Jacksonville,
>> he got offers. I'm sorry. I mean,
>> no, no, go ahead. finish this up.
>> He he got offers to play elsewhere, but
he wanted to stay at SFA.
>> Go ahead.
>> Uh Jacksonville just took the Houston
tight end, and boy, right before that,
>> so like I mean about 20 minutes ago,
somebody had texted me and said
Jacksonville has overdrafted every
player they've taken.
>> Jacksonville's class has been really
Well, but this is a team that does
things their own way.
>> They are the Jags, just a guy, but they
have the Rams.
>> Well, yeah, they don't go They don't
Well, they don't do the combine stuff.
They don't do the they don't do the 30
visits. They just naturally just, you
know, they they kind of maybe this is,
>> you know, something to think about.
Maybe Bobby, you're right. Maybe
everybody's a
>> What the hell is a thought process about
not doing 30 visits?
>> I I don't think they want to they I
think they want to just I think they're
really big on just taking the tape and
they want to take the player for what he
is and they don't want to be influenced
by any other thing. There's there's some
people who will argue it's not common,
but there's some people who will argue
that the interview process during 30
visits
>> influences guys
>> gives yeah too much weight to we liked
him like like like we liked him and that
that it can solely what you're
>> what you're looking at in terms of them
as players. I would think you'd want it
though just to be able to do the extra
medicals.
>> I would think I would think you'd want
it for that if nothing else.
>> Well, at least the players that don't go
to the combine that you got to bring in
too. The Rams do it too, right?
>> The Rams. Okay, so the Rams are are
fascinating the way they operate because
people around the league will talk about
them as though they're scouts have
become private in they become private
investigators.
>> Was that Marinelli's problem, Brian?
>> Fighting for guys, you bring him in, he
falls in love with them. Now you get
Tristan Hill in the building.
>> That's probably
>> they the Rams I don't know how much
things have changed there. And if you
look at the Rams draft, they also along
with the Jaguars look odd to me. Um, the
Rams will have their area scouts, at
least in the past, basically just
>> they will lean heavy on analytics and
different like formulas and then they
use their area scouts to just basically
do background research.
>> They're information gatherers.
>> Yeah. Somebody had told me their their
area scouts are private investigators
basically.
>> Yeah.
>> Well, going back to Jacksonville, uh, I
I I can't I won't speak for the rest of
their class. I think they they might
have reached on some of those guys. I
don't think they reached at all on
Tanner Kosio. I love this kid. I I think
that he was fantastic last year for
Houston. Let me find my notes on him
here eventually. I I promise I will. 67,
240 pounds. He's an incredibly tough
player. Seemed to take big hits every
game that I saw him play and yet he just
still gets up and keeps going and make
plays for the offense. Senior Bowl
wasn't really his setting. He struggled
that week, I'll say. But put him in a
game and I think it just completely
changes everything. He has a matchup
problem uh to the point where I think
refinement in his route running didn't
really matter when he was going up
against some smaller players that were
covering him. But if he can get that
worked out, I think that he'll
significantly improved. Not going to
blow you away with speed, but he's
tough. He's willing to pull it all on
the line. He was another guy that we
talked to at the Senior Bowl and I came
away really impressed with. Teammates at
Houston had nothing but good things to
say about him, too. So, consider me a
fan of that pick at least for
Jacksonville.
>> Couple of good picks, Tennessee with
Nicholas Singleton, the running back
from Penn State. And then Kan Elliot,
the Arizona State linebacker, going to
the Chicago Bears here at pick 166.
>> I like the Bears class.
>> I don't know what they were doing with
their uh second, third, and fourth
picks.
>> Talk to us about it.
>> These Well, let me let me go ahead and
pull it up. Um I think they they traded
for a center, I think, after uh Rolman
retired, and then they take Logan Jones
from Iowa in the second round. Um they
were part of that run in the third on
the blocking tight ends. They take Sam
Roo from Stanford. Uh and then Xavon
Thomas in the third from LSU, the wide
receiver, super fast.
>> Um but I and I don't really know what
the necessarily the plan is for his
utilization there. They've got a really
young receiver room. Um and then today I
thought they've been much better. Malik
Muhammad, I've talked about him a lot. I
think he's a really good player. I think
he will help them out in the secondary.
And then Keshan Elliott. I know we've
talked about him as a as a group, the
linebacker from Arizona State as a solid
player.
>> I mean, I like I do like what Dallas has
done. I like Dallas. I like the Ravens.
Um the Rams one is bizarre. The Rams
took Ty Simpson, which Shawn McVey
doesn't seem to want.
>> No, it's bizarre.
>> They took Max Claire as like the third
tight end off the board. And then their
final pick was in the third round. It
was Keegan Trost, who was a seventh year
senior at Missouri.
Yeah.
>> And it's just that I have no idea what
they were doing.
>> No, that's very bizarre.
>> But that was also a team that everybody
said the thing they needed to improve
was their special teams. That that their
special teams is what lost them games
last year.
>> And then Jaguars Nate Borcer uh in the
second round, Albert Regis, uh Emanuel
Predan, which you know pick.
>> Was it Medicals there?
>> Uh I think so.
>> Okay.
>> Uh Jaylen Husky, which I I liked Husky
not in the third round. uh Wesley
Williams uh the edge out of Duke, which
it depends how you feel there.
>> And I know one team had Williams as a
free agent.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So,
I saw a tweet earlier. It was like, uh,
do you think the Jaguars are looking at
their board upside down?
>> Let's uh let's reset that Cowboys draft
in case somebody missed some of that
fourth round. I know we've had some
texts coming in on the fan side asking
for that. So, today uh in the fourth
round, you had picks 112, 114, and then
137. Drew Shelton, the offensive tackle
from Penn State. Devin Moore, the corner
from Florida. And then LT Overton, the
edge from Alabama. Nick, you uh you
talked about Drew Shelton as like maybe
a guy that can come in and and seriously
compete with Tyler Gayton.
>> I I think you're if you're asking me, I
would love for Brian Shenheimer to come
out in this press conference later and
be like, "Yeah, Drew Shelton's going to
be competing for the starting job at
left tackle." Just just give even if you
don't believe that, give Tyler Gayton
that motivation going into the off
seasonason. um that you know there's
going to be a job on the line going into
uh training camp and with Nate Thomas as
well. You know, elevate that room. I
think they need that. Um I I feel
comfortable enough about Terence Steel
right now at right um to to to throw
Drew Shelton on the left side. I think
he's more of a left tackle anyway and
and see what that looks like from a
competition standpoint.
>> Devin Moore, the corner from Florida who
we got to talk with. We talked with all
these guys a little bit earlier, but
that is a big corner long range. can
play zone, can play uh certainly some
man. I think you like him more in the
run game. And it's not that he can't
step up and play in the run game, just
some I I kind of want him to be a little
bit more physical for his size, but he
can blitz off the edge. He's a fun
player. I'm kind of interested to see
what the plan is for Christian Parker
with him.
>> See, I liked the physicality and and
they they mentioned that a couple times,
too. Um and I I the plan is going to be
fascinating to compare with what
Philadelphia has done, not only with
Zack Bond. They mentioned him in the
presser yesterday. I I don't necessarily
see like a Zack Bond type role. I see
more of like a Jiad Campbell type role.
Um
>> Oh, so you're talking about Rashan. Uh
Jan Barum.
>> Jan. I'm sorry. I thought we were on
Sean Barum.
>> Barum. I'm with you 100%.
>> My fault. My fault. I thought we were on
Jan Barum. Uh you're talking about Deon
Moore. Yeah. Outside corner. Um and he's
going to step up and play really good
run defense. I I think in in my opinion.
Um and you wish he had more than 17
starts. I think the technicality lapses
probably come from that. Uh, and then
the injury history is certainly
something that they are going to have to
monitor and and they did. And Eric
Ellingworth came in and and talked about
the injury history. It was like, well,
it's more soft tissue stuff. We don't
feel like there's anything longterm. And
so that's that's good to hear from from
somebody about that and their thought
process there, but if he could stay
healthy, then yeah, I think this guy
could push that room for sure.
>> Zach, can I give a can I give a player
is due is the Tennessee's I because
we've talked about
>> Nick Singleton. Nick Singleton.
>> I just wanted to rehash I'm glad you
did. Cowboys by the way. Kilgore just
went by the way. That's a great pick for
Buffalo. Buffalo's had some stinky good
ones today. Jaylen Kilgore.
>> You want ahead? You want to talk about
Kilgore since he was picked? And I'll
circle back with single.
>> Yeah. And we do Elliot, too.
>> I would love to, man. I love Jaylen
Kilgore and I I think this is such a
good value pick for for Buffalo. While
he did play mostly nickel at South
Carolina, I I'm projecting him more as a
safety at the NFL level. Uh 61 and a
half, 210. It should give him the
ability to maximize the athleticism in a
range over the top rather than in short
areas where his compact bulked frame. It
can make movement a bit more stuttered
for him, I think, in the nickel. I still
do love him in the nickel, though. I
will I will point that out. I'm banking
on the potential position change to
safety being a super beneficial one for
him and for uh for Buffalo. If the ball
production follows him to the safety
spot, he had 21 pass deflections and
eight interceptions in the slot. this
could end up being an absolute uh steal
here for uh for Buffalo. Um and I had
him as my fourth ranked safety. I had
Caleb Downs, Dylan Theam, and Traden
Stukes and Jaylen Kilgore. I I I like
Jaylen Kilgore that much.
>> Yeah, he's he's a he's a really good
player. Brian, tell us more about
Nicholas Singleton, the running back
from Penn State who went to the
Tennessee.
>> Yeah, I this guy's extremely tough and
you look at him, he's 61, 221. Uh he
runs with an attitude. Uh there's some
some quick feet for the position. He'll
run through tacklers. He can be a hard
guy to stop once he gets ahead of steam
for a big guy. Does a nice job of
running in tight spaces. He shows
patience for the position. Kind of
allows blocks to develop and then
working behind his guys in order to get
the most out of the run. He plays with
some contact balance which allows him to
run through those arm tackles. I feel
like he's a better straight ahead runner
than one that's really kind of shifty in
the way he plays. I think he catches the
ball well out of the backfield. He's
softhanded. He could adjust the open
field to grab a pass. He was walked down
in the open field on some long runs, but
the speed, I believe, is good enough.
Love how physical he is with the ball in
his hands.
>> Yeah, I I I you get him near the goal
line. Game over. I mean, the dude has
the most rushing touchdowns in Penn
State history with 45. Nicholas
Singleton, tremendous. And then Keshan
Elliott, we disagreed a little bit on
him, Brian. I liked him. The
production's fantastic uh with him. I
mean, he certainly does have some
instincts. I I think he looks bigger
than what his size indicates. Like to
me, I think he's got really good size,
at least on tape, just from the eyes to
play the position, but he's a guy that
gives you some rush ability. He tackles
well. I just questioned a little bit of
the sideline to sideline range and speed
with him. But you uh you were a big
Keshan Elliott fan.
>> I was uh I think he's got some This guy
was a uh that was a wrong guy. Let me
get to Elliot here real quick. Uh
>> you should have amped longer.
>> No, no, you should have amped a little
longer.
>> Here we go. Vachy instincts, physical.
What else we got? Vot
>> echo. Come on. subdowns probably get
picked on in coverage. You know what I'm
saying? Stuff like that. My notes my
notes. He's a little older maybe. I
think
>> tracks down plays in the run game.
>> My notes went off. Here we go. Uh yeah,
as said is a blitzer. I think there's
some I think there's some sub package
stuff you could do with this guy. I I He
never stops hustling for the you know he
could tackle very well. I think he's got
the vision. I think he dispels the
ability to avoid, you know, to avoid
blocks and to get into position as a run
defender. I think he's physical. I think
he's got the play strength. you know,
his athletic ability might not be the
best thing, but he he you know, and
you're and you're right, Walchuck, he
doesn't have that sideline to sideline
range, but I think when you he's
sufficient against the run, and I I
think with the stuff with with his size,
you know, you could do some things with
him because of the the the quick trigger
and the overall his ability to to make
plays in space.
>> Did we talk about Kamari Ramsey going to
the Texans?
Sorry if we did a little bit. Uh we did
very briefly. Do if you want to go back,
we can talk some more Kamari Ramsey
because that I was surprised he lasted
this long.
>> I'm just I would love to talk more about
the fit specifically.
>> No, he's he's a player.
>> Gosh, that Texans defense, man, they
they just understand when to get these
value picks and and this is a perfect
example. Um you know, Jaylen Petri was
very similar uh simil similarly drafted.
Um
>> was he a second round player?
>> N Yeah, he was second round. Never mind.
I'm thinking of someone else. Uh maybe
it was
>> I thought I was losing my mind.
>> Maybe it was Kaylin Bulock that was
drafted a little bit later, but
nevertheless, that's uh two um USC
safeties that they've they've they're
going to put on that back end for uh for
Houston. I love the pick.
>> All right, we're about to get the
Steelers uh selection in as it looks
like it is another tight end that will
be off the board. Kendrick Law, the wide
receiver from Kentucky, went to the
Detroit Lions. We will continue to track
everything that's going on. Cowboys
don't have a pick till the seventh round
for now as the fifth round continues.
You're listening to the 2026 NFL draft
of 105 through the fan and
DallasCowboys.com.
All right, since we're just on the dot
side, I have been alerted from the man
himself, Chris Beam, that he has reached
out to Brian Shottenheimimer. There's a
chance that Shotti could come down. He
might not. He might say, "I'm too busy.
I can't do this."
>> Man, look at Beam with the connection.
>> If Beamer does if if he's able to pull
this off one, you're the man. Uh but
we'll have to just rotate Vachi over
here and shy.
>> Crazy as hell. That's the That's That's
the instruction I've been given.
>> You crazy ain't tell me nothing.
Hey, fellas, I got a question. If y'all
ain't doing nothing else, we just
talking.
>> Let's do it. We're just talking. It's
day three.
>> So, I was I was corresponding with uh
some of my audience there on my break or
whatn not doing some content and people
were kind of asking about some of the
Cowboys draft class and how they would
who they're directly competing with with
on the Cowboys roster right now. Uh
somebody was like, "Hey, Vatch, Drew
Sheldon just got drafted. Do you think
Tyler Gayton is in any kind of trouble?"
And I think my honest answer to him was
no. I think he's more of a I'm going to
compete with Nate and like develop type
situ. Like if if you're Deon Moore, like
you're more a Kalin Carson competition.
You're you're fighting him right now.
You're not fighting none of the top guys
right now. If y'all had any any thoughts
about, you know, the the rookie class
and how they directly compete with the
guys on the roster right now, like Ready
Stewart, for example, like Caleb Downs
going to come right in and be nickel
safety dude and you know what I mean?
Like what what are some of your thoughts
on it if we ain't doing nothing?
>> I've mentioned it a couple times. I I
would not be surprised if they throw
Drew Shelton into a competition with
Tyler Gayton, even if they don't believe
it, you know, just to be like just to be
like
>> just just to be like elevate Tyler
Gayton this off seasonason and Nate
Thomas both. It would not surprise me if
we're looking at a left tackle
competition in training camp.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah, I mean I think Malachi
Lawrence probably rotates right at first
uh because you got Gary and then
hopefully Donovan Enzaraku is healthy
and ready to go and that's I think
that's perfect for Malachi Lawrence. I
think that takes a little bit of
pressure off of him. Uh Barum probably
competes as an inside linebacker and
just knowing the injury history there,
he might end up needing to start some
games during the season. Shelton, I'm I
hope that you're right here. That would
be awesome to see him go ahead and just
push Tyler Gayton at least get get the
best out of Gayton that way. I think
that you're on to something with that.
Devin Moore I think special teams and
will compete as a backup safety and we
saw last year with all the injuries
there at some point you're probably
gonna have to start and then LT Overton
a rotational player. I mean what do you
am I off base with any of this? What do
you guys
>> just a question you want more at safety?
>> No corner. Did I say safety?
>> Yeah.
I my my question for the group would be
how open do you think the quarterback
room is competitionwise right now? Like
who can you say definitively is going to
be a starter for you? Don Bland,
>> Caleb Dson,
>> Caleb D. Let me sum it down. Just
corner.
>> Outside corner.
>> Outside corner. Your nickels good. Your
safeties are fine. Who's starting for
you at outside corner? If week one is
tomorrow, health is good to go. I would
say Bland and Kobe Durant. I would just
assume Rebel kind of got to prove
himself and work his way into that
situation. Then I would imagine that
Deon Moore is right behind him and he'll
be fighting with Kaylin Carson.
>> This should be a hell of competition.
Hell of
>> competition. That's where what I'm
saying is if if we get to the season and
you know Devin Moore all of a sudden is
the third or fourth corner on this
roster, I don't know if I would
necessarily be surprised.
>> No.
>> Well, see Kaylin Carson wasn't drafted
by this group and we have this
conversation every two or so years or
whatnot. So like if Kaylin Carson had a
sponsor,
did y'all see how excited Christian Park
was talking to Deon Moore? So like you
he kind of jumps him a little.
>> You think that more that they would play
him at safety that they would try and
play him with that with
>> I think they got a ton of safeties right
now. I think he did drop safety when he
was on the phone with us.
>> Yeah, he did say he did.
>> But he he mentioned safety.
>> Yeah,
>> I'm just saying it because of Hooker and
stuff.
>> No. Yeah, I hear you. And
>> with some length,
>> you might be playing three safeties
regularly.
>> So that that that could be a thought
100%.
>> Lock Hooker Downs Thompson. Uh Ready was
probably going to do some rotational
safety type stuff. If if they're going
to play more safety, I would imagine
they need more depth at safety. So
possibly. Sure.
>> Sure. Uh Joe Royer.
All right, sixth round still rocking and
fifth round still rocking and rolling
here on the 2026 NFL draft. Thank you,
Vachi. Uh you got me covered here on the
video side. Zack Walchuk alongside
Baratis, we got Nick Harris, we got
Tommy Arish, we've got Vach Lombardi,
Bobby Belt, Kyleman's rotating in as
well as the fifth round. We are now at
pick 172 with the New Orleans Saints on
the clock. Couple of picks that went.
Riley Noacowski, the tight end from
Indiana going to the Pittsburgh
Steelers.
>> That's such a steal.
>> Kind of a fullback, right?
>> Tight end. He's going to Hback. He's
going to play a lot of different stuff.
>> Crash test dummy guy. That is Mike
McCarthy's Hunter Lipkkey.
>> Oh, yes. Yeah.
>> Yeah. That's a lot of fun.
>> Ryan, Hunter Lipkkey, that that same
group of guys.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Joe Royer, the tight end from
Cincinnati, going to Cleveland. And then
Karan Prunty, the cornerback from Wake
Forest, is now the newest New England
Patriot. Uh, if anybody wanted to
highlight either of those players,
please take the floor.
>> Yeah, I don't know.
>> I can talk about Royer.
>> I looked at 30.
>> I can't I don't
have a ton of them.
>> I do not have name on my list.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh, Royer, you got to watch film in true
Patriots fashion. Uh, yeah. Royer
Cincinnati.
>> Here's Colton Strange, everyone.
>> Yeah, Joe Royer Cincinnati. Smart
quarterback friendly play quarterback
friendly player who can find his spots
in zone and sit in them to make himself
available. He's got strong hands that
can bring receptions in through traffic.
Solid as a blocker with room to grow.
Limited in ability to make plays down
the field. Kind of struggles to hold up
at times his lower body against more
powerful defenders when he's blocking in
line. Physical, but he's not necessarily
speedy when he's working after the
catch. He's more of a lower his shoulder
and try to pick up those extra one or
two yards whenever he's in those
situations where guys are closing in on
him and he's working after the catch.
>> Yeah, it looks like Prunty was the first
player that's been drafted I did not
look at.
>> Well, I don't believe he's even in the
beast.
>> Really?
>> Yeah.
>> Call Dane.
>> Karan Prunty. I don't think he's even in
the beast.
>> That would be a first time that's
happened for him since uh
>> I don't see him. I just
>> How about in the How about in the
others? Like he is in the beast. He's
got to be
>> He's 57 corner 57.
>> Corner 57. Okay. cuz I searched his name
and nothing came up.
>> So, you got to do digging down that
corner. Don't scare us like that.
>> Let's see what he I was shocked. I was
like, there's no way he's got 318
corners on here. How in the world is he
not here? So, you said he's 57.
>> Wonder if he's got anything good on him
here.
>> Just probably just height measurables.
>> Best of the rest.
>> Yeah, free agent. Sip. You're right. 33
inch
>> 445 76 inch wins span. 61 and a half
190. Heck of a pick. New England. All
right. Here's the Saints selection.
Round five. pick 172 as the Saints
making the pick.
>> The New Orleans Saints select Lorenzo
Styles Jr., defensive back, Ohio State.
>> Lorenzo Styles Jr., the brother of Sunny
Styles, who transferred from Notre Dame
to Ohio State, now a New Orleans Saint.
Ryan.
>> Yeah, I'll tell you what though, you
know, this is a again a very talented
family though and you watch the way that
this kid played. They the thing with
when you looking at now when you get to
this point in time, you're just looking
at the traits and I I when when you
watched him, it was I was impressed by
the kind of with the movement skills
with this kid, you know, as far as
somebody that's it's you know, the
football family, the background, but the
movement skills with him. I I could see
absolutely somebody making this guy a
free safety uh and and using him that
way. I don't know how much you want to
really play him down, but as like a true
free safety, I I would I I can
understand what the Saints are going to
try and do here.
>> What do we think about New Orleans draft
so far as I look to pull this up? We did
get a text asking about that. They start
off with Jordan Tyson in the first
round. Christian Miller, the defensive
tackle out of Georgia. Back-to-back
Bulldogs. Oscar Delp, the tight end out
of Georgia in the third. Jeremiah
Wright, the guard from Auburn, Bryce
Lance, the receiver from North Dakota
State, and Lorenzo Styles. There's a lot
of really good players there. I don't
think it's been a bad draft for
Kellymore.
>> So, they got the brother of Cleveland
Cavaliers guard Jaylen Tyson, the
brother of Trey Lance, and the brother
of Sunny Styles. It's just a bunch of
brothers.
>> Yeah, a lot of brothers,
>> black ass.
>> And then Oscar Dell's
>> I was looking right at you. I'm going be
honest.
>> It is a bunch of brothers.
>> I was like, I know V is going to have a
>> about 215 brothers in this draft, man.
Jeremiah right have a brother
>> I whisper devil
>> maybe
>> maybe he does Baltimore on the clutch
they got backtoback picks here 173 and
174 who's the best player that Baltimore
could Michael Trigg from Baylor that
would be an excellent pick you don't
think so this range
>> is that character stuff for him I mean
that's that's
>> have they taken a tight end
>> I don't think so have they came in
>> and everybody had them taking a tight
end in the first round
>> right that was who we saw a lot of mocks
for Baltimore
>> I wouldn't I I wouldn't be surprised
they go secondary again their past
defense wasn't that great.
>> They did take a tight end. They took
Matthew Hibner from SMU.
>> SMU. Okay. Sorry, I missed Hibner there.
>> VJ Payne, Kansas State, probably be my
best safety left.
>> Yeah, that can make sense.
>> Did Fitzgerald get taken? I I to Bishop
Fitzgerald from USC.
>> Hey, don't be shocked if he's better
than Kamari Ramsey.
>> Some teams had him as a UDFA, which
shocked me.
>> Yeah, that shocked me a little bit.
Hezekiah Masses, I really liked out of
Cal.
Masses was a Masses was one of the those
players. I know Vach and I were looking
at him. Uh you talk about one of the
ball skills and stuff like that. He's
like 179 pounds though. He's a little
bit of a
>> slider built guy, but the ball skills uh
were outstanding. I think he led the
nation in interceptions, I think, you
know. So,
>> uh and pass deflections.
>> Pass deflection. But how many he had six
interceptions? Five. Yeah. Five. Okay.
Five interceptions. So, yeah. this I I
was when you're starting to talk about
guys, you know, at this point in time in
the draft, you know, what are the guys?
I know Nick, you like to kind of remind
us, oh, this guy gave up a lot of yards
or this guy did this or he made a lot of
play. This kid was one of those guys
that when you watched him play coverage,
you know, he he had a really good feel
for that, how to put himself in
position, knock those passes down to get
some interceptions as well.
>> I wonder I mean, you brought up Hilner,
the tight end. How how high was he on
the Cowboys radar? Was that a player
that the Cowboys were were kind of
interested in the tight end from SMU?
>> Hibner.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh I I don't know as much him. Um
>> he was a local day visit.
>> Local day visit. There's another tight
end too there. RJ Maryland, son of uh
former Cowboys.
>> He got taken.
>> Was he?
>> No. No. Just saying.
>> I was talking about tight ends at SMU. I
think Maryland's the better player.
There was an injury a couple years ago
with him
>> uh that that limited kind of the speed
that he plays with. Um, but with all
these tight ends, I'm kind of surprised
that
>> he's still on the board. Um,
>> yeah, he's Russell Maryland's son,
former Dallas Cowboys.
>> Just had another tight end go and here
it is to Alabama. Uh, Josh Quavvis,
Baltimore Raven being selected here at
176. They did go tight end, but it's
Josh Quavvis from Bama. Nick,
>> back toback tight ends or not
backtoback, just two in the last three
picks. Yeah, it's fascinating. That is
fascinating. I didn't put a whole lot of
effort into tight ends. I'll be 100%
honest.
>> No, Quavvis.
I don't like I don't like drafting tight
ends. I'm I'm just not a tight end guy.
Okay. I'm But I watched a bunch of them
because people online were kind of
sharing the idea that, hey, this is a
loaded tight end class. And I kept
watching tight ends and I was like, man,
they lying to me.
>> Well, and I kind of thought the Cowboy
the Cowboys seemed like they were doing
a lot of homework on tight ends. So, I
kind of thought maybe they wanted one
>> and they they still very well probably.
>> Well, I mean, listen, I I I'm I actually
watch tight ends and but I didn't watch
>> Quavvis. I mean, you know, Trigg, I'm
sure Bobby will come in here and tell us
that Trigg has got character problems or
is a bad human being or something like
that,
>> you know, with Indris at Texas. I I you
know, I'm watching Texas play football.
The guy's making plays down the field.
Uh he's, you know, run after catch is
okay. You watch the Ohio State game,
he's making plays. So, you know, that
would be a consideration. I watched
Bentley uh play. I mean, there's I I
just kind of feel like there's some guys
that are that some other tight ends that
were left and maybe Quavvis works out to
be much better. I I didn't have him in
my in in my stack or on my board, but uh
I I have seen some tight ends I thought
that that Mike could play and that teams
are kind of staying away from right now.
injuries from Texas was an interesting
one just because I think it took a while
for him and Arch Manning to get on the
same page and that offense really took a
while to click and so typically like we
talked about earlier
>> tight ends and Steve Sarkeesian's
offenses have done really well for
themselves. So that was a little bit of
a disappointment I think for Texas this
year but
>> you go back and watch some of the Cal
stuff with and he was he was real deal.
So this might be some good value here
for somebody down the line. Couple of
former Cowboys sons still out there with
RJ Maryland and then EJ Smith.
>> Yeah.
>> Still out there in
>> Son of Emtt Smith. I think he's he's
probably projecting towards being, you
know, free agent guy.
>> Maybe that seventh round pick
>> maybe. Um
>> we like to do that around here with
running backs.
>> Be a fun story.
>> It would be a fun story. Come on, bro.
>> It'd be wild if they got UDFA, RJ
Maryland, and EJ Smith.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Bring them in. Uh the Ravens
still on the clock here 174 with
back-to-back picks. Then you got Vegas,
Kansas City, Miami filthy, San Fran,
Miami, and Buffalo to round out.
>> When you guys look at your board right
now, do you feel like you looked at
about 30 guys too many?
>> I mean, or stack 30 guys too many.
>> I'm feeling solid, right?
>> I mean, I like to I mean, I know we're
going to get into a sixth and seventh
round here, but do you feel like that
your board has a lot to it still?
>> In what in what sense?
>> Well, okay, I'm looking at mine. I'm
looking at mine. I know this is terrible
radio right now. But I'm looking in the
fourth round. I've got all these names.
I've got all these names and I wonder I
mean I guess teams are going to you know
like I say we got six and seventh round
but I'm just wondering if if teams if it
maybe even need smaller boards you know
when you start doing your stacks and
stuff like that
>> you know we need tiny boards.
>> It is funny just because like teams
typically only put like 180 guys up. I I
I I went to I was part of an like I do
two 220 names,
>> but I feel like I mean my Green Bay
Packer day is we were doing 140
>> interesting
>> 135 names on a board and sometimes it
Yeah, I know what we're trying to what
we're trying to do is because the
Cowboys don't have a lot of picks, but
we like to be able to kind of talk
about,
>> you know, all the players that are
picked. But I'm just looking at my
board, I'm like, I wonder if this was
one of those years I should have just
put 140 names on this board. It might
have focused me a little bit better on
some of these names.
>> Bobby and not build one, right?
>> Bobby doesn't build a board. So, I mean,
I don't know why Bobby's arguing with me
about anything.
>> No, no, no, Brian. We're just we're just
building a board for like 32 teams cuz
we're a 32 team program.
>> Oh, no. Absolutely.
>> So, we just happen to have 200 players,
but if this was just the Cowboys board,
we probably wouldn't put quarterbacks on
there for real. We probably wouldn't put
a whole bunch of running. Just I just
it's something when I look down I go man
I've got all these names and you're
gonna you're going to ask me who's your
who's your best player and I could give
you like four of them right now.
>> Who's your best player Brian?
>> Well Luwellyn Nusmeer
>> I am surprised Nusmeer is still there in
the fifth round just
>> that's a combination of things. Didn't
interview well. Um
>> maybe not smart
>> assist on the back and the uh yeah the
injuries. Yeah. Yeah. And if you're if
you're bringing in a quarterback with
that kind of injury history, then you're
not expecting him to be a rookie
contributor. And so you have to plan for
the event that he might not even be
available for camp.
>> Quarterback still there. Nus Meyer,
Tenon Green from Arkansas, Cole Payton
from North Dakota State, and Luke
Altmire from Illinois.
>> Okay, let's give an example here real
quick. And I know like I say, it's we're
doing it for the whole league here, but
this Adam Randall that that just went
>> Oh, the running back from Clemson, big
boy, 63. Is he a fullback or is he a Is
he a running back?
>> That's a good question. I think you
could play him at fullback much like
Michael Robinson did. I mean, he kind of
reminds me of that a little bit.
>> Okay. You you scouted him?
>> I I watched him. Yeah, because I know
Aisha talked about him uh on our show,
so I went back and watched him. I mean,
he's good in between the tackles,
runner, can catch the ball out of the
back field, solid player that way, but I
I could see the I didn't think of him as
a fullback, but now that you say that,
that might be his best spot. See, I'm
I'm thinking because I've got other
guys, too, like Moss from Texas A&M,
>> you know, uh
>> Taylor from Virginia. Yeah. Allen.
>> Al McGawan.
>> Robert Dam Henry.
>> Roman Hemi.
>> Yeah. So, I mean that that's it's it's
interesting that that some of the the
way that some of these teams do look at
some of these these these players and
and I just kind of feel like that. Wow.
Did I
>> What it is, Brian, is that you got guys
on your board that you like a lot and
teams are drafting dudes that you
probably ain't heard of before. I think
I think
>> I I get mad at that.
>> That's my problem right now. Like like
we're like they're drafting like the
20th tight end and I'm like dog Bentley
I thought was somebody that could be
talked about for real. You know what I
mean?
>> Exactly. Exactly.
>> Yeah. There's your backtoback clips.
Alabama uh picks to the Ravens. Josh
Quavvis and then Adam Randall from
Clemson going there with the Raiders now
on the clock and their pick is in V.
What you got?
>> No, I just wanted to ask the cast. I got
some some players on my board and maybe
this what me and Brian need to work
through. Maybe I'm too high on Let me
just ask y'all if y'all don't mind. CJ
Daniels, the wide receiver from Miami.
Did y'all watch him? What y'all watch?
>> There's evidently some uh character
issues there.
>> Character issues with him. JC Davis, he
was a tackle at uh
>> Illinois.
>> Illinois. But I got him as a guard
though. Maybe I got him. I mean, I had a
four or three on him. Is that like Did
y'all watch me?
>> Five on him.
>> Yeah, I put a five.
>> Uh Nuser, we talked about Llewellyn
Perkins. I can see
>> Perkins is a little surpris I get it,
but it's a little surprising someone
hasn't taken a swing on that yet.
>> Anthony Lucas got drafted yet. The edge
from US like what do we like like what
what am I missing with those guys?
>> That's that's the thing I guess maybe I
shouldn't have talked about the numbers.
>> Yeah,
>> maybe I should have talked about you
know when you go back and evaluate your
board maybe this is something
conversation afterwards
>> but you wonder like okay what what did I
see in what did I see in York from
>> tour and York can play though?
>> Yeah, it's saying
can play.
>> It's got to be small. You know, the size
and the speed with him, right?
>> But that is Dixon is another one. I
thought that Dixon has some damn good
film.
>> I like that.
>> Meanwhile, it's who this cat Michael
Taff got drafted. No disrespect to
Sorry, Tommy.
>> Don't apologize. I'm with you. Tommy
didn't he wasn't fighting for Michael
Taffy and them
>> Durant. Durant the defensive tackle from
Penn State. Another one.
>> Zay Durant. I'm I'm befuddled. I'm I'm
confused. You know,
>> y'all know how I feel about teams and
how they
>> have tendencies.
>> The tackles like Nick Barrett just went
uh earlier in this round out of South
Carolina.
>> Okay. Masses just went
>> good.
>> There we go. We just talked about that.
Way to go, Tommy. You wield it into
existence.
>> You're welcome.
>> To the Raiders. The Raiders again
continue with this draft. Nick, what do
you think about Masses? I know you were
giving him some love earlier.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Let me pull up my notes on
Hezekiah Mass.
>> My line. I pull up my notes.
>> CB13 uh 6 foot and a half 179. So, the
179 lbs. He does have a thin frame and
it leads to him getting overpowered
physically or overcompensating initial
punches and grabs, but he is super
technical and fluid. I love his his
technicality. Uh I think he's got
starter upside if he could just either a
beef up or increase his play strength.
Um he's got natural movement, footwork,
and uh there was a there's something I
learned in my recruiting days called hip
dexterity. And it's just the ability to
be able to move in and out and it shows
up with a guy like Hezekiah Masses. And
then you add the ball production in. Led
FBS in pass deflections last year with
18. He added five interceptions with it.
Um man, this is backto-back years that
I've kind of fallen in love with a third
round Cal corner. Null Williams was the
one last year to be good.
>> And I put a third round grade on
Hezekiah Masses this year. I expected
him to go early day three. He ends up
going here in what the fifth. U you know
I I I guess that's probably where the
league had him. I'm just higher on
Hezekiah Mass.
>> I don't think you're wrong. You ain't
wrong.
>> I don't think you're wrong about this
guy. I think he's going to be a hell of
a player. The Raiders I I think they got
a guy here that when you watch him when
you watch him play in coverage, when you
watch him play, the awareness he plays
with. I Yeah, he's 179 pounds, but man,
I'll tell you what, he is a guy that the
ball skills are there, the instincts are
there. He want he's a willing tackler. I
I I think that I think that that you're
talking at 175. Uh they they got a nice
player here.
>> All right, Chief's pick is in round
five, pick 176. After that, there'll be
five picks left uh until the end of the
fifth and then we'll roll over to the
sixth round as you're listening to the
2026 NFL draft on 1053 the fan and
dallascowboys.com.
Right back here on the.com side with
Kansas City on the clock. Oh, we're
joined again back. Oh, you're going to
eat. You're going to eat real quick.
>> No, no, no. You you guys go.
>> Oh, okay. All right. So, we're going to
do a little switcheroo here. Uh Kyle's
going to come back in the captain's
chair and uh it looks like uh Bobb's
just gosh, he's just eating some wings
right now and in a very seductive.
>> Okay, close to that mouth.
>> So seductive from
>> might lose a limb.
>> Look at him just winking. Just winking
>> or two.
>> He's going, "Wow."
>> Talk to him. What?
>> Let us know. Let us know. Uh all right.
Kansas City on the clock here at pick
176. And we got Miami, the Eagles, the
Niners. Miami again.
>> Tommy's liking Kansas City straps,
right, Tommy? I sure am.
>> They're going to take Tommy's best
player off his board. Watch this.
>> Who is it?
>> Who you got?
>> Who's your best player on your board,
Tommy?
>> Uh, Trigg Baylor.
>> Really?
>> Mhm.
>> Oh, wow. Okay.
>> I like Trigger a lot.
>> There was some questions. Tell me.
It surprised me. It just surprised me.
That's all.
>> It's a little shocking.
>> Okay. Why am I wrong? Cyrus Allen.
>> I just like CJ I like CJ Daggers better.
I like Lou Allen better. I like Perkins
better. I like the running back from
Wake Forest, Claybourne better. Rashawn
Benny Anthony Lucas better.
>> Can't say he just took a fourth round
receiver off my board.
>> Cyrus Allen.
>> It's the wrong Cincinnati receiver.
>> I like route runners though.
>> I love router. Cyrus Allen. Um, slot
dude. Can run a bunch of different
routes. Savvy releases. Uh, solid solid
yak guy. Not nothing too too crazy, but
he's but he's a little bitt and can get
pushed around a little bit. You know
what I mean? But I like the player.
Yeah, I got three players left with
third round grades. How about y'all? I
got Robert Spears Jennings out of
Oklahoma, Jeff Caldwell out of
Cincinnati and Deont Clayborn Wake
Forest.
>> Benny Perkins, Llewellyn, Nusmeire,
Davis Daniels, and Burke. Dalen Burke.
Dalen Burke, Arkansas wide receiver.
Yeah.
>> I'm sorry. I was just doing some house
cleaning here. I'm sorry.
>> No, take your time. I I um my last
second round grade to fly off the board
was Kilgore, obviously. Um, and then now
these third round grades are starting to
get plucked a little bit. I just wonder
when the running back run really starts
>> like it did last year.
>> Yeah.
>> Sixth round and all of a sudden Vot is
going to tell us about a guy he had in
the fourth.
>> You know,
>> cross.
>> Yeah, exactly. A cross merit player. Uh,
take take I've got third round guys.
Daniels, we've talked about Nusmire.
Something obviously wrong there. Uh,
Llewellyn would be a guy he is my last
third round guy. Llewellen.
>> Gotcha.
>> Gotcha. How you guys doing?
>> Doing fantastic. How are you, Kyle?
>> Kicking it up.
>> Feel like I haven't talked to Nick here
in a little bit.
>> Yeah, we've been off. We've
>> Have you been on the uh the sicko mode
yet?
>> Have I got I don't feel like I can
answer that. Have I? Have I?
>> I think I think we all
>> Have we hit that yet?
>> Nick certainly has done a great job.
>> Okay,
whoever wants to roll out, get some
food.
>> Just as I say that, I'm going to go eat
real quick.
>> Yeah, go eat.
>> Please do.
>> Oh jeez.
>> Brian, do you have any more five corners
left, Brian? Top five corners.
>> Five. Five corners.
>> Brian doesn't like me sitting next to
him because I'm
>> five corners. Bobby, you need a beach
towel to wipe your face off.
>> Bobby told over the state.
Over here.
>> Oh man.
>> Gosh.
>> D'Angelo Ponzi is a beach tow a blanket.
>> I'm surprised Fitzgerald hasn't gone.
Have I Did I miss that?
>> Bishop Fitzgerald.
>> Fish Fitzgerald. Nice.
>> Uh, what round are we in? Five.
>> We had five. Yeah.
>> Yeah. I talking to people, they had said
Fitzgerald was in the fifth for a lot of
teams.
>> I had him in the fourth and then and
then I liked was it Lewis Moore from
Indiana?
>> Lewis Moore,
>> the other safety that
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Lewis Moore from
Indiana.
>> I think that Dixon, you start to talk
about corners. Dixon from North Carolina
would be a guy. Uh
>> Deon Marshall also.
>> Marshall. Marshall. We like North NC
State was another one that we had that I
thought was pretty. Lewis Moore was uh
seventh for at least one team that I
talked to.
>> Yeah, probably a good drafting team.
>> You liked Lewis Moore? I thought
>> that's what I'm saying. Had him in the
seventh.
>> Bobby, do you have an idea of who the
Cowboys are going to throw $600,000 at
in about three hours?
>> Um wait, is that $600,000 in terms of
free agency or Okay. Um a bunch of
receivers, I would think.
>> I think that receivers going to be part
of this. So, so maybe in the seventh
round they grab the best receivers.
>> They get somebody they don't want to
>> they don't want to fight for.
>> There you go. I like that.
>> Can I throw a name out there for you
guys?
>> Receiver.
>> Can we say Can
>> Coleman?
>> Uh, what was it?
>> Can we say it on three? Cuz I wonder if
it's the same receiver.
>> Oo. Oh, let me do it, too. Can I play?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> I think I know who you're talking.
>> Long name or short name? Long name or
short name?
>> Short first name, medium normal last
name.
>> Mine is two syllable, first name, two
syllable, last name.
>> Okay. On three. On three. One, two,
three. Jordan
>> Benson.
>> Okay. I was going to say Anthony Smith
or Ben Patterson.
>> I think I think they do like Malik
Benson. Yeah.
>> All right. We are at pick number 177 in
the fifth round. The wide receiver out
of Missouri, Kevin Coleman Jr. goes to
the Miami Dolphins. Kyleman's back with
you. Thanks to Zack Walchuck giving me
an opportunity to go do some TV on the
uh DallasCowboys.com side of things
alongside Bobby Belt and Brian Bratus of
1053 the fan Tommy Yarish of
DallasCowboys.com F Lombardi of Crown
Global Media running down the last few
picks. The Baltimore Ravens at 174 take
Adam Randall the running back from
Clemson. Corner out of Cal Hezekia Mazes
goes to the Las Vegas Raiders. Hezekiah.
>> Hezekiah, excuse me. Masses goes to the
Raiders. Chiefs Cyrus Allen, wide
receiver from Cincinnati. And then we
just said Kevin Coleman Jr., wide
receiver from Missouri. Some of these
pass catchers coming off the board.
>> Kyle, you know something? I got um just
listed these these shorter wide
receivers. I got them all down my board
a little bit cuz I just don't value
short receivers in this way. But I
noticed that they all run three routes.
>> Careful about the short guy. I work with
that guy. He does the work.
>> But I noticed Damn. But I but I notic
that they all run three routes, but they
run three different routes. You know
what I mean? Like Zack Branch runs his
bubbles, slants, and hitches or
something. You know, Brennan Thompson
runs deep ball post, maybe like a slant.
Ke uh Kevin Coleman, I liked him a
bunch. He's he's hitch, dig, and crosser
guy.
>> And my small guys, they only run three
routes. Like that's all they like, if
you watch the highlights, they only
going to have those three routes. And
I've been undefeated at it so far. Like
even in the highlights, they just run
those three. Is Harold Perkins still not
gone? He ain't gone, Bobby.
>> Why? Why do you think?
>> That's what we asking you, Bobby.
>> I think it's cuz nobody knows what they
want to do with him.
>> Put him on defense.
>> He looks like he could play football,
but I mean, I agree with you. Trust me.
>> Damn fullback got drafted. I
>> I love Harold Perkins. He's he's my
>> some guy named Pertney got drafted.
>> Who that is?
>> They don't have a picture for him on
NFL.com.
>> No, from Karan Prunty from Wake Forest.
>> Prunty. They also don't even have like a
designated position. It says DB. Says
defensive back. Like they don't even
know if he's a corner or safety or
whatever.
>> This is like the
>> Clayborn from Wake Foright,
weight, nothing on NFL.com for him.
>> And who did he go to?
>> Uh New England Patriots.
>> Of course they did. What the hell going
on?
>> This is what happens when Vable's not in
there picking on the third day.
>> Boy, they go they go and make
>> I wonder what Philly's going to do here.
>> Do anything.
>> Trying to change the subject there,
Tommy.
>> What? Uh uh going back to Kevin Coleman
actually I I was I was a fan of his. Uh
I had a fourth on him. I remember when
we were talking with um Drew Fabianic at
the Senior Bowl.
>> He was raving about this kid from
Missouri. I had a fourth on him. I think
Vaj had hit the nail on the head in
terms of the routes that he runs. I
think he's great when he comes across in
formation. He's got the change of
direction to give corners fits in the
middle of the field. Solid hands, but
he's got, like V said, kind of a limited
route tree with only three or so that he
runs. likes to go over the middle, get
those quick, easy receptions. Um, so
consider me a fan of of Kevin Coleman.
It'll be an interesting fit there in
Miami.
>> Some of these these names in the the
fifth round as I'm doing some
housekeeping myself. I mean, Parker
Braillesford goes off the board. I liked
him. Joshua Joseph, the edge rusher from
Tennessee, good solid player. Justin
Jefferson, the linebacker from Alabama.
You I remember you talking about Justin
Jolly, tight end from NC State. You
liked him a lot.
>> Blocker. Yeah. Catcher, blocker kind of
guy. What's going on with Dion Burks?
>> Maybe injury question marks there.
>> We're at a disadvantage there because if
it is an injury thing
like
>> Oh, wait. No, he is 510 though.
>> Yeah, he's a smaller guy, but he was
nice at Purdue. I said he's a smaller
guy. That's He's 510. That's I'm not
saying he's a bad player.
>> That would be a smart thing to say.
>> He's gonna get mad at you, not at me.
So,
>> I like I like I like Brian's little
guys. the uh
Philadelphia fifth round pick.
>> Man, I like Cole
>> 178. They take the quarterback from
North Dakota State, Cole Payton.
>> Garrett Nusmire must have just blown
these interviews.
>> It It has to be just catastrophic,
right?
>> The fact that he's still on the board
and they're taking other quarterbacks
here
>> there. I mean, I had asked about
Nusmeire a couple weeks ago and I had
heard third round and he's just still
sitting there.
>> A quarterback who was thought to be a
third round are still sitting there now.
is that's not
>> Well, it's very reminiscent of what
happened to to the to uh Deion Sanders
>> Shadore.
>> Yeah,
>> it's a good point. Second year in a row
we've seen a a drop like that uh from
the quarterback position. The uh
>> but not anyone to talk about this kid
though, Cole Payton.
>> Yeah,
>> I think you liked him, right? Botch,
>> you know, I I thought he was Dak coming
out of Mississippi State like not like
Cowboy Dak, but like Mississippi State
run you over toughness. He's
left-handed. deck ain't left-handed, but
I thought he threw the ball with some
pretty decent touch. Uh I felt like even
when he wasn't starting like these
previous three years or whatever, he was
still getting involved as just running
the football read option type stuff. But
then when they actually let him throw
the football, I thought he was able to
make some cool little throws. I thought
he placed the ball really well. And um
of course he, you know, when he runs, I
mean teams going to try to make him
slide, but uh in college he was trying
to run folk over and I just love how
like physical he was as a runner. U I I
actually had him pretty high. I I was uh
I had a fourth on him and um man, you
know, maybe I'm just a maybe I'm just a
sucker for for tough football play, but
>> yeah, imagine that. Oh, that doesn't
work out very often. How about that?
>> But the Brian, I'll tell you this. I do
worry, Bill, about what's going on with
NMER. I' I'd love for that's and I'm
going to reach out to I'm going to start
hitting some gang of seven here in a
second. Uh the thing with Payton, man,
is that he he's a lefty and sometimes
the mechanics, you know, usually with a
left-handed quarterback, you could kind
of like I mean, they're really really
pretty mechanics, but his are just
they're okay. And I and I feel like that
maybe somebody will work with him on
this. I didn't know Vi and I got in a
discussion about I didn't know if he had
the the ability to drive the ball,
>> you know, with the way he throw but the
touch was really really good. And maybe
it's like he's all of a sudden he's
developed touch because he doesn't and
here I am I'm like arguing for Drew
Allard cuz I think he could throw a ball
through a car wash and it won't get wet.
Yeah. You know that kind of thing.
>> But this guy is when you start to talk
about dual threat and like the ability
to and this will give him something a
little bit of a different look too with
him being left-handed. But this guy's
got 31 career rushing touchdowns. So,
you know, he there's some manufactured
runs, called runs, but uh I mean, you
watch him move around and throw the
ball, he can he can he could make some
winning plays and he's under duress at
times and and and he's able to make
those plays. So, I just didn't like the
the arm talent with him, but everything
else about him, I think, is is pretty
good. The Eagles might have might have
uh you know, you're kind of looking for
the lottery ticket here. you know, maybe
they work with him and he he gets a
little bit better with the mechanics and
builds a little bit more strength.
>> I've seen him hurdle like six guys on
highlight tape that we're watching here.
This is also 10 years after they took
the last North Dakota State quarterback
that drafted Carson Wentz.
>> Uh Trey Lance.
>> No. Oh, that was drafted by the Eagles.
By the Eagles?
>> I thought you were just talking about
it.
>> No, no, no. There have been a couple
guys since
>> No disrespect to Trey.
>> With that being said, though, does that
bring up any sort of concern? I know you
don't want to scout the helmet and
things like that, but with it being
FCF's versus FBS, at least for now, the
the past failures of North Dakota State
players, specifically quarterback
position,
>> I used to think that with Penn State
running backs.
>> Yeah.
>> And then Mississippi State started
having problems with defensive tackles.
>> And I, you know,
>> was that didn't it used to be Tedford
quarterbacks, too? Jeff Tedford
quarterbacks.
>> Anybody was at Fresno or at Cal with
Tedford? Yeah. that was going to be a
problem.
>> A-Rod just kind of blew that out.
>> Exactly.
>> But but when you look at North Dakota
State quarterbacks, no matter how highly
they've been regarded in the draft
process, day three guy, day two guy, or
a top pick, they haven't necessarily
worked out.
>> Maybe well and Wentz got derailed a
little. Wentz was on his way to an MVP
season before he got
>> got hurt. Um and then he was just he
wasn't good after that. But
>> I don't know. I I know somebody had
talked about I was talking to somebody
about North Dakota State a couple years
ago where uh I mean this was maybe a
year ago where they had said that there
they've still become a program that the
NFL just acknowledges as a talent
factory now.
>> Not like they can turn them out like
Alabama, but they recognize as like
that's a legitimate place to go get
talent at North Dakota State. So I I
don't think that there
a championship winning program. So they
do they have to they have to have that
kind of ability.
>> They're moving f FBS soon, right?
>> They are.
>> Is it this next year or is it the year
after?
>> I want to say it's this year. I think
so. I remember watching them play
Colorado opening night and gave Colorado
all they can handle there at Fold four
for Flesome Field.
>> That was some of the best tape Travis
Hunter put out all year though against
North Dakota State that year.
>> That's true.
>> Uh yeah, they're joining the Mountain
West this year.
>> Our first football only member. Do you
think that's a good thing or a bad
thing? Because they do have that
reputation, but now they go to a group
of five conference and they're kind of
in that conversation just with everybody
else muddied up.
>> I man I'm I'm Hey, it's time to go prove
it. Still think it's
>> they got the backing, man. They got the
people that show up. They Listen, when
they come down here, you've you've have
you ever called a game in a championship
game for these?
>> I haven't called it, but I've been to
those games.
>> These folks these Dakota need to come
down here and pay taxes as much as
they're around us.
>> Them It's North Dakota State and South
Dakota State. like they're both here all
the time.
>> They they need to come pay some taxes.
>> Mhm. All right.
>> Money does. They do.
>> Yes, they do. Most recent picks as we
get close to the end of the fifth round
here on day three. Kevin Coleman's
junior goes to the Missouri Tigers or
excuse me, it goes from the Missouri
Tigers to the Miami Dolphins at 177.
178. Cole Payton quarterback North
Dakota State goes to the Eagles. And
then the 49ers at 179 taking RK Cruz,
offensive tackle from Kansas. The
Dolphins have their pick in at 180. And
then the Bills are on the clock. Final
selection of the fifth.
>> These are the two fifth round picks that
Dallas sent to Miami for trading up to
get Caleb DS. By the way,
>> Kevin Coleman Jr. and
>> Kevin Coleman Jr. and TBD.
>> Yeah. and whoever this ends up being the
case. That looks like a a a steal of a
of a trade at the moment because you
have
>> Well, pick since you're
>> two players already.
>> Pick pick pick two players then. Pick
the two play and maybe pick two players
like you're the Cowboys.
>> Mhm.
>> You know, just
>> like if they would have already if they
if they were in the same situation right
now.
>> Is this okay? You said this is the first
of is this how many how many?
>> No, this is the second. The first
>> the second. Okay. Coleman was at 177,
right? Was that a Dallas pick? 177.
Yeah.
>> I mean, Dallas in a way of it. It it was
it owned Dallas had to pick. Correct.
All right. Pick a player at 177 that you
had.
>> Garrett Nmire.
>> I would honestly I would just I would do
it if I was sitting here right now.
That's who I would take right there.
>> Yeah.
>> Just cuz I I I really do love him.
>> Perkins.
>> Perkins. Perkins. That's probably where
I would go. Okay. Pick a player now at
180.
>> Claybornne running back. Wake Forward.
>> Um
>> is Johnson still on the board? Is he
gone?
>> He's off. He's off. Uh Josh Cameron,
wide receiver Baylor.
>> That's a good one.
>> I'm actually with Bobby, too. Like if
Dak's older and you know falling,
>> that's who I would take this year.
>> Take nuts.
>> Nutser and Parker.
>> See, you kind of feel good about that. I
mean, yeah. You made the trade. Downs
is, but you still feel like, you know,
>> winners is going to start.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> And be good, too.
>> Yeah.
>> The
is is Michael Trigg still on the board?
>> He is. Yeah. I I would consider that if
you're looking for a tight end because I
know Kosil's gone, right?
>> Yes.
>> He went Yeah, he went 164 to the Jags.
Yeah, it is good pick.
>> Triggin if you got it.
>> Plenty of options still on the board for
Dallas as we get closer and closer to
their selection. Still a long way away
though as we get ready to close out the
fifth round here of the 2026 NFL draft.
We'll step aside. We're going into
another hour of coverage. You're
listening to the 2026 NFL draft on the
Dallas Cowboys Radio Network and on
dallascowboys.com.
>> I want to play a game with you guys. We
come back.
>> Yeah. What you got there? Because I've
got Cowboys position specifics.
>> Uhhuh.
>> I do this with Vatch and Vatch. I give
him a position and he and he tells me
who the player is
>> at the best of. And maybe what I could
do is I could just kind of pick and
choose and you could tell me you could
tell me who that player is left on your
board. How about that?
>> I like it.
>> Can you guys do that? Yeah.
>> Do we have
>> do we have that ability? If when I when
I say a name or when I say a when I say
a position and then I'll say the uh I'll
say the trait. Do they have to still be
available?
>> They have to still be available.
>> Got it.
>> Does that work for you over there?
>> Yes, sir.
>> So we can do it. We can do it when we
get back. Yeah. When we get back on the
radio back, I think it'll be because
like I said, maybe it'll give us an idea
of like
>> because I'm going to say a position and
I'm going to give you a I'm going to
give you the trait.
>> Mhm.
>> And then you tell me who the best player
is that on
>> I'm not sure I'm following. Give me an
example of what you're saying.
>> For example, Vachi.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Running back vision.
>> Uh I would say Moss has the has the best
vision vision left over.
>> I got it. Okay.
>> Would you like to go get some more
chicken wings?
>> I I had the one. I was good.
>> Okay. Did you have some not that good?
>> No, they're fine. I just I was eating
one of those coming in here to get Nick
time off.
>> Who is
>> Nick Harris is right there.
>> Who is that?
>> Nick is Nick.
>> Look on your other side. Brian Nick's
>> dog. Who is that?
>> Who is what?
>> Oh, say you Trayore from Mississippi
State. Big receiving tight end. They
used him a lot at the second level and
in red zone packages at Mississippi
State. He is a big dude. Oh, look there.
Looks like he's from
>> Oh, is this one of those international
player deals? Yes, it He he played a lot
at Mississippi State. I don't know if
it's specifically that.
>> He's apparently
sixth rounder.
>> Uh he is from London, England.
>> Oh, so this is the start of the sixth
round.
>> This end of the fifth. I'm saying I'm
saying
>> that there was a team that said sixth.
>> Uh yeah, smooth athleticism after the
catch talent. Uh had just three catches
of 20 plus yards in 2025, but he was
used a lot in red zone action. did have
knee surgery last year going into the
year. So, he was a little uh slow out of
the gates, I would say, for the Bulldogs
to start the year, but I actually really
liked him uh when I was doing game prep
for Mississippi State last year. Uh and
that that was an offense that had some
weapons. We talked about Brennan
Thompson earlier. Uh, of course, their
their quarterback is uh uh or was Blake
Shapen, who was a former Baylor
transfer, but they they struggled to get
off the ground offensively. It wasn't
because of him. He was utilized where
they needed to in in late down scenarios
and in red zone especially. See him on
the sideline there. Contested catch
ability. Some of those elements too.
>> I was outside playing and Brian was
probably like working with the Cowboys
or something. But Mississippi State used
to be like a factory for offensive
lineman.
>> Yeah.
>> Like like like tackle factory and and
and playing football in Mississippi.
Playing old line in Mississippi. They'll
make us all go to the Mississippi State
camps and it was like this hellish hard
ass camp and I was like bro I don't even
want to be this good that bad. you're
like, I just don't want to be here.
>> Like I just like I just want to be
better. I don't want to be this good.
Like Miss like Mississippi has some
tough camps for offensive line.
>> I will say there was a conversation that
I I had with uh one of the scouts couple
days ago where they were talking about
Treyor as like a sixth or seventh round
possibility,
>> but this is an international player. I
assume by the flag and stuff like that
and the fact that the commissioner gave
him a helmet and all that stuff
>> and the
>> he's just he's from an international
side, but I I think he's considered I
don't think he's a part of like the
international program
>> or anything like that
>> because we did that before. Didn't the
Minnesota Vikings they made Zimmer draft
a wide receiver from
>> maybe or something like that way back in
the day.
>> Did they make teams do that?
>> I think they asked him. Would you be
kind enough to like We won't investigate
you.
>> Boy, that money. Boy, that money. Boy,
>> listen. Uh, would you be happy to You
got a lot of picks.
>> Hey, trying to bring the organizers
back.
>> Would you
happen to Rams?
>> Not Toronto.
>> What's up?
>> What was that?
>> Didn't that happen to the Rams years
ago?
>> Maybe that sounds vaguely.
>> What? What? Ram? What happened?
>> The Ryan fire.
>> Ry that was old NFL Europe days.
>> Uh, all right. So, final pick is on its
way following I'm sure and then we go
into the sixth round. Yeah.
>> Bills on the clock. Their pick is in.
>> I'll run down these selections when we
get back here on the radio side and then
we're going to play a game.
>> Yeah. I'll give you again to give you
some just use your board. I like
>> that last pick was really good. I only
just saw it a few seconds ago.
>> The Bills.
>> Yeah. How they took Kilgore. I didn't
realize they had taken Kilgore yet.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, their last pick.
>> Huh?
>> That's medical, right? Kilgore. Medical.
Uh there's some teams that didn't like
it. Yeah,
>> I I got the top punters and kickers if
you need them.
>> Didn't Florida have a kicker?
>> Trey Smack.
>> Smack.
>> You a damn lie.
>> I got a scouting report.
>> That's all it
spits. Welcome back in to our 2026 NFL
draft coverage here from the Star in
Fris just a couple steps away from the
Cowboys war room as they sit and wait
for a little bit. Almost nobody in the
war room at the moment just having
conversations. It's really just Will
Mcclelay sitting by the phone and that's
about it. In
>> case it rings
>> at the moment. The Cowboys taking three
players in the fourth round and they're
happy with their selections at the
moment. And it started with Drew
Shelton, the offensive tackle from Penn
State, followed by Devin Moore, the
corner from Florida. And then at 137,
they turn around and they take uh the
excuse me, lost my notes there for a
second. The Edge from Alabama, LT
Overton,
>> Buffalo.
>> Can Can I ask you Are you still running
through stuff or can I ask Brian a
question here?
>> Can I Yeah, ask him a question because I
got to play some house.
>> Well, I'm going to ask you a question
after he's done.
>> Okay. Zayn Durant, defensive tackle from
Penn State, just went to Buffalo uh with
the 181st pick. It's the final pick in
the fifth round. We are now officially
into the sixth round today. Kevin
Coleman Jr., wide receiver from
Missouri, goes 177 to the Dolphins. Cole
Payton, quarterback from North Dakota
State, goes 178 to the Eagles, 140 or
179. The 49ers, taking RK Cruz, the
offensive tackle from Kansas. Seu
Trayor, the London, England tight end
who played at Mississippi State last
year. He goes 180 to the Miami Dolphins
and then at 181 as I mentioned, Zayn
Durant defensive tackle from Penn State
with Bobby Belt, Brian Bratis, Zack
Walchuck, all from 1053, the fan, Nick
Harris from the Fort Worth Star
Telegram, Vot Lombardi from Crown Global
Media. Brian or Bobby, go ahead and ask
Brian your question.
>> Here's my question for you, Brian. Uh
we're talking about uh Drew Shelton and
how clearly that was like we can tell
now that that was definitely a uh your
your offensive line coach and his
relationship that exists there. So when
you make a pick like that,
>> do you think it more often lends itself
to we know this player better than
anybody else because of the relationship
and because the work done in or we're
more biased to this player than anybody
else because he's wanted Shelton this
entire time?
>> I think that I think it's that's it.
>> I think it's a bias.
>> I was just curious.
>> I think it is. I really do.
>> Okay. Uh let me mark this down.
>> It's worth noting that he
>> stay here.
>> Yeah.
>> All right. Uh it's worth noting that uh
Drew Shelton also worked with Duke Manny
during the draft process. Worked
alongside Terence Steel.
>> You need that. Good.
>> There you go.
>> There was a lot going on as far as
connections go.
>> Welcome back, Nick.
>> Thank you. Got a quick meal in. I am
ready to go sicko here for the next um
>> Let's go.
>> What are we at? Uh
>> 182. 182 pick is in for Cleveland. So,
we got like what? 63 more picks. Let's
do it.
>> Yeah, we got a little bit of time. Then
they're going to make a play. Hey,
quarterback.
>> Ryan, your guy.
>> The Browns take Tailon Green out of
>> How about that?
>> Is he going to play quarterback? He
shouldn't play receiver.
>> He might be their best
>> their best quarterback.
>> Talk Nick, talk about him because I I I
get in fights about this kid.
>> No, I I I'm actually not a huge believer
in his quarterback availability. I was
that was more of a joke on the Browns.
>> Sorry about that. I I I will say though,
I think he does have the big play in him
and I think he's smart in the back
field.
>> I walked right into that one.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I do. Uh yeah, it would be
funny if their best quarterback ends up
being a receiver.
>> Maybe
>> he's uber athletic.
>> Very athletic. I mean, his numbers are
Calvin Johnson like sideby side.
>> He could return for the Browns if he
ends up being like QB3.
>> Yeah.
>> He could be a returner for them if if
they wanted it to be. But
>> yeah, fascinating pick. All right. So,
Brian, before we went into the break,
you wanted to play a possible uh Yeah.
hypothetical scenario.
>> Take your take your boards. Everybody
take their boards out and I'm I'm going
to give you a position and I'm going to
give a a characteristic uh a trait and
you tell me what player you have on your
board at that position matches my my
trait. You ready? Go with wide
receivers.
Who's got the best run after catch on
your board?
>> Available or in general?
>> Available. available. Available
>> Jordan Hudson SMU.
>> Yeah, I probably go with Hudson as well
or Caldwell
>> or
>> I was looking at Jeff Caldwell from
Cincy. Yeah,
>> pardon me. Eric Mallister.
>> I did not watch Mallister.
>> Tell me about him a little bit. Vod
>> TCU big as hell. Yeah, guy.
>> That was a double uh injury character
flag on him.
>> Yeah,
>> but I I would take him. I like I like
Eric Mallister.
>> Yeah. By the way, Carson Sh, Iowa
linebacker, goes 183 to the Cardinals
here.
>> I had him. I like that. He was my last
Oh, I didn't rank him, but I put a sixth
round on him. I hate when that happens.
>> I had a sixth round on him, too. Let's
go.
>> Yeah, I didn't rank him, though, by by
my fault. He had 18 missed tackles last
year. I didn't love that. Uh, but he he
is athletic, affects everything in front
of him, all the way into the back field.
Heat seeker and functional mover
arriving downhill. Uh, needs better play
recognition. um but can can often get
lost with misdirectional play action.
Tons of special teams experience, so
it's going to give him a 53man roster
floor. That's why I put him in the
sixth. Um but overall, the linebacker
ability, it's going to be tough.
>> Iowa born and raised after playing 35
games as a reserve from 2021 to 24.
That's where that special teams
>> came in as well. I got to talk to him at
the Shrine Bowl and he's got a great
character to him. He's he's got a
phenomenal underdog mentality and he
kind of needs that because he had the
little unders sized experience and he
was kind of undersized frame as well.
Got pushed around by bigger blockers
when guards would try to reach the
second level as well. Uh packs a punch
for his size, not afraid to blitz. Uh
you could see the sack of Diego Pavia in
their final bowl game too that I thought
was a good read on his side. You talk
about processing. I think if he plays
more that might come naturally for him.
He looks like a linebacker and Iowa's
had some pretty good linebackers in
front. I just think he needs a little
bit of reps this season. I think he's a
developmental guy in the sixth.
>> Anyways, going back to your game there,
Brian,
>> offensive lineman
>> ability to pull
>> tackles and guards.
>> Yep.
>> Um,
>> do we like Brian Parker's ability to uh
Logan Taylor, Boston College? Logan
Taylor, Boston College.
>> I I would go with Parker. I like Parker.
I like Parker, too.
>> Parker. I Yeah, Parker. I think he's
going to move inside.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I think he he looks like a center
to me. He's got a center body.
>> I tabbed him as a center.
>> Yeah.
>> I I think hands and feet are smooth.
They're calculated. Keeps his hands in
sides. He finishes blocks with a mean
streak. I I liked Parker a lot more than
I think most people did.
>> Pat Couan.
>> I had him in the fifth.
>> I like Patan.
>> Patan Indiana.
>> It's a good one.
>> He pulls.
>> He's still available.
>> Yeah, he is.
>> Interesting.
>> He is still available. How about running
back?
>> Yeah. elusiveness.
>> Claybornne.
>> Claybourne.
>> Wait for us.
>> Just to be different. Uh, Robert Henry
for the for the bit.
>> Would you call that elusiveness or would
you just call that broken tackle
ability?
>> They just scared of him. So, they don't
want to tackle.
>> They don't I I feel like people just
don't want to tackle.
>> I tell you a running back that I really
loved in this process that's still on
the board, could very well be an
undrafted free agent at this point is
Jamari Taylor. Talk about a bowling
ball. He remind me. I loved um
>> Oh my gosh. Bears running back.
Manungai. I loved Manungai last year in
the process and Jamari Taylor reminded
me a lot of Manungai.
>> Jaden, it's old tape.
>> J that is so weird.
>> Confidence got shot and look I
>> Demarco Murray was great for the
franchise. I don't think he's a great
coach.
>> Bam up
>> there. Could be there.
>> How about this one?
>> Tight end vertical threat. Michael
Trigg.
>> Yeah, Trig.
>> Trig
>> to be different. Uh Dalen Bentley, Utah.
>> Okay. Okay.
>> Jiren Kak also in that DJ Rogers, TCU.
Uh I just wasn't that big on Trigg.
>> What did it just I mean they had three
guys that say this and what what did you
not like about Trigg?
>> Uh Trigg overall the off the- field
about character. Yes. Um I think he's
more of a one route guy too. I think
you're just going to slot seam him and
and try to try to maximize what the seam
looks like. But I don't think he has a
route tree to him at all. I think what
Baylor tried to do with Serge Robertson
and him was just like, "Run down the
scene. We're going to contest a catch.
We know you have a big frame and a big
uh catch radius." And yes, that worked
for him, don't get me wrong. But I I
don't know.
>> I mean, but that's the vertical ability,
though. That's what we're talking about
here is vertical.
>> That's That's it.
>> But he But he's got it though. I mean,
if he's got a fast ball, he's got a
fast.
>> I guess when I'm more so think about
vertical threat, I I want I want the
whole package. I want the whole load.
>> Sure. And I want the whole load. You
want you want you want a little bit of
route running ability to go along with
>> Give him the full package. Don't you
hold an inch back.
>> Huh?
>> What you got, Brian?
>> Defensive line. I was trying to get
there. I didn't I just let him go.
Defensive line defeat blockers.
Okay. Harold Perkins because I got him
as an edge.
>> Ben Cleveland.
>> Tell me about him.
>> Strong as hell, powerful hands. Uh,
stack and shed, can extend, does not
move. Uh, double teams don't really
bother him. Uh, cool motor pocket
pusher.
>> Quintavius Hutchkins is still on the
board, right?
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah, I'd probably go Quintavius
Hutchkins.
>> Tell me a little bit about him.
>> Yeah, he was a Senior Bowl guy that I
really liked. Uh, I thought he had a
really good week at the Senior Bowl. Um,
and obviously had the experience with
Donovan Azaraku as well. Uh, but I his
motor and his athleticism off the line
is freakish. And I I I think in a
setting like Mobile, it made sense why
he shine cuz I went back and watched the
tape and he wears down by the end of
games. Uh but that hey, a first half
from Quintavius Hutchkins, I'd put that
in like the fourth third round.
>> Linebackers.
>> Yeah, Blitz Murdoch.
>> Even with the the medicals.
>> Yeah, he's best guy on this board.
>> I just like him.
>> Harold Perkins because I have him as a
backer. Pachi
>> outside linebackers count like is it
outside?
>> Just throw it. Yeah, whatever you want
to go.
>> Sure. I I'll go Perkins. Yeah, I think
Perkins makes sense.
>> Would you call him and would you say
he's off ball there?
>> He's anything you want him to Well, no.
He's not anything you want him to be.
He's anything
>> that your mind allows you to think he
could be.
>> Okay.
>> Does that make sense? Cuz like he
doesn't have a uh
>> That was some Christian Parker brain
works type stuff right there.
>> Yeah. He doesn't have necessarily a
position at the next level.
Defensive backs.
>> How about range?
>> Range. Range.
>> Bishop Fitzgerald.
That's the answer.
>> Has Deshawn Singleton been taken out of
Nebraska?
>> No.
>> Yeah. Uh, give me that. That 80 plus
inch wingspan. Oh man.
>> Did I miss Price? Did Price go?
>> He did. Okay.
>> Bishop Fitzgerald.
>> And yeah, Fitzgerald. I'd probably
cosign.
>> I cosign Fitzgerald as well. Yeah.
I'm still trying to catch up on names,
too. Did Dalon ever go?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Long.
>> Oh, man. He went in the third round.
>> You went yesterday. What?
>> Did he really? Yeah.
>> Oh, I missed that one then. My bad.
>> I think you even
>> I just didn't check it on my list, I
guess.
>> No, I I caught myself.
>> I just had to clean my list, too.
>> Actually, VJ Payne.
>> Okay.
>> Pay still there.
>> He is still there.
>> I can't believe that. I had to stay.
>> VJ Pay was fantastic. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Singleton and Payne are my two
fourth round safeties left.
>> Agreed.
Let's go back to wide receivers.
How about
acceleration? Malik Benson.
>> Aaron Anderson.
>> On my board. Uh Jordan Hudson. I'm just
out of receivers. I'm running out of
receivers.
>> You're out of receivers.
>> I am going to catch everybody up here on
these last couple of picks here. Brown.
>> We're going I'm looking at the names.
It's nobody we're talking about. No, not
at all. The first five picks are off the
board. Trust me, I'm looking.
>> Don't even Don't even put pressure on us
like that.
>> I I'm looking down. I'm I'm trying to
tell I'm just trying to
>> Sharp from LSU. Brian don't even know
him.
>> Not a whole lot of stuff going on there.
Bobby Jameson Travis just kicked. Yeah.
By the Giants. You can't. Top half of
the sixth round. 182. Tayen Green,
quarterback from Arkansas. Carson Shy,
linebacker from Iowa, who we talked
about, goes to the Cardinals at 183. Uh
184, Jackie Marshall, the defensive
tackle from Baghdad man,
>> goes to the
Jackie Chan,
>> the Tennessee Titans. That was close. Uh
the Buccaneers at 185 take Bower Sharp,
tight end from LSU. One of your Tigers,
though.
>> My Tigers.
>> Yeah. And then another Tiger. It was
Auburn Tiger. Bobby Jameson, Travis.
>> Interesting guy with three first names.
>> 186.
>> That's That's crazy.
>> He goes to the Giants, so you get to
play him twice a year if he makes the
team. So there you go.
>> Bobby Jameson, Travis. What are we
doing?
>> Those are three first names. And then
Kron Allen.
>> Okay, we talk about this one.
>> Yeah. Penn State running back here goes
to the Washington Commanders.
>> Wow. Okay.
>> I like how we all just agreed that this
is the the good pick out of the last 10.
>> Yeah. And he he's in the division, too.
>> Oh, man. Yeah.
>> Tough runner though, man. Tackle
breaker, patient, uh, one cut north and
south, solid pass blocker, not really
receiver, you know what I'm saying? For
real, for real, but he'll catch some
short little, you know, short little
passes, whatever. I like him. I would
have like uh I would have liked to have
to have had him here and I had a fourth
round grade on him.
>> I think he has a high floor. Like he
doesn't do anything exceptionally well,
but he does pretty much everything good.
>> Um man, Washington does such a good job
of finding day three running backs like
Bill Crosky Merritt last year, Kron
Allen, Chris Rodriguez in the past.
>> Um yeah, throw him into this mix now
that Eckler looks like yeah, his career
is not looking too great moving forward.
And there's a lot of questions in that
running back room. So, I mean, they were
rumored to be, hey, if Jeremiah Love
falls, he will not get past the
Washington Commanders. And um yeah.
Yeah. He they didn't even get close to
that. Um so, uh yeah, Kron Allen, he was
a guy that if he had come out last year,
and I bet he's kicking himself, he
probably would have gone second or third
round. Uh whereas like this year, he
didn't really do anything better, if
that makes sense. And that Penn State
team, I mean, it was a disaster. Um so,
that's probably part of it. But he still
rushed for a thousand yards and that was
while splitting time with Nicholas
Singleton.
and 15 touchdowns, too.
>> Yeah.
>> I mean, not only is he running and he's
in a split back field, but he's scoring
>> and a lot of that wasn't just red zone
touches. I know he's got a powerful
lower half, so you're going to see him
in red zone situations on that tape, but
a lot of it was from distance and he
just got around and got through.
>> He's got tree trunks for legs, man.
>> Yeah, he's he's explosive for sure.
Durable, too. Very,
>> that was one thing. He he stuck in there
and and and played almost every game he
could. Uh, Jets, Bengals, Saints,
Patriots, and Giants are the next five
picks due up here in the middle of the
sixth round. All right, Brian, you want
to continue?
>> Yeah, let me give you a couple more of
these. Tight ends catching a crowd.
Contested catching guy.
>> That might be Andrew separate.
>> Catching I catching a crowd. I think I'd
have to go contested catching tight end
guy.
>> Jack Andrew cuz he don't separate. Yeah.
>> So, that's probably where I would put
Trigg.
>> Well, I mean, I thought about Trig. I
just went that last time.
>> Anybody else?
>> Jump is another man.
>> I'm trying to I would agree with Trig.
>> I'm trying to click on who's been gone.
That's my thing is I'm trying to figure
out who's still available because I
looked at it and I I I was thinking like
Royer, but
>> Royer's gone. Yeah, that was why you
were gone though.
>> Kyle, maybe you need to host this game.
>> Yeah, hold on. Yeah, here you answer for
it then. I got you. I'm good. What you
got? No. What? Who's your contested guy
that's left?
>> I think contested catch tight end.
>> I think Let me look at mine real quick
though.
>> Contested catch tight end. That's great.
>> Contested catch.
>> Supposed to be Burkshire, but teams want
to overdraft him.
>> Catching a crowd guy.
>> Yeah, he ended up
>> they overdrafted the head.
>> I think it's I think it's uh I think
it's injuries from Texas is who I would
say.
>> I'm surprised he's still on the board
here. Yeah, completely honest. I had a
fourth on him.
>> Let's go with the running backs. How
about this one? How about inside runner?
>> Inside runner.
>> That's uh Moss for me. Boss or
>> Le'Von Moss.
>> Moss. I say Leon.
>> Jamari Taylor for me.
>> Yeah, I think it is Jamari Taylor.
>> It was by Jamari Taylor. Jamari Taylor's
like little but he's like
>> so a little bit powerful. Yeah,
>> he's a bowling ball.
>> Could I throw Eli Heiden into that
possibility? What about Seth McG?
>> I like him in between the tackles.
>> Price had been taken.
>> McGowan. I think you got it right. Yeah,
>> Seth McGan.
>> You say McGowan or you're surprised?
Yeah, me too, dude. He's such a
>> Mac will probably go undrafted.
>> Is that another one of those where you
don't know where exactly he fits in
because he does a number of different
things here.
>> It's not just that like you're going to
need a team like a Mike McCarthy or
somebody who wants to use him in that
type of role.
>> He was really good at the East West
game.
>> Yeah, he's who's willing to spend a
roster spot on a player like that.
>> He's a dude. Brian, you asked me about
him in the uh the Shrine Game cover and
I you asked me for a comp of him. Yeah.
And I thought he was he's not the same
talent level, not the same guy, but
because of the way you could use him, he
is a very light version of Christian
McAffrey cuz he he can line up anywhere.
He can block. He can do a little bit in
between the tackles outside whenever we
get there. I'd say he's arguably one of
the better in between the tackle guys
left outside of Texas A&M's Lev Yamas.
All right, we got to take a break here.
We'll continue that later. I like that,
Brian. We could come back to it here in
a little bit. Before we take a break,
Cowboys fans, while the team is making
big picks, make the smart pick at home.
Call Ontime Experts, the official AC,
heating, and plumbing partner of the
Dallas Cowboys. Fast, reliable, always
on time. That's on timeexperts. Visit
ontimeexperts.com
and click book now. You're listening to
the 2026 NFL draft on the Dallas Cowboys
Radio Network and DallasCowboys.com. Oh.
Oh my gosh. All right, guys.
Long way to go until these uh the the
final pick.
>> Why does round six feel so long?
>> Was it 218? We got 30 picks. 30 out.
>> I feel like 50 picks go in this round,
man.
>> You know, 218.
>> I think the commissioners I saw this the
commissioner's first year as
commissioner 2007.
>> The first round went 6 hours and 28
minutes.
>> How does that happen? 15-minute picks,
right? Is that what it was?
>> They're trying to remember what happened
in 2007.
>> And teams just wait them joints out,
man.
>> But yeah, it was over 6 hours long. And
last and in the first round in this
year, I think was 2 hours and 50
something minute, I think, is what it
was. Wow. Was half the time.
>> Thank God.
>> I got
>> seriously 2007 was Jamarcus Russell
going number one overall. Man, they got
that.
>> They not only had 15 minutes to think
about that, they had six months to think
about that. Calvin Johnson, Joe Thomas,
Gaines Adams,
>> ah
>> went to the Tampa Bay Bucks, Levi Brown,
Penn State offensive tackle, Jeron Leon
Landry, Adrien Peterson, Jamal Anderson,
defensive end out of Arkansas going to
Atlanta. Teddian Jr. and then Amobia
Aoy.
>> Then you also had Patrick Willis
drafted, Marshon Lynch was drafted,
Derel Rivas. This was actually a really
good draft.
>> We're going to go through all 257.
>> No, I'm just going through Dwayne Bow.
It's taking him six hours to get
>> Well, I mean, I'm trying to fill time.
>> No, no, I know you're doing a great job.
>> Anthony Spencer was the Cowboys pick
that year
>> cuz I don't have a report on Bobby
Jackson Travis.
>> I don't know.
>> Sound like a It's not like It sound like
a bass fisherman, doesn't it?
>> Yeah.
>> Let's go down to the boat and let's
check in with Bobby Jameson Travis.
>> It's like a bowler.
>> Yeah.
>> Pro Bowler.
>> Who do you think you are?
>> I am.
I think uh who you think LT Overton is
hitting him up to go bowl?
>> Yeah,
I think the bowling hall of fame is
here. Do you think LT Overton is
>> Paul? He's a big bowler.
>> He said yeah, he likes to bowl in his
free time.
>> Yeah, somebody doesn't watch the damn
draft show.
>> I was doing TV. Give me a minute.
>> They I walked in there and they're like,
"Hey, put the put a suit on and get a
tie." And I was like, "All right, I'll
be there."
>> Fine. Nick asked him like a scummy
bowling alley.
>> It smells like when we have to keep your
own score.
said he preferred that. And I was like,
"All right." Yeah. So, we're stepping
over a Marlboro red and you got to a
bullet down, you know, a little shady
bolt. The one that's my kind of joint.
>> They spray that they spray that that
that stuff in the shoes and it doesn't
kill anything.
>> Not at all. There's one in the colony
that really does fit that mold. You walk
in there, it just smells like cigarette
smoke and throw up.
>> You said fit the mold. It sound It's got
the mold.
>> Yes. Yes. Pun intended.
>> Oh, man.
>> Yeah.
>> That poor cop.
>> Have you ever walked out with your
bowling shoes on? I've never done that.
>> I I think I did that once in college.
There was a reason why.
>> My shoes cost a lot of money. I wouldn't
want to leave them behind
for the bowling shoes. You know what I'm
saying? Wouldn't want to do it.
>> Yeah. Must be nice.
>> No, man.
>> Must be nice,
>> man. I I saved up.
>> Brian Parker got selected. Cincinnati
Bengals.
>> Do you like Oh, yeah. Brian Parker
center. You were just talking about him,
Zack.
>> Oh, gosh. Yes, I was. What are you doing
over there? Getting out of here.
>> I had a moment where uh I'm going to
have Bobby come and and relieve me for a
second. Uh
>> Oh, no. Your tummy hurts. Brian, just
don't even talk right now. Brian Parker,
I did like a lot.
>> Yo, Z, just go, man. Z, just Z, just go.
I got you, Z. Z, just go.
>> Oh, yeah. You I did like him a lot.
Shout out to Graham Barton. He is Gran
Barton Jr.
>> Oh,
>> Zack, just go. If it's bad like that,
don't don't even call.
>> Just leave the leave the chair. Little
do you know he has a phobia about doing
this.
>> Oh no.
>> Damn dog. But yeah, man. Brian uh Parker
has some uh pretty pretty decent
movement like like in the run game and
stuff. I didn't think he had a bunch of
range as a tackle. So that's why I had
him as a center because I thought that
his range would work a lot more there.
>> We'll come back to it.
>> I ain't coming back to it.
>> No, we're going to come back.
>> I ain't coming back to it. Y'all y'all
break him down. I ain't coming back. I'm
sick of this.
>> Continuing on in the middle of the sixth
round, the last five selections. Bobby
Jameson Travis, defensive tackle from
Auburn, goes to the Giants at 186. 187,
the Commanders take Katron Allen,
running back from Penn State. 188, the
Jets take Anz Cooper, guard from Miami.
The Bengals at 189 take Brian Parker, I
second, the center out of Duke. And then
Barry and Brown, the wide receiver from
LSU, goes to the instate squad, the
190th pick to the New Orleans Saints. I
kind of like me a little bit of that
Brian Parker. Uh, you know, it's a
really strange year with these 300 pound
guys, but you here we are. I mean,
they're all athletes. So, he did start
at right tackle for the Blue Devils, and
I project him to play center. I think
he's a really good foot athlete that
lacks some bulk. His movement skills are
outstanding. The movement is not a
problem for this guy. The lack of bulk
is. He tends to catch blocks more. He
strikes with his hands. The wider the
rusher, the better chance he has in
order to to run that defender past the
quarterback. He can put himself in
position to make his block, but you'll
see him give up a ton of ground at times
in his set. Uh he doesn't have the great
lower body power to sit down on a rusher
and but he'll put himself in position to
make the block, but he will struggle to
sustain the block. Um there were some
snaps where he got walked back,
sometimes tossed aside.
>> TJ Parker gave him fees.
>> Yeah, he was he was it was a struggle
for him. Uh but he he does have he does
do a good job as a run blocker when it
when the movement skills have to take
over where he can play in space and
those things work out for him there. The
re the reach blocks, the scoop blocks.
He could tie defenders up. Does well
with the double team stuff on the second
level. I think he's smart. I think he's
athletic and to play center and so but
he might struggle some with some bigger
noses, bigger tackles, but the athletic
ability will shine as that player. 65300
is kind of where I got him uh as a as
his height and weight.
>> I think we're starting to see some some
really good names coming off the the
board here in the middle of the sixth
round. 191 the Jacksonville Jaguars take
Josh Cameron, wide receiver from Baylor.
>> Where'd he go?
>> Jacksonville.
>> Let's go. Let's go. Josh Cameron.
>> He's one of our our pet cats that we've
been talking to. You've been on it since
his recruiting days.
>> Jacksonville is vindicated for an awful
weekend that they've had. Yeah. Um
>> upside down board is what you were
saying.
>> No, I had heard that. Uh yeah, right. I
had heard that uh um Jacksonville was
one of the teams that was talking to
Josh Cameron a lot coming into the week.
So, um I'm I'm glad to see that that's
where he landed. No, a physical uh
receiver who uh started as a walk-on at
Baylor out of Cedar Park High School in
the Austin area. Uh made his way onto
the roster and there you see it. He's a
he's been a red zone weapon, but he's
also got a router to him. Uh I think
this is going to be a guy who just
sticks around in the league. I'm not
saying he's going to end up getting a
major contract one day. I just think
you're going to look up seven, eight
years from now, be like, "Who's still
left from this draft class?" You're
like, "Wow, Josh Cameron, huh?" And I
he's got a very high special teams floor
that I think will he'll be able to
provide day one. He's going to make the
roster in Jacksonville. And uh he's just
he's a he's a team first guy. Comes from
a phenomenal family. Uh I know his uh
his mom is overjoyed right now. I'm so
glad to see this kid get drafted. He
deserves it. Shout out to Josh Cameron
of Cedar Park High School. He was a late
ad to the Senior Bowl roster and he
didn't have his helmet or or nobody gave
him his helmet uh going to Mobile. So,
he had just a white helmet on wearing
number 34, which he did wear at Baylor.
And the first practice that we were out
there, I was looking down, I was like,
who's this running back just routing
people up in the secondary? Cuz I'm
thinking 34, that's a running back that
they just added from who who knows
where. And sure enough, it was a wide
receiver. He wears 34 because what was
it? it was it Jackson or it was Bo
Jackson. It was his favorite player
growing up and and so it it always looks
a little odd but that's kind of what
he's wanted. If you're a wide receiver
in the in the league, can you wear 34?
Is that possible?
>> I don't think so.
>> I mean it's anarchy now. They let
anybody wear anything. It seems like
>> Okay.
>> It's not to that extent though.
>> Be a running back and just line up at
receiver the whole
>> He's built like a running back.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Tom McGomery does that.
>> Yeah. He's he's built like a running
back. I thought he was uh cuz he's a
wide build wide receiver.
>> Wouldn't surprise me if they do try to
put him in uh some backfield situations.
He's got the he's got the size to do it.
He's got the thighs to do it. And I
think he would be he has got he's got
the vision to do it. I think he would be
a fun weapon there as well. Uh I'm such
a big Josh Cameron guy. I put a fourth
round grade on him. Um and uh glad to
see him get drafted.
>> I put him as a cowboy fit in the
magazine. I I was kind of hoping that he
would be around, but the Cowboys don't
have a fifth or a sixth round pick. So,
and that makes a lot more sense.
>> Anybody like anybody like JC Davis? He
just went to the Football Giants.
>> Did you watch?
>> Yeah, I had a third round on him, left
tackle, but I had him as a guard. Um I
just like big powerful guards with
anchor and punch. And I thought he dealt
with uh with, you know, powerful uh
linemen pretty uh decently, but but his
range was really limited to me. So,
that's why I didn't have him at tackle.
and he was just much more of a guard. Uh
kind of kind of tall, you know what I'm
saying? So
>> 65 335 is kind of what you're dealing
with right there.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So you know knee bend wasn't
all that good, but please go ahead.
Rough around the edges as well. Go
ahead.
>> No, you're right about it. You got him.
He's got a kind of a natural anchor that
the way he plays uh to him. There's like
I say, the knee bend stuff like that
needs to be a little bit better with
him. I think the best thing he does is
he can get movement in the running game
and he can sustain and I think that's
good for the position. I do like the way
he plays on his feet, but there's times
you'll see him kind of over the tops him
a little bit and he'll he'll lose that.
But, uh, but at 6'5, 335,
uh, you know, the Giants taking a shot
on the on those kind of those
measurables,
>> but with a guy that can play a little
bit, like I say, we'll see about the
pass about as a pass blocker, I think
that's where he's a little bit limited.
Uh, but the run blocking stuff's pretty
good.
>> Currently at 193. The Giants picking
again here go back back to back.
>> So they take the JC Davis out of
Illinois and then they've got another
pick here in a moment. Anybody want to
update the top of their board as of
late.
>> I still have three third rounders that
are just hanging around and I I
>> One of them is Nusmeire, right?
>> No, I do not have a lot of thirds. Um
that's that's a Bobby over here. Sorry.
You're right.
>> Um Robert Spears Jennings out of
Oklahoma. Um the safety wide receiver
Jeff Caldwell to Cincinnati and then
running back Deon Claybourne out of Wake
Forest. Those are my three third
rounders left.
>> My threes I got a couple of them. JC
Daniels wide receivers wide receiver
Miami Don Burks. Uh Arkansas Davis just
went Nusmeire, Llewellyn, and Perkins.
Llewellen from Iowa. Perkins from LSU.
Also got Lucas from USC. Um Anthony
Lucas the edge. And I got Rashan Benny
uh tackle from Michigan.
>> Who are some of the names you're looking
at here, Bobby? Anybody around the
league? feel like anybody's falling.
>> Uh, let me look here. Who's available on
the board?
>> All them names we just mentioned. I just
find it odd that Bobby James and Travis
has been drafted. I I never heard of.
>> There have been a couple of those guys
already.
>> No disrespect to none of these people
neither. You know what I'm saying?
>> I mean, Deion Burke still has not gone,
right?
>> No, I I don't get the Deion Burks love.
>> Yeah, but
>> six round up
>> here.
No, Nick. Josh Cameron, you need a guy
for but like I mean you look at like the
athleticism that's
>> he can't return.
>> No, I know. But I mean you're talking
about that.
>> What are you going to do with him on
>> But you're talking about that
athleticism when we're like into the
six.
>> He's better than Bowers Sharp is what
he's saying,
>> right? But like if you're drafting in
the sixth round, seventh round as a
receiver, you have to bring special
teams. And this guy's not going to bring
special teams if he
>> No, I know. But so he's he's apparently
I guess fallen this far, but I'm still
surprised that it would go this far.
He's apparently fallen this far because
of some character stuff, but
>> I I
>> I just had a team tell me about Daniels.
Did we do that? That wasn't character,
right? That was I had a team just say me
was a knee. They're saying that's a
that's a medical for CJ Daniels.
>> Okay,
>> that's a knee is what a team
>> What about Llewellen? Did he have any or
or maybe I just suck at evaluating? I
don't know.
>> I was with you on Llewellen. I was
totally with you on Llewellyn.
>> Bobby.
>> Bobby what?
>> Llewellen from Iowa. come.
>> I just remember a couple weeks ago, V,
when you were giving us hell about age
and injuries and you're like, why aren't
these guys going?
>> Yeah,
>> injuries.
>> These guys suck at drafting.
>> It's the sixth round. What we doing?
>> I'm just I'm just I'm just calling back.
>> I feel you. But at some point, Izz
Cooper, you know what I'm saying?
>> Barry and Brown. Brian, you are LSU
Brian Broadis. Yeah. Who is Barry and
Brown? Brian,
>> sixth. Yeah, that's
>> they got a six on Max Llewellen.
>> Not here, but in general, that was the
feedback
>> in the league. Got a six on Max
Llewellen.
>> I mean, not universal.
>> I think what happens with I think what
happens with Max Llewell and his people
are looking at that he doesn't test
well.
>> Babe, do we have highlights on Max
Llewellen back there just just for no
reason? Just
>> I'm sure I'm sure he does. He's
>> just cuz we can.
>> In the sixth round, the draft show has
selected
>> Yeah, exactly. cuz I have seen
highlights of receivers catching three
routes or we've seen highlights of
corners and their highlight is tackling
somebody. You know what I'm saying?
>> It's good players on the board and the
league can be okay. Okay, don't show the
highlights to be. That's cool. It's it's
just it's just interesting that so many
good players that I feel like can play.
>> Yeah.
>> At this point, you ain't got to take
them where I have them graded, but like
dog, we we in the sixth going on seven.
>> Yeah. By the way, Pat Kugan, center from
Indiana and the Rose Bowl MVP just went
to the Tennessee Titans at 194.
One of the better
>> Malik Benson just went too.
>> Pat Kugan Jack Kelly.
>> Oh,
>> yeah. Kougan plays with power. Um, you
know what I'm saying? Get a little bit
of movement. Solo blocker. I felt good
about him. Really good combo guy. Can
reach and pin. Pass blocker, grip
strength, picks up stunts. I like
Kougan, but he can play and he's better
than some of these other guys. I had a
fourth on
>> Malik Benson just as
>> Oh, we got L highlights. Oh, snap. Let's
do it.
>> Go go go go go crazy,
>> man. Just look at this character, man.
Look at big big 10 competition, dog. Get
off the line of scrim. Go up there. Make
a play in the run game. What we do? Show
the spin. Do we have a look at the spin
move, please? Just look at him. Hand
down. He could be a linebacker, too.
Look at the spin. Oh, we so we could
look look Nick, did we rehearse that?
Did we rehearse that? Nope. V just be
knowing V. And I think that was on uh
Okay. No, that was not on uh our guy
Drew uh what's his name? But dog Lwellen
nice. Lwellen nice. Just whatever. I
hope we get him in the seventh or
undrafted or something.
>> Yeah, that's a quarterback that uh Brian
has in the second. Diego Pavia.
>> Just look at this. Look at I don't have
Pavia.
>> Now, there's a lot of things I've done
wrong, but that Pavia ain't one of them.
He is not one of
>> nice
>> that Iowa front seven played well
against Van.
>> I don't know about the front seven. That
was a hell of a game.
>> It was a good game.
>> Uh guys, Zack Walchuck is going a little
wild on on X right now.
>> He texting us. What are you talking
about? Yeah.
>> I don't know what's going on. He's he's
locked in the men's room.
>> Yeah, he might be.
>> He tagged me and said, "Thanks, Vice,
but I don't know what he's talking
about."
>> He said Yeah. He said, "My man." And
then he said, "Nick Harris hates Jacob
Rodriguez because he never answered his
text when he was making a crystal ball
predictions at 247."
>> Yeah, look at my reply.
>> What was your reply? He wasn't good
enough for me to text him.
>> Why did Wchuk tag down Rousini to
>> And then Walchuk said, "How much better
would the draft show be if they just
removed Kyleman as host and let me solo
this thing?
>> What is he doing? What is What is Zach
doing?" in the in the men's room right
now.
>> Did someone take it? Oh, wait.
>> Oo, no.
>> Oh, is Bobby You know what's happening
now?
>> You pick it up. You pick up what I'm
putting down.
>> Oh, no.
>> Zack Walchuk left his laptop in here.
>> No.
>> Text in what we should tweet off of
Zach's uh Twitter at the moment.
>> Yeah. Go ahead and tag tag all of us.
Tag Bobby specifically and uh we'll make
sure it gets out on Zach's Twitter
account here in a little bit. All right.
noise.
>> It is the middle of day three. We're
having some fun inside
>> the Star in Fris.
>> You're not even smiling.
>> Bobby Belts is more locked in today than
he ever has been on day three of this
show in the past.
>> You're listening to the 2026 NFL draft
on the Dallas Cowboys Radio Network and
on Dallas Cowboys.com.
>> I don't even know.
>> Don't tell him. Don't tell him.
>> Yeah, man. He had his phone.
>> They still ain't draft Well, dog. That's
what's up, Jug.
>> What the hell you been doing?
>> Nothing, man.
God, that was an aggressive tweet. I'd
like to talk about gender theory AND
>> HEY, how many have you fired off?
>> I don't like Kyleman's haircut. It
doesn't project the alpha presence
required to carry you through four hours
of Brian wondering why he's 55 receivers
that runs 47 is still on the board.
>> Fix this bleed Chris Bean.
>> How much better would the draft show be
if they just removed Kyleman's as host
and let me solo this thing?
>> Oh no. Botch Lombardi, my man.
>> Yeah,
>> the gang gonna be the gang.
>> I'm about to retweet all this.
>> You have a Juan on here? I
>> was about to
>> Oh jeez.
>> Do that dance y'all do?
>> Whole question. Should Brian retire
>> with your eyes wide open and your tongue
out. What's that dance y'all do?
>> Golly, we were 50/50 on the retirement.
>> Is that haka?
>> Hey bae, what?
>> Do that hawker dance, y'all.
>> Jacob Rodriguez. Hawaii
>> man. All right. Should I just leave
these up?
>> Probably. They're going to take the
gender theory one. I'm going to move.
>> Hawaiian. Djon.
>> Tommy died. Where did he go?
>> He wasn't in the bathroom. I'll tell you
that.
>> Oh, this is crazy. Wow.
>> I'm going to retweet these.
>> I'm crying. I think we're on the side
cuz this be bad radio.
>> This is bad radio. If it is I'm
legitimately crying.
>> Bobby is on your Twitter account. LMF
AO.
>> Oh man, my favorite one was watch
Lombardi. My man
>> with two fist bumps above
>> as he fist.
>> Oh boy. Y
>> that was good.
>> I'm trying to win an Emmy and y'all
playing.
>> You look good. I like that that sport
coat. Hey man,
>> showcase the sport coat all three days.
I'm happy for you.
>> I' I've worn something of the sort all
week, man. I'mma wear some next week,
too. And then I'm going back to hoodies
and white TE's.
>> There you go.
>> You feel me?
>> Good for you.
>> It's just draft week. No.
>> No. That's good. Uh yeah, by the way,
the the draft is like on pause for some
reason. Uh
>> yeah, there hasn't been a pick in a
while.
>> In a while. We're we're laughing. We're
we're killing time here and we're kind
of having a good time, but they haven't
actually announced a pick since Malik
Benson the
>> Oh, dang it. Benson went.
>> Yeah, he did. He was last.
>> Let's keep tweeting from Zack's account
then. Bobby had
>> Roger Gadell's like, "Stop. There's some
fun stuff going on."
>> Hold on a second. What's happening? Did
Bobby get loose again?
>> Oh, man.
>> This is incredible.
>> Fix this beam. It's crazy.
I'm I'm just reading Zach's tweets now.
Currently,
>> in the middle of it, he was retweeting a
highlight.
>> Was he?
>> I I did retweet a
>> Bobby. Somebody 7 seconds ago named
leftist suck says, "Cook these frauds,
Willie." I think they think it's
serious.
>> They They think he's out.
>> Bobby's about to be quote training right
now.
>> I'mma just keep these retweeted, dog.
>> Oh man, that's so good.
>> They think he's serious.
>> Gosh.
>> My favorite, like I said, the the my man
Deva was good, but I don't like
Kyleman's haircut is pretty good, too.
Lord,
>> I'm going to retweet the V. My bad.
That's just
>> Nicely done, Bobby. Nicely done.
>> I should never have left this up.
>> I hope you guys are having fun. We I
usually ask around this time when we're
killing a little bit of time, waiting on
the the draft. Where are you watching
from? Send us tag us.
>> We got a question.
>> Yeah, we can answer some questions on
the.com side of things. Uh at the
moment, we
>> Twitter on the 20. We can do a little
hashtag or something.
>> Yeah, we could. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. tag us
in it.
>> Oh, the offensive tackle from the&m went
Demetrius Crown over. Yeah.
>> U so finally we're back to drafting.
>> But uh but yeah, go ahead and tag us.
Tell us where you're watching from. If
you've been watching all three days
questions, y'all got questions for the
draft show. V going gonna tweet that
out.
>> Yeah.
>> So go find VC. My man. My man.
>> I wanna I want you to screenshot that
and make that your cover photo.
>> My man.
>> Yeah. I don't know.
>> Oh, man. All right. Rams are on the
clock. Their pick is in. Then it's the
Vikings, the Seahawks, the Dolphins, and
the Packers. Uh middle portions of the
sixth round here. Once again, the
Cowboys, I mean, they pick right at the
jump of the seventh round. That's the
Cardinals at 217, then the Cowboys at
218. So, we are starting to get at least
into the realm of everybody working back
into the room and yeah,
>> getting close to to having some
conversations here. And we'll have that
on the radio side as well.
Welcome back in as our coverage
continues. It's day three of the 2026
NFL draft. Having some fun with Bobby
Belt, Brian Brada, Zack Walchuk, all of
1053 the fan, Nick Harris of the Fort
Worth Star Telegram, and then Votamardi,
my man from the YouTube and Crown Global
Media. I'm Kyle Yman's from
DallasCowboys.com. We've had Tommy
Yarish in and out as well from
DallasCowboys.com. At the moment, he's
just out. I don't know. I don't know
where Tommy
>> I don't know where Tommy went.
>> Uh, but he's he's around here somewhere.
>> But appreciate you joining us wherever
you may be joining us. We put this uh
request out on the uh the
DallasCowboys.com stream side of things.
But if you're watching, let us know how
long you've been watching, where you're
watching from. We always love seeing uh
how much you guys love the the content
and the fun that we have over the
weekend. But also, uh send us some
questions. Vot is going to put out a
tweet uh here in a moment or a post, I
guess, on X. Uh and then we'll uh we'll
talk about uh some of your questions as
well as we've got about 20 picks
remaining. just went
>> 20 picks remaining until the Cowboys are
up. And yeah, CJ Daniels is the most
recent pick, wide receiver from Miami at
197. I'm going to catch you up for a
couple of them that we missed on the
radio side. 194 Tennessee takes Pat
Kugan, center from Indiana, and the Rose
Bowl MVP. 195, the Raiders take Malik
Benson, the wide receiver from Oregon,
uh goes to Las Vegas. Demetrius
Crownover, the offensive tackle from
Texas A&M, goes to the Patriots at 196.
And then CJ Daniels, the wide receiver
from Miami, goes to the Rams at 197, as
Brian talked about. Do you want to talk
about him, Bratus?
>> Yeah, let me do some housekeeping here
real quick. Uh, but yeah, let me uh let
me get to my notes on him as the wide
receivers.
Uh, but yeah, I was surprised. I I was
told from a team that his knee's not
good. So, this I guess we're getting
late in the late in the day and and uh
you know, you're looking for guys that
we always talk about the traits and
stuff, but let me get to my notes if I
could. And uh I'll read you what I had
on this guy. Um
Daniels, why does it always do this to
me when I ask it? Uh yeah, he's Miami
62205 is what I was going with.
Impressive the way he attacks the ball.
I think he's got a knack for making huge
plays when it comes to contested passes.
He'll contort his body in all kinds of
ways to bring the ball down. He does a
really nice job of tracking the ball and
coming down with it. The concentration
level I thought was super high. Uh there
are passes he brings down which you feel
like he has no chance to get. He'll line
up in different spots in the formation.
He could play outside. He can line up in
the slot. He's got some initial
quickness off the line for a guy his
size. Uh you can get him into the route
quickly in order to get to top speed.
He's got some running back skills with
the ball in his hands. I thought he'll
make his share of plays when it comes
down to with the run after catch. Uh
does a really nice job of finishing
runs. I'm surprised he didn't have more
receptions due to his playmaking
ability.
>> He's the type of receiver who can make
things happen. So yeah, but there's a
need there's a knee issue that teams
were dealing with right there.
>> The Mon Clayborn and the Vikings.
>> Yeah, he goes 198 to uh to Minnesota and
then the Seahawks are on the clock here
at 199. Looks like Emanuel Henderson Jr.
here. The wide receiver from Kansas is
the pick for the Seahawks there.
>> If if Deont Claybourne ends up being
what I think he will be, which is a
starter in the NFL and a very capable
starter in the NFL, I am going to start
a service for um scouting day three
running backs for NFL teams.
>> Kyle Manungai a couple years ago. Um and
this year it's it's Dean Clayborn, I
guess. I thought he would be going way
earlier on day three. I don't get it. I
don't get it.
>> I don't either.
>> Maybe could he add 15 pounds? Sure. But
I I I don't understand why he's still
sitting here. 4-37 speed between the
tackles, outside zone, explosive. Uh
great vision. Um foot quickness is
there. Uh great contact balance despite
being 188 pounds. I I don't get it.
Return value receiving. Like what else
do you want?
>> Incredibly shifty, agile. Yeah, keep
going. You got it.
>> He can return kicks. You know, he's got
a twin brother named Damian.
Does he?
>> He does. He's got three other brothers,
too.
>> Oh, shoot. I should have made him a
second round there.
>> Just, you know, he's a twin.
>> Right up the board.
>> He's a good space player.
>> Vikings pass.
>> The issue is the the fumbles. My bad.
>> It glitched on the system.
>> Glitched. Okay. My bad. My going crazy.
I
>> apolog
Trout on Twitter says he's listening
from North Carolina. Appreciate your
player. He says, uh, do you think the
Cowboys have done enough at linebacker?
Nah, they still need to add. Whether
that be free agency and picking here at
218 or
free agency trade, they only have four
offball linebackers on the roster right
now. True offball linebackers. It
depends on how you want to factor in Jan
Barum. And
>> it sounds like Maris Leafoul is going to
kind of be more of the Jan Barum line of
thinking, not not a true outside
linebacker. I heard that somewhere in
the last 24 hours. It's been a lot of
conversations.
>> Yeah.
>> Um, so that I thought that was
fascinating. So, if you're looking for
like those versatile guys that'll play
both, Leaf apparently is factored into
that. But if you're looking for just
true offball guys, four of them on the
roster right now, three of them that you
would expect to be on the 53, so you
need to add more there. Yeah.
>> Ryan Sims asked, "Would you guys
consider Nusmeire at 218? Might as well
at this point."
>> Yeah.
>> Ah, I'm good.
>> Another dart at at defense or
>> I'm good. take one of the guys that
you're you're going to try and sign in
terms of a undrafted free agent at wide
receiver possibly. Um, couple of those
opportunities as well. The uh got some
international uh responses. Portugal,
England, Spain.
>> Okay.
>> Um, looking for There's New Hampshire
right there. Oh, no, excuse me. Maine.
Elliot, Maine. Right on the border of
New Hampshire, it says. Um,
>> may as well be international.
>> Yeah, it's up there. Uh
>> DJ Campbell, the guard from uh Texas.
This one,
>> I thought he was going to be awesome
when he first went to Texas and it just
he was okay. Just kind of
>> just a massive human being. I I just
thought he'd have more power for how
large of a specimen he is.
>> Did he get banged up at all?
>> No, just um
>> I think the ability is not great.
>> Not particularly athletic.
>> Didn't really show up in uh he he always
showed up in big games, but against like
the Kuckies and the Mississippi States,
he didn't really. And that that goes
back to his high school days, too. Like
he didn't really show up against lesser
competition.
>> Interesting.
>> JSB from South London asks, "How do we
feel about the draft overall?" But let
me make it more difficult because we all
love downs. How do you guys feel about
what we've done so far in day three, not
counting the the uh trade with Dwinners
for for Dwinners?
>> Just a just a question. How does the
Penn State tackle Shelton?
>> Drew Shelton.
>> That might be the biggest question I
have.
>> Huge question. Yeah.
>> Yeah. But other than that, I think I'm
okay with what's going on in day three.
>> Yeah,
>> I like more a bunch.
>> I think more I like more a bunch as
well. And I think they I think they
might play him at at safety. I I really
really do. Maybe, you know, he we'll see
with the corner stuff. I hope he doesn't
one of these things where he plays
corner safety and they don't find a spot
for him. Yeah.
>> But I think he's got some safety type
traits to him with the length and stuff,
the the way he plays with eyes. He's a
smart guy, high IQ guy. I I'm thinking
that. I the Shelton one.
I'm You know what? Need to see that one.
Need to see how that's going to play.
>> Why is that a question mark? Like why
why don't you see that at the same way
that they would because they were pretty
>> I haven't seen a lot of things that that
the way they have. I mean to be honest
with you, but I mean that's let me let
me get my
>> Brian likes his tackles to be a little
more powerful and
>> he is very athletic
>> and he saw some film where Sheldon
probably got walked a little bit. Yeah,
he he does get pushed backwards, but he
moves very well.
>> Yeah. And I And I felt the move
>> and and I felt the same damn thing about
our guy from North Carolina several
years ago,
>> Austin Richards.
>> Awesome.
>> Richards thought the same thing, you
know. I just they they have not whether
it's they have not had really good
success. Help me here, Nick, with this.
when you start to talk about like the
the balls, the Wletkos, the awesome
Richards, it seems like we're kind of
throwing a dart at a tackle
>> and done it every year
>> and it and it doesn't it doesn't pan out
the way that I do. Maybe it's
>> Nate Thomas.
>> It's when they take a tackle or
something or offensive line earlier
>> tends to work out better for him when
the the vision for the player. So yeah,
I that would be my
>> it does seem like with this one that
there's more of a plan and you've got,
you know, Clayton Adams who clearly
wanted him and likes him. Uh so I mean
that's the one thing I love about all
three of these picks. I do like Deon
Moore where they got him. I like LT
Overton where they got him. Yeah.
>> Drew Shelton I thought was probably the
best tackle there. Uh he was he was
right around where Demetrius Crownover
was. I mean all these guys I thought had
flaws. Shelton probably had the most
consistent tape out of my opinion, but
he he does give up some power. But I do
like that they seem to have a vision for
what they want and and how these guys
will help the football team.
>> I I think that's the thing is they have
they have a plan for LT Overton. They
have a plan for um for Shelton and for
more and it may not be a starting
caliber thing now, but they have
packages that they can use those guys. I
I don't think they're bringing in
Shelton to try and compete right this
second with Tyler Gayton, Terrence
Steel, whoever it is. I think they are
competing for a swing tackle spot. He he
could come in and immediately be a
conversation for a swing tackle spot and
they're going to move him more and
choose choose to see the athleticism
because they liked Farmer too. Remember
they liked Farmer out of Kentucky but
they saw straightforward strength guy
>> and they didn't feel like they needed
that.
>> Initially I didn't think that
>> initially I didn't like Farmer and Vot
and I were talking and I started
watching him and I'm like I had a bad
day
>> and then I started talking to people in
the league. I said, "Hey, I'm I'm
struggling right now with this farmer."
And they were telling me about and it
was in line with what Votch was talking
about. We were broadcasting about it.
And then I'm thinking, "Okay, so I do
have him a higher than Shelton." And I'm
thinking, and then what happens the very
next pick?
>> They take Farmer. Farmer goes the very
next picked after Shelton. And you're
like going,
>> "Oh, damn. Did I, you know, did we did
we miss an opportunity there?" And and
maybe they were talking about him. Maybe
they were in that room talking about
him. And I, you know, you just, you just
hope that, but you just hope it works
out for him.
>> Just to ask the question, what does
Farmer give you that TJ Bass doesn't
already have on your football team?
>> I don't think TJ Bass is here for the
long haul.
>> Yeah. Four years versus one year.
>> I'm just asking. And I think TJ Bass is
TJ Bass should probably been drafted.
Yes.
>> Way back in the day, should have been
drafted. But is TJ Bass going to be a
guy that's going to be, you know, it's
expensive and he's going to be gone? And
you know, I'm just I'm just kind of
resetting. I think Farmer might be even
a better player.
>> I think he's way more powerful.
>> Way more powerful than better.
>> I mean, your middle would be if you if
you let's say and again I mean let's
that would be Tyler Smith probably
moving out to left tackle if you wanted
to start a a farmer.
>> I think Farmer can't start.
>> I do too. I mean I think it would have
been Farmer BB Booker and now you have a
mean nasty and you do anyway with Smith
there but if you're maybe you're better
covered at left tackle. I mean, I I I
get the concerns. I I understand it
100%. If they had have drafted Farmer
and you wanted to play your top five and
Gayton doesn't
>> prove that he can start,
>> that probably that might have ended up
being the way that you go.
>> Yeah, I'm sure these are similar to the
conversations that they had in the war
room going into that uh selection. Or if
the if those were the exact two names.
Remember last night when we got off the
air as we were waiting on the press
conference, we were looking at the war
room film and we saw Conor Riley come
into the room. We saw Clayton Adams come
to the room and they had a a decent
discussion just over the last 5 to 10
minutes prior to the press conference
and that had to be an offensive line
discussion. Then it ends up being
Shelton as the first pick uh the next
day 12 picks into the fourth round. So
they had discussions about Shelton andor
somebody else. If it's Farmer maybe
that's who was on our boards. If it's
anybody else that's out there. I think
they had those different conversations
and stacked their board one way or the
other uh in that case. All right, couple
of picks to catch you up on. Emanuel
Henderson Jr., the wide receiver from
Kansas, goes to the Seahawks at 199.
Dolphins at pick number 200. We're now
in the 200s, gentlemen. Uh DJ Campbell,
the guard out of Texas as as Walchuk
mentioned earlier, another Texas pick
for Miami. They've been very active.
They took Trey Moore earlier in the day.
>> Three Texas Longhorns. Yeah, Demani
Jackson, corner from Alabama, goes to
the Packers at 2012.
It was Logan Taylor, the guard from
Boston College to the Chargers. The Jags
just made the most recent selection at
203. CJ Williams, wide receiver from
Stanford.
>> Don't know what the Jaguars are doing.
>> It was a little
>> like how could you look at CJ Williams
and and look at Jeff Caldwell or some of
these other receivers on the board and
take
>> I don't know. I
>> I like
>> he also doesn't have a head shot on
NFL.com.
>> Yeah. So, he was a former big-time
recruit. I got to cover him, and he just
he doesn't have separation ability. Uh,
he used to have contested catch ability
before some injuries caught up to him.
He started at USC, went to Wisconsin,
went to Stanford, finished with 1,179
total yards in receiving over the course
of his career. That's a six- round draft
pick.
>> So, I I don't know. I don't know. I
don't know what I'm doing.
>> Except for day three running backs.
You've got that one down,
>> I guess. But even then apparently I
don't know what I'm doing because Deon
Claybornne's going in the sixth round.
>> I I I think every year I get hot around
this time. I'm like what what what are
we doing? What are we doing in certain
aspects?
>> Is it just traits at this point when
you're Is that why it gets so wonky
because it should be
>> it's not value based
>> but there's guys with actual proven
production with traits still on the
board. So that's where I ask what am I
doing?
>> I agree with you.
>> I got to look in the mirror.
>> I mean Trey, we were just talking about
TJ Bass. TJ Bass was a fourth round
grade on my board that year. I thought
he should have been drafted. He had
production. He had tape. He had all of
it. He ended up not being drafted and
now he's stuck stuck around the league
the majority uh more than what that
draft class was even when he was uh in
that point. So, lots of conversations in
the Cowboys war room. They are all back
in there and getting closer and closer
to their pick at 218. We are officially
in the 200s as the Texans are on the
clock here in the sixth round of the
2026 NFL draft. Our continued covers or
our coverage continues right after this
on the Dallas Cowboys radio network and
DallasCowboys.com.
>> You know what, Kyle? Uh Mark from
England uh just wanted to tell everybody
thank you. Fantastic work. But one thing
that I've So thank you Mark. But but I I
have noticed just out of all the
questions that I got, I got about a hund
of them. I'm just going to be sifting
through them. Nice.
>> It's been about 20 questions like all in
the bunch saying, "Hey man, Harold
Perkins, what's going on?" And I would
love to know the answers to to what's
going on with that,
>> man.
>> I know like it's it's fair to be like I
don't know what we do with him,
>> but Lewis Bond from Boston College just
went to the Texans or whatever. Whoever
that is.
>> Yep. It was the Texans at 204.
>> Who whoever that is.
>> Like what are we doing? You know what
I'm saying? Like I think this is past I
don't know where to play him in my
scheme.
>> Yeah. Yeah, I don't get it. I I'm with
you 100%. I mean, Harold Perkins is a
player with a lot of talent. You could
play him at linebacker if you want. I
think if you put him back to edge, he
he's going to be a phenomenal player. I
mean, there's players like Kaden Curry,
uh Max Llewellyn, I know you guys like a
lot. VJ Payne, I don't get it. Rach
Benny from Michigan, I think you could
play up and down the line of scrimmage.
>> Some of these receivers going over Jeff
Caldwell out of Cincinnati, I think, is
pretty crazy.
Yeah, he's the highest player left on my
>> There's a There's a lot of really good
players still here and
>> him and Robert Spears Jennings.
>> Nuts.
>> Yeah,
>> I did say no, but I know it's out there,
though.
>> But but I mean, I'm straight, but them
jaws just look glisteny and delicious.
>> Oh, it's it's fantastic.
>> It's really good.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Let me just
>> There's a box out there. Go get it.
>> Just step out.
>> I think so.
>> They put their foot in it on Saturday
every year.
>> Also, there's cookies in the uh in the
control room. Not that it's cool, but I
mean
>> I'm just look they just look glisteny.
>> There are also desserts in the control
room if you would like some of those.
>> Damn.
>> Just for those that are wondering. There
you go. Tommy's already hit a couple of
those. Hey Tommy, where have you been,
dude?
>> For us.
Is it time you
>> like is it your time?
>> Is it?
>> I don't even know.
>> Just about.
>> Is that for me?
>> Oh, it's time for us to go on break. Oh,
boy. Hey, man. Let me tell y'all
something. Uh Kyle, you can just go to
my Twitter
>> just find all the questions. Thanks,
man. Man, we were about to run through a
hundred of them and it's Votch that's
not able to to be on there.
>> I just want to let y'all know I love
you, man. I'll be back for the Cowboys
pick or something. I mean, they about to
pick in what, 12 picks, 10?
>> Yeah, about 10.
>> Yeah, I'll pop back up. Catch y'all
later.
>> Oh goodness.
>> Long lunch break.
>> Yeah, we do. Skyler Gil Howard,
defensive tackle from Texas Tech, goes
to the Lions at 205. I
>> liked his proday.
>> Did you? He's a talented player. I mean,
he did get hurt during the season there
at Tech. Uh, and and they were able to
withstand that injury. Lee Hunter
obviously stepped up big for them, but
he he if he doesn't get hurt, I think he
probably gets taken much higher than
this.
>> He's the other defensive tackle that was
beside Lee Hunter
throughout the the Texas Tech year. Best
front seven in college football. You
might as well take a stab at somebody
that was in it, you know.
>> You might as well.
>> Other than Jacob Rodri, you guys,
>> course you don't want to take that guy.
>> That was a bad bad.
>> Who the hell would
>> Yeah, Miami. And that's why they that's
why they they lose all their games.
>> They're just I mean the draft's looking
terrible for them.
>> Hey Tommy.
>> Hello everyone.
>> Hi Tommy.
>> Hi K.
>> Trying to find Vatcha's Twitter. All
these notifications.
>> I got you. You want me to Yeah, go for
it. You want me to pump them out? Pump
pump. I got the Twitter up because
Bobb's been on it.
>> That's true. So, and I've got
>> those tweets are blowing up.
>> They are. I got a lot of comments. I'm
just going to leave them up, too,
because I think people most people know
that this was Bobby, but then there's
other people that are like, "What the
hell?" They're like, "Dude, this guy's
so right.
>> Serious? What are you doing? What's
wrong with you?" Uh, okay.
>> You got tripped.
>> That scared me.
>> Let's find this vot tweet. I like one of
the responses on the you should just
remove Kyle as host tweet says, "Does
the show like short hosts though?
Brian Bryan
>> short games crown global.
>> What do we got? What do we got to do to
get your Twitter back, man? Have you
given up?
>> I don't think you should give up. I
think there I think there's got to be
some sort of cuz it's happened so much
in the last couple of months to
everybody that I think there's been more
intention put in the last couple of
months.
>> We're too busy. We're too busy being
political and firing rockets into the
sky to worry about Twitter accounts.
>> That is very true.
>> It is true.
>> That's very true.
>> That's fair. I mean, I'm a I'm a premium
member with them. Over 100,000 125,000
followers.
>> Unbelievable.
>> I mean, I've tried. I tried. And there's
people around the country that have
tried to help me.
>> No avail.
>> That's a wild That's terrible.
>> All right. I got a question pulled up we
can hit.
>> Yeah. Let's wait for the radio side and
then we will knock it out. Some really
good uh responses here on who and where
they've been watching. I'll hit some of
those here in a little bit, too.
Good stuff, boys.
>> Thanks for grabbing the food.
>> Yeah, it's good, right?
>> Scott Purcell helped. Thank you, Scott.
All right, we are in the penultimate
hour of our coverage on 1053 the fan and
DallasCowboys.com
as we are now at pick number 206 in the
middle of the sixth round of the 2026
NFL draft alongside Nick Harris of the
Fort Worth Star Telegram. Brian Bratis
and Zack Walchuk hosts on the GBag
Nation on 1053 the fan. We've got Tommy
Yarish, Cowboys beat writer and insider
for DallasCowboys.com. I'm Kyleman's the
TV host and a podcast host for the
Dallas Cowboys hosting your coverage
this weekend. We've also got Bobby Belt
and Vot Lombardi mixing in. Uh they are
currently on break at the moment. Let's
run down some of the most recent
selections as the Cowboys are now
closing in on 10 picks away from their
final selection scheduled in this year's
NFL draft. Logan Taylor, guard from
Boston College, goes 202 to the
Chargers. The Jags take CJ Williams,
wide receiver from Stanford at 203. 204,
Lewis Bond, the wide receiver from
Boston College, goes to the Texans. 205,
it was the Lions, Skyler Gil Howard, the
defensive tackle from Texas Tech. And
then the Chargers back on the clock
again at 206, take Alex Harky, the guard
from Oregon. It is the Eagles on the
clock right now, followed by the
Falcons, Commanders, Steelers, and
Ravens. Nick, based on your board right
now, as we're getting into Cowboys
territory for that pick at 218, who are
some of the names that we should
probably keep an eye on?
>> Yeah, I've been wondering about Cole
Wisnueski. Wasi
Tech out of Texas Tech. That was
somebody that they had a 30 visit with
and it it wasn't qualified as a local
day. He's not a DFW product. So, this
was a true 30 visit for Cole Wooki.
>> All right.
>> Do you like him though?
>> Uh, I do. I do. I I uh I put him Let's
see. Um
I put him at the top of the sixth round.
Um, really good tackler, flies downhill
to make impact plays on ball carriers
despite not having the speed you might
want at the NFL level to be a starter.
Uh, this one could end up being a
starter though with his instincts and
range and just having the ability to
always be around the football. At the
very least, he'll provide day one
special teams ability. He will be
starting his rookie season at 24 and a
half years old. Uh, had a torn Achilles
in 2022 and missed seven games. Broke
his left foot in 24 and missed the whole
season. So, he's got a little bit of
injury history coming from North Dakota
State, but overall, u fascinating
player. That's one to look at. We've
talked about Michael Trigg. There's
connections there. Uh RJ Maryland,
obviously connections there. Um gosh,
there's got to be a running back, too.
>> McGawan.
>> Uh no,
>> they they draft him.
>> Not looking at McGowan. I think he's
going to be an undrafted guy.
>> Same with EJ Smith.
>> Um undrafted guy.
>> Uh hot maybe
>> undrafted guy.
>> Okay. Jamari Taylor.
>> I would I would like it. There haven't
there haven't been any connections other
than was he a he was a shrine guy, was
he not? Or his senior bowl.
>> Oh, I think he was senior bowl.
>> Taylor was senior. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Um
>> yeah. So, I mean it they don't
necessarily have to have a connection
for the Cowboys to draft them. Um I
don't think there was really a lot of
connections with Drew Shelton. Um but um
nevertheless, yeah, I think there's
going to be some players here. I would
be looking at
>> maybe one last offensive guy just to
come away in the class with two
offensive players. Uh, but if you're
asking me, I I would love, you know,
just to get an offball Mike linebacker
at this spot. Red Murdoch is still on
the board, isn't he? Um,
>> Aiden Fischer still on the board.
>> Tory New York's still on the board.
>> Um, Harold Perkins, they have been
connected to through the process.
>> Harold Perkins, please.
>> Yeah. Um,
>> I'd love that.
>> That would be that would feel like a
fourth round pick at seven in the
seventh round. It would feel like that.
>> It'd be a lot of fun. Um, I like Jackson
Kuwatch as an undrafted guy out of
Miami, Ohio as a offball linebacker.
>> Um, Ernest Hman is another interesting
offball linebacker out of Michigan. Um,
a quick note on Ernest Hman. He's the
youngest of 23 children.
>> What?
>> Yeah. My goodness.
>> Insane stuff.
>> Reggie born in Uganda.
>> Oh, from tech.
>> He's been taken.
>> He did get taken. I was in the bathroom.
>> Bobby didn't tell you.
>> No, Bobby didn't. Let me Did uh Jack
Kelly get taken?
>> Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay,
>> there you go. Refresh.
>> Uh also, Alex Harky, we mentioned out of
Oregon to the Chargers. The Ram or
excuse me, the Eagles take Micah Morris,
the interior offensive lineman, aka the
guard for Georgia. Uh Harky went to the
Chargers.
>> Oh, dang. He went to the Giants.
>> What was it,
>> Kelly? He went to the Giants.
>> Oh, yeah. Falcons on the clock, followed
by the Commanders.
>> Micah Morris going to the Eagles. I
mean, that's just two massive offensive
linemen they've taken. Now,
>> I like Michael Morris.
>> Morris. Tell me about Michael Morris a
little bit here.
>> Yeah, let me see if I can pull up uh
Sorry, I've had like a million things
going on over here. Do you have it in
front of you by chance Walchuk?
>> Yeah, I mean he's super wide body. I do
think he plays with some power. I like
the hand placement. Uh his pad level is
something to me that like I thought he
could have worked on, but in big games
and against some quality competition
like Alabama, LSU, like you see him play
really well and rise to the occasion.
He's a guy that I thought played a lot
at Georgia. I was a fan of Morris. I
actually had him in the fifth round. For
him to be here in the six. I think he's
actually got some pretty decent
athleticism for his size. You can see
him get out in space. I like some
nastiness to his game. He's one of these
guys that'll finish you uh and and put
you in the ground, let you know about
it. Um but, you know, I I guess there
are some slipperiness like in terms of
faster upfield guys. They can kind of
dip underneath him and give him some
trouble. Yeah, he's a big guy. There's a
lot to There's a lot to take on.
>> There's a lot of man there.
>> 335 pounds. Uh he plays super high.
That's the one thing, I guess. But
that's a that's kind of what you get
with a guy that that big. But um he's a
mer in the run. Mauler in the run game.
Um
>> I just want to see a bit more
athleticism in the foam in the foam
booth, if you will, and pass protection.
But uh yeah, this a good six round pick,
man. They they just the Eagles
philosophy over the last couple of years
of just getting like the ginormous
offensive lineman is fascinating. Like
so you get Markeel Bell and Michael
Morris this year. You pair them with
Cameron Williams from what that was last
year, right?
>> Uh yeah, fascinating.
>> I'm surprised they didn't take DJ
Campbell.
>> Not big enough.
>> Yeah, you're probably
>> big enough. Which is funny because huge
Kyle Flood, the offensive line coach at
Texas, we used to have a joke in the
recruiting rankings is like uh his like
first question to recruits would be
like, "So like how much money do you
spend at like fast food restaurants?"
And like you have to meet like a certain
level for him to even like want you cuz
he always just took the fat guys.
>> Yeah.
>> He always took the fat guys. And so it's
Cameron Williams. It was like, "Oh,
that's Kyle Flood's dream."
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. And and
>> how much was he spending? Do we know? Do
we have a number?
>> Oh man, there's no telling. It was all
of his NIL bag. a lot. But
>> Waterburger's the uh the sponsor here,
right? Yeah, he was he was spinning it
all at Waterburger.
>> Yeah, we got Waterburger and Wingstop, a
couple other ones, you know.
>> Is there anybody you absolutely don't
want to fight for in free agency?
>> Because you got to make that pick count.
I I think this when you get to the when
you get to this point in the draft, you
know, and as the board has been
completely picked over,
you need to just take whoever that best
player on your highest rated player on
that board. Mhm.
>> I think regardless of the position,
whoever your whoever your highest rated
player is and the highest rated player
on your stack, just take that player,
>> you think about what they've done with
that the last couple years,
>> you what? No seventh round picks, right?
>> I mean, you just you just go ahead and
whoever that player is with with like I
say, no seventh round picks. just you're
better off trying to say, "Listen, we
might have had a fifth round grade on
this guy or a sixth round grade on this
guy and then and then and call it a
night and then go work on free agency
and hopes their board isn't completely
picked over at the end of it." So, you
know, Dallas is going to go and get free
agents off their board. That's the first
place that they're going to go.
>> Yeah.
>> Is they're going to go off their board.
So, in this case, when you get this,
just take your highest rated player
regardless of the position. Think about
the seventh round picks that Dallas has
has made the last couple of years. Jay
Toya last year, uh Phil Mafa last year,
Tommy King Basot last year. Yeah.
>> Uh 2024 was Nathan Thomas and Justin
Rodgers. 2023 good indication of what
you're talking about. Jordan Brooks, the
wide receiver, thought maybe he would be
a UDFA. Yeah. Instead, they said, "No,
let's not take a a risk on him falling
to somebody else." They did the same
with Matt Farnio back in 2021. Uh Ben
Denucci in 2020. They do it every year.
>> Well, yeah. The I think the Ben Denucci
one was was Mike McCarthy's.
>> They ran into him in an elevator. Yeah.
And Ben's a great guy. I mean, he is but
just a poor football player. The uh
>> good broadcaster now, I guess.
>> Yeah. And and doing a fine job. The But
yeah, whoever whoever that player is,
because you're not going to have another
crack at this. you're gonna go straight
from this to now trying to figure out
free agency, you know, and then Stephen
Jones is going to give them their
marching orders like, "Okay, here are
the numbers. We got to try and get this
many guys and stuff like that." So, um I
would I would take it regardless of
position, take the guy.
>> Yeah.
>> Take whoever the best guy is on board.
Tell What's the situation with your long
snapper by the way with Ste? Is he is he
expensive guy? I don't think he's I mean
he's he's on a top two contract in the
league at long snap.
>> He's top two.
>> There's not a lot of difference there.
>> I was wondering if you can you move on
from that. I mean I know it's I know
it's if you wanted to just use a pick.
How about a punter?
>> Well, if you'd like to know about the
punters and the kickers
punter's 38.
>> Is your punter starting to show wear and
tear?
>> I don't think so.
>> I know he holds well. He does a great
job of holding for your guy. But to me,
is is there is there the wear and tear?
Do we see the distance? Are we starting
to see like I don't know. I'm watching
games. I'm kind of like going, man, that
that's a that's kind of an average
looking 42 yard right there.
>> You know, I I'm just trying to think of
how to use the best the best way to use
this last pick. If it's a the punter
guy, I know you're not going to do the
kicker guy
for me might be the guy. Maybe maybe
you're maybe maybe you look at the
returner, you know, maybe you want to,
you know, maybe you want to move on from
>> get a burner.
>> Yeah. Get somebody that can, but I I
would take whoever the best player on my
board is and then and then call it a
day.
>> Just figure it out from there. Matt.
Yeah. Uh Goldman, center from Michigan
State, goes to the Commanders at 209.
>> They needed a center. They moved on from
Tyler Bianish. Goldman's not a bad
player.
>> You think he's their answer in the
sixth?
>> I don't know about immediately. I think
he could develop into a guy. I mean, he
played 52 games over the course of five
seasons. He transferred from Wake Forest
to Michigan State and he played most of
his career there. He was a team captain.
Uh he's got a good slide to mirror. He
moves well laterally. Uh he's one of
these guys that plays with power. He can
knock people on their rear. He can drive
his feet to create movement in the
running game. The combo blocks are
there. He just doesn't have the mass and
the upper body strength that you really
need. But he does have good leverage.
You'll just see him get over extand
overextended at times. that can, you
know, I don't know. I mean, to me, like,
is he a guy that'll carry that over to
the next level? The tape's solid. I I I
like the player overall, but at 64305,
he's just kind of a light center.
>> Yeah, we that's kind of been the kind of
what they've done.
>> That's kind of what Well, no, that's
just kind of what going on in the
National Football League right now,
right? All these centers, the
slaughters, the lose, the
>> other than your guy at Kansas State,
they've all been kind of 305, 300, 299.
I mean, he did start games at both guard
spots and center, so maybe they're not
going to leave him at center. But, I
mean, that that's definitely like when
you're looking at a backup offensive
lineman like you've had with Brock
Hoffman and TJ Bass. And I mean, he can
play all three of your interior line
spots.
>> Yeah. Getting some good look of it now
on the Wake Forest film
up against some ACC competition. He's
holding his own. He's not a bad player.
>> Yeah.
>> You think he ran the ball well.
>> You think Do you think he is a center,
Zach, or is he a guard? Which one do you
think? I think he is a center. Yeah. I
mean, I I I would keep him there, but
for them, I don't know. Like, did they s
What's their situation right now? I
know. I don't know. Did they make up for
Beish? I'm going to look up their death
chart.
Maybe. So,
>> I don't know if they did or not.
>> We've got some uh
>> Oh, yeah. Nick Aliggretti.
>> Oh, yeah. There you go.
>> That's their guy.
>> So, this is their reserve. Maybe try and
Yeah.
>> work him into a conversation sort of
guy. Got some questions here from the
fans. Do you guys want to answer them?
Let's go. Let's do this.
>> We'll we'll knock out a few, take a
break, and then we'll get ready for the
Cowboys pick, and then we'll come back
to uh some fan questions on the back
half of the seventh round. Uh Oswaldo
wants to know since we're getting close
to the Cowboys pick. Yeah, he's our guy.
Uh Renee Conga or Jay Ratliff to finish
the 2025s
>> draft. He was a 30 visit.
>> About Renee Conga. Yeah, I forgot about
Renee Conga.
>> Do you feel like that's off the table
with Overton? No, I don't think you can
have enough to completely different guy.
>> Yeah.
>> Um Yeah. Fascinating. Yeah. I think
Renee Conger should definitely be on the
radar.
>> You You're talking about three technique
guys here.
>> Yes. That that was where he was headed.
Alswaldo was
>> Yeah. I Me personally, I know you we
talked about earlier about Robinson from
Navy
>> would be you talk about an explosive get
across the line of scrimmage, get small,
attack gaps, make tackles in the back
field. But I I know he's way undersized.
Nick, did you mention Benny from uh
Michigan? You did not That was not when
you
>> I like him and I think he can play
multiple spots for you.
>> I I think him I mean I I have him above
the Conga guy as far as I
>> BJ Payne's probably my best guy left
from Kansas State. I'm surprised that
he's
>> But the uh the safety, right?
>> Safety. And I I know look, you've got
you've got safeties, but you got Lock on
a one-year deal. You've got Hooker who's
got one year left. I think VJ Payne at
the very least is going to be a special
teams contri contributor, but he's a
little bit different. I mean, he's got
he's 6'2. I think he moves well. I think
he's actually got some good coverage
ability. Come up and hit you. I'm really
He was 94 on my board. I'm really
surprised that I maybe something's wrong
with him. Maybe there's a medical. Maybe
he's done something terrible off the
field or he interviewed terribly. I
don't know. But to have VJ Payne from
Kansas State still available here.
>> No, we just had a punter go.
>> Who was it? Was it Stonehouse? Ryan Ryan
uh Eckley from Michigan State.
>> Okay, let's see. I'm checking. So,
Spitzy uh is our punter and kicker
expert. And uh that's not one of his
guys. He said the top two punters here.
>> Brett Thorson from Georgia.
>> Oh,
>> Ray Guy award winner. Big leg, 15 kicks
over 50 yards. Australian.
>> Shows how much I know about punters.
>> Aussies have punted well in the NFL.
He's a good athlete. He played
quarterback at one time prior to
Georgia.
>> Aussie Aussie Aussie
>> averages 45 and a half yards.
>> We're showing puns. Yeah, they have that
pro kick.
>> Let's go. Punter film. Chris Beam.
>> Let's go.
>> I love this consistency.
>> This is my favorite part of the draft.
>> This is good. Uh Jack Stonehouse from
Syracuse was his second guy. He
transferred from Missouri after his
freshman year. What a pedigree. Both his
father and cousin have punted in the
NFL. So, he's got the lineage here,
boys. East West Shrine game, strong at
the pooch punt to pin teams. His average
is just under 46 yards. So, those were
the top two punters according to our
punting and kicking insider. Uh, but he
did not have this guy from Michigan
State or this he's holding right now.
>> Yeah, I was about to say that was not
him kicking there.
>> It's not Kim.
>> Uh, but
>> the kicker Trey Smack from Florida and I
draft him just for that name alone. My
god, Trey Smack. That's outstanding. He
had a
>> I think he's top uh kicker
>> Trey Smack.
>> Okay, so Spitzy said Ekley was a
surprise third punter for him. That's a
bit of a surprise. Thought he maybe
overdrafted here.
>> Yeah, boss man needs to get back this
afternoon here. Hey, but hockey in about
15 minutes.
>> The pick was made by the Ravens, so that
it's a good pick.
>> Okay, that's what happens. It's the
Ravens.
>> Could they have Tyler Loop? Was that the
guy they initially uh had to replace?
What's his name? The massage guy.
>> Yeah. Well, that was the kicker. This
was a punter that they to that they
>> You know what? You're right. I'm just
I'm flipping punters and kickers.
>> Tucker.
>> They're not the same thing.
>> Tucker. Yeah,
>> that guy.
>> Yeah,
>> he was just talking.
>> Mhm. the uh uh oh here's a uh a guy who
visited for uh Dallas day uh Namdi
Obisor. Is that how you say it?
>> Obiser.
>> Obiser
TCU linebacker now, aren't you?
>> No, that one's OB.
>> No, I think that was actually how it is.
The uh linebacker from TCU.
>> Sometimes I do. You're right.
>> Yeah, I thought you were doing it that
case. Yeah,
>> I sir. Uh linebacker TCU goes to the
Patriots at 212,
>> but he was a guy that met with the
Cowboys and was in the building for a
little bit here. So, he was a Dallas day
guy.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Dallas.
>> You got a history on this kid at all?
>> Yeah. Let me pull it up.
>> I mean, I was just curious.
>> You give him a three star?
>> No. Uh, no. No. He was, uh, he wasn't
one of mine. Seventh round grade on him
for me.
>> Uh, converted safety, adequate
understanding of man and zone
responsibility, but really only factors
in on passing downs. The athleticism
finish rate is high enough for me to see
a special teams role early on while he
gets used to the linebacker position at
the NFL level. Uh, 81 tackles last year,
seven missed. More of a will outside
type of guy. Yeah, he he's got some
length. He's 45 speed. Uh only 190 pound
safety out of high school. Then they
bulked him up, moved him inside. Played
three years and started at linebacker.
So pretty interesting.
>> He's got a lot of velocity to his game.
>> Velocity.
>> Wait, what?
>> What you say that again?
>> Yeah. Velocitosity.
>> I like it.
>> He's a bit dinosaurian with the way he
plays.
>> All right, we got to take a break
because the Cowboys pick is coming up
very, very soon. You're listening to the
2026 NFL draft on the Dallas Cowboys
radio network and dallascowboys.com.
>> So Jerry's security guard just peaked
around the corner right here and I
thought for a second we may have been
getting Jerry. So I looked over at the
war room camera and he's still there and
I was like
>> he's still there.
>> He's hanging out. That would have been
cool.
>> That would have been wild.
>> Just make us let us make a picture.
>> I was like we've been trying to do that
for years
about Harold Perkins.
>> Yeah,
>> that would have that would have been
great. I think are the feminine.
>> We got Jerry in a headlock.
>> Yeah. We're like, "Okay, we're making
this pick."
>> Yes, you made that.
>> Perkins or else.
>> Guys, you guys have had a great draft.
You got Caleb DS. You redid your front
seven. Just let us have a little fun and
let us pick one. I think it'd be fun.
Just take it. Be great.
>> Nuts.
>> Seventh round.
>> And if if it hits its noting my LSU
guys, imagine like having a hard time
getting picked.
>> We draft like a starting left tackle who
plays for 15 years. He puts on a gold
jacket at the end of it and we drafted
him.
>> Did you know Tyron Smith was drafted out
of a podcast?
>> This is crazy.
>> If you want to make headlines, Jerry,
that's how you do it is you let the
podcast make the pick. It would go viral
immediately.
>> You have any idea how quickly that would
that would go? I mean, I'm just saying.
>> So, just ideas. We're all about content
here. That's all.
>> So, I'm catching up on some of these
pics here, fellas.
>> Hey, Tommy. Wow, that was like
>> Sorry about that.
>> That was like when you have a brick.
That was when you have a bad missing
basketball on the back mic on the
stansion catches and going off the back
rim. That's how bad that was. Um I'm
catching up on some of these picks here,
fellas. In sixth round, there was a run
of like six players that probably would
have been great for Dallas. I'm looking
at Jack Kelly at 193 to the Giants, the
linebacker from BYU. Pat Kugan to the
Titans, the next pick at 194 to the
Titans. Malik Benson, who the Raiders
traded up to get, um the wide receiver
from Oregon at 195. Demetrius Crownover,
the right tackle from Texas&M at 196. CJ
Daniels, the guy that we were talking
about earlier, the Rams at 197. And then
Deont Claybornne, the running back from
Wake Forest at 198. That's a tough
stretch there.
>> Yeah.
>> I mean, good picks, good players, but
>> you're getting wiped a little bit.
>> Is Jack Andre still on the board? He is.
Yeah. So they So that was So Tampa Bay
took Bower Sharp over Jack Andrews.
>> There's been a lot of wild tight end.
>> So strange.
>> I I don't understand.
>> Marlin Klein going in the third round.
Second or second or third round
yesterday was bonkers.
>> Sharp was a comfortable UDFA for me.
>> Uh oh yeah, Klein went in the second
>> second round.
>> It's got to be a high I acuity type of
player.
>> Not a Velociraptor.
>> No, he's not. He doesn't have the
velociastory.
>> Yeah, that's a
>> Is there anything else you want Is there
anything else you want to get in while
you're at it?
>> I mean, I don't know. I think Garrett
Nusmeire is very Omahanian.
>> Omahanian.
>> Mhm.
>> It's a good one.
>> Very smart. Smart player. He channels
after Peyton Manning.
>> Yeah,
>> Omahanian. Uh Jordan Vandenberg is the
pick for the Bears at 213. Jordan
Vandenberg. It's a cool name. Defensive
tackle out of Georgia Tech.
>> Yeah, it's it's a weird weirdly typed
name, too. And I'm very glad I don't
have to type that here at this franchise
for a while because the van and the den
are not capitalized.
>> Oh
>> yeah. It's but they're different words.
Like it's Jordan Van Denberg. Yeah. I
don't know.
>> It's like a It's like a lead in.
>> Yeah. It's German or something.
>> It's German.
>> We've heard we've heard from a couple of
uh international
>> Paris Fort Worth Star Tele.
>> Bobby Belt stole his phone too. It's It
wasn't me. He actually stole my voice
box. This is not me.
>> AI.
>> Jordan Vandenberg.
>> Wonder if Bobby actually just doesn't
like my haircut.
>> I I Maybe there is something there. I I
think it looks good, dude. Don't worry.
>> Maybe there's something there.
>> He doesn't even have enough.
>> Don't lie to him, Zach.
>> All right, three picks until we're into
the seventh round. Colts, Falcons,
Seahawks coming up here in a little bit.
Cowboys fans, while the team is making
big picks, make the smart pick at home.
Call OnTime Experts, the official AC,
heating, and plumbing partner of the
Dallas Cowboys. Fast, reliable, always
on time. That's on time experts. Visit
ontimeexperts.com and click book now.
Welcome back in to our ongoing coverage
as we wrap up the sixth round of the
2026 NFL draft. Only three selections
remain. The Colts, the Falcons, the
Seahawks, and that is it. The most
recent selections
coming off the board, Matt Goldman, the
center from Michigan State, goes 209 to
the Commanders. 210, the Pittsburgh
Steelers take Gabe Rubio, the defensive
end from Notre Dame. 211, the first
punter we've seen off the board. Ryan
Eckley, punter from Michigan State, goes
to the Ravens. 212, the Patriots take
Nami Obazor,
the tight or the TCU linebacker. And
then 213, Jordan Vandenberg, the
defensive tackle from Georgia Tech go or
Georgia Tech goes to the uh Chicago
Bears along with Nick Harris of the Fort
Worth Star Telegram, Brian Bratis and
Zack Walchuk of 1053 the fan. Tommy
Yarish of DallasCowboys.com
of DallasCowboys.com.
Kaden Curry, edge rusher from Ohio
State.
>> Oh, Kaden Curry goes to the Colts at
214. A
>> lot of cerebrality with the way that he
plays. This guy is a technician. I mean,
he's just one of these guys that does
the a lot of really good things well.
He's not going to wow you. I don't know
that he's got an elite trait, but Kaden
Curry is just a starter that can set the
edge for you, play the run, and he'll
give you a little pass rush ability. I
don't think he's going to be a double-
digit sack guy at all, but just a solid
all-around good football player.
>> What did you like about Curry there,
Brian?
>> Yeah, I think Zach's got him right
though. you, you know, a lot of sacks, a
lot of production, and he's one of these
guys that, you know, he has a really
good awareness of where the ball's
going. He's uh he knows how to read
blocks. He kind of gets himself off
blocks, puts himself in position to make
plays, plays down the line of scrimmage,
kind of moves around. Uh he's he's not
always for I don't think he's for
everybody's eye the way he plays, but
when you watch him, he does he he for
somehow someway he gets burst off the
line and then gets around the corner or
then or he works underneath and uh he
finds a way to to affect the pocket by
the way he attacks the pocket. Uh, I
thought he would go a little bit earlier
than where he's uh than than than what
we're looking at in the sixth round, but
no, he's a really a really good football
player.
So, we're sitting at the 215th pick. We
have 215 Falcons, 216 Seahawks, 217
Cardinals, and then it's the Cowboys on
the clock with their final pick of this
year's draft at 218.
Uh, Nick, any sort of thought process on
where they could be leaning? It goes
back to what we were talking about.
>> Yeah. Nothing at all. I think this is
just going to be whoever the BPA they
feel good about that they don't want to
have to fight for
>> in uh undrafted free agency and u you
know we'll see what it ends up being.
>> It really could be any position.
>> I have a feeling it's just a hunch is
all it is that it would be a wide
receiver.
>> Okay.
>> They've done that in the past. I mean
>> so you could go Deion Deion Burks. I
mean I know we were talking about him in
the hall Nick but I mean at this point I
wouldn't care. I mean, Jeff Caldwell
would be the guy that I would take if
I'm taking a wide receiver from
Cincinnati.
>> If he was taken, wasn't he?
>> No, I think he's still available.
>> Uh,
>> he's showing up to me as he's available.
>> I think he's still available.
>> Yeah, he's available.
>> You know who's not available?
>> I miss somebody then.
>> Who? How about the linebacker Harold
Perkins Jr. LSU 215 Falcons?
>> Gosh darn it. Atlanta.
>> We're in the seventh round now, right?
>> That was the next to last pick. We got
one more for the Seahawks or now it's
the Packers, but Packers have one more
pick in the sixth round. Brian,
>> it's a great pick.
>> Well, they need a James Pierce Jr.
replacement.
>> Yeah, the fact that he fell this far was
a little shocking. I I don't know. We
haven't had any sort of medical concern,
right? Nobody's heard anything.
>> No, it's just I think a lot of it has to
do with the uh I think a lot of it has
to do with what everybody's kind of
talking about that maybe it's they don't
have a position for him, you know? And I
like I I would personally I mean just
you can watch him his freshman year play
at LSU. And by the way biggest misuse of
a player I've ever seen in my life.
>> Uh you know they play him as an offball
linebacker and he's you know dropping in
coverage and the game's on the line
instead of rushing the passer he's
dropping in the space and not covering
anybody when he could be rushing the
passer. But this guy his freshman year
and into his sophomore year he got hurt
in the UCLA game. you know, hurt his
knee and had to rehab it and all that,
but man, I thought we he was one of
those guys that was going to get into
the portal and leave because of how
poorly we treated him when it came to
how we used him, but he stuck it out.
And, you know, unfortunately for him,
he's, you know, he's in he's getting
picked now here in the seventh round.
Good for him getting drafted, but my
gosh, what a what a fall for a player
that's I think he's super talented. He's
just he's small and you know, but teams
kind of figure out ways to use these
kinds of guys. A designated pass rusher,
nickel player. You know, there's there's
things you could do with this guy.
>> By the way, the first kicker is now off
the board. Trey Smack.
>> Trey Smack. How about that?
>> The guy you were just talking about.
>> Trey Smack getting picked, baby. Go
Gators. Oh, Shott. He's looking up. He's
like, "That's one of my guys. Let's go."
There's a Florida Gator. He is off the
board. one of the best kickers in all of
the NFL already kicked.
>> Wow, they got fired up over something.
Um
>> they're they're happy fired up.
>> Yeah, they were in the war room.
>> They were smacking the table and all
that.
>> I think it was for smack.
>> There you go.
>> We were smacking for smack.
>> Maybe they're drawing us off sides
again.
>> All right, Will just picked up the
phone. So now it's time to react. Where
are they going with whenever it comes to
the uh the thought process
in trying to find a uh an opportunity
about Xavier Harris?
>> Uh there was a lot to that medical.
>> It is a lot to that.
>> A lot of people are asking like why is
he sliding? Yeah.
>> And so that that's a medical thing.
That's the defensive tackle from Old
Miss. Something happened.
>> I No, not yet.
>> Okay. No, I'm sorry. the uh
>> Adams walking around the war room.
>> He's trying to drum up business in
there.
>> There's Junior Adams. You gota do you
gotta walk around and make sure they see
him. And they all they keep having to
yell for Christian Parker, you know.
See, your defensive coordinator, hey,
Christian, come on. Hey, he's he's
always kind of milling around like he's
waiting outside for a bus or something,
you know?
>> Yeah. Jerry's on the phone and Junior
Adams in the room.
>> Junior Adams getting a lot of DAP for
everybody.
>> Okay, we're going to wide receiver this
thing up, huh? and and I had a feeling
it would be a wide receiver. Two names
that I brought up earlier today the and
and you can go back and and talk about
it. The first one and I put them in my
mock draft yesterday is Ben Patterson,
the the UT perian basin wide receiver.
>> Dallas had an eye on him. They they
thought about maybe UDFA seventh round
pick as a guy that they wanted to look
at. The other one is a guy that I I
loved watching throughout the year uh
during my time covering the American
Conference and and calling some games
for ESPN. Anthony Smith is a ECU wide
receiver. East Carolina big play threat.
Those are the two guys that I would
throw out there. Who's the top of your
list? Uh, Zack Jordan Hudson did go from
SMU.
>> No,
>> not to my knowledge.
>> No, he's still available.
>> I would love Jordan Hudson from SMU.
That
>> was a 30 visit or a Dallas day guy,
right?
>> Him and Jeff Caldwell would be at the
top of my list for Cincinnati.
>> And Tyron Montgomery is an interesting
player from John Carroll. I mean, that's
a guy that showed, didn't he show up and
and just dominate the Senior Bowl? It
was tough to find tape on him, but I
mean, that's a guy if you don't want to
fight for for somebody maybe as a UDFA
that the league might also like, Ty
McGomery wouldn't be a bad option.
>> So, again, the final couple picks prior
to the Cowboys, Harold Perkins Jr., 215
to the Falcons out of LSU. Trace Mack,
the kicker from Florida, goes to the
Packers at 216. And then Jaden Williams,
offensive tackle out of Miss goes to the
Cardinals at 217. Cowboys pick is in on
the national broadcast. It's the final
pick of the day and of the draft for the
Cowboys who have already had a uh solid
week across the board uh as we await who
the uh the wide receiver could be
because we've got Junior Adams on the
phone line now talking to the newest
Dallas Cowboy.
Also remember, don't go anywhere when
this is over. We're gonna hear from the
the newest draft pick and we will also
get some secret audio and we'll get that
to you
>> as time.
>> By the way, if you've been hanging out
with us the whole time for the draft,
don't quit now. Stay with us to Mr.
Irrelevant, please.
>> I love it.
>> Make sure you do that.
>> We've done too much work for you to quit
now.
>> Yeah, don't quit now.
>> Yeah, we need the numbers. Thank you.
>> We love you.
>> Cowboys at 218. This was a pick that at
least at one point in time we thought
may not have belonged to them. There was
a report out there that they had traded
this pick on night one and then it kind
of got confused between the NFL came
back and and it is ending up as a pick
for the Cowboys. And there it is. Wide
receiver Anthony Smith, East Carolina
wide out, big body catcher, 6'2, 297, 44
speed and a big play threat. Nick, I I
told you about this guy a couple
weeks ago just because I thought as a a
mid- major group of five type of player,
I thought he belonged in the draft. I
thought he'd be maybe undrafted, but he
is the seventh round.
>> They didn't want to fight for him.
>> It's something about these East Carolina
Pirates that the Dallas Cowboys love all
of a sudden. Savone Revel and now
Anthony Smith in backtoback years. Good
point.
>> Uh yeah, uh this is just uh if you're
going to draft a receiver this late in
the draft, you want to draft for
physical traits that so he can at least
have special teams value on day one.
This guy will bring that. And then if
you also look at this roster right now,
Jaylen Tolbert is gone. There is a spot
to be had for that fifth wide receiver
and this is a perfect competition for
guys like Tawn Holden who a lot of
people loved at training camp last year,
fans and content creators and rightfully
so, but he didn't have the special teams
experience. And so you have Anthony
Smith here um who can come in and either
help elevate Tayan Holden or be the guy
to take that spot. And so I I like what
he brought from his days at ECU.
Granted, it's uh you know, a different
type of competition level. I do like the
American Conference and what they had
this last season and the contested
catch, the downfield threat, it is
certainly there. I would love to see if
he could figure out a way to carve a
role into the offense, but at the very
least, this is a pretty solid special
teams guy to have on day one. Last time
they went with an East Carolina wide
receiver, Dwayne Harris in the sixth
round.
>> Worked out pretty well. Harris had
Harris had a nice career.
>> When you look at what he did this year,
too, he took over in a couple of games
for uh for East Carolina. And he did so
in late late game situations. He almost
singlehandedly won the bowl game for
them without a quarterback at Pit or
against Pit. In that bowl game, they
didn't have their quarterback. They went
to a guy who actually is now going to
play for the University of North Texas
next year. Uh who transferred to. Uh but
their quarterback threw to Anthony
Smith. They gave it to him. He had a I
think it was like a buck 80 and two
touchdowns in that game. They they used
him well. They used him over the top and
he is a a big play threat. Vertical guy.
Can run routes. Uh they could use him in
the red zone. I'm I'm super happy for
this guy. Brian, I also pointed him out
to you at the Shrine Bowl. walked by as
a late ad. Yeah.
>> And I didn't even know he was on the
roster and I said that that's Anthony
Smith. This is who they they wanted to
go get. I'm glad they went and got this
guy. I've I've liked him all the way
through the college football season up
until this point. I think this is a
smart play. And I had a feeling wide
receiver was the case. Nobody told me
that. I just
>> had a thought process that wide receiver
is kind of an under the radar need. And
if you're going to fight for somebody in
undrafted free agency, Brian, a lot of
times those positions are premium.
>> No, absolutely. And you know and I just
that's you know when we look back at
this was probably one of the best
players on their board. I I was like I
was uh you know that's that when you're
looking you mentioned the traits you
mentioned the size the production the
possibility of being special teams guy.
These are all things you look for in
those wide receivers.
So that rounds out what is the Cowboys
draft class here in 2026. We're going to
step aside. We're going to continue to
wrap up the seventh round just getting
underway. Actually, corner TJ Hall just
went to the uh New Orleans Saints at 219
after the fact. Stick around. We're
going to hear from Anthony Smith. We're
going to hear the secret audio as well.
And we're going to run down the picks
for the Cowboys and what they did in
this year's 2026 NFL draft on the Dallas
Cowboys Radio Network and
DallasCowboys.com.
All right, welcome back in everybody.
Everybody updating their boards
currently?
>> Yeah, trying.
>> I think that's kind of the thought
process. I'm going to give you the exact
numbers on that that bowl game here for
you. Uh the the pit game. How about four
receptions, 156 yards?
>> Wow.
>> That's dominated.
>> That's 39 yards per catch by the way for
those. And he had two touchdowns in that
game
>> against UTSA. most of this in the fourth
quarter. Had eight receptions, 143 yards
and a touchdown. He had four receptions,
a buck 50 and two touchdowns against
Tulsa. And then against Coastal, he had
11 receptions for 136 and uh 12 yards
per car per catch in that one, too.
>> Older player is 24 um but 4440,
149, 10 yard split, 36 inch vertical,
10'3 inch broad jump. There's a lot of
good traits there.
>> Started at NC State,
>> then transferred. Yeah.
>> Four years there. He He was This is a
>> six-year guy.
>> This is a pandemic pandemic.
>> 24, didn't they just?
>> Yeah. 24.
>> Four years at NC State.
>> His freshman year was the pandemic
shortened year.
>> Um.
>> All right.
and then transferred after the 2023
season and started all 26 games for ECU
that he played in.
>> 13 touchdowns over the last two seasons.
Really productive. It's the deep ball
stuff with him that is really
intriguing.
>> It looks like he's got great hair. He
does have good hair.
>> Ask him about it.
>> I will.
>> Yeah, ask him about it.
>> Just a perk.
>> Oh, so you say he has great hair and
then you say my haircut isn't the
outfit.
>> Can you grow it out like he can, man? I
mean, he's shampoo and conditioner. I
think you might just be shampoo.
>> Brian has better hair than you, Kyle.
>> Oh, me?
>> Yeah, you do.
>> Thanks. It's fair.
>> If you saw him back in the day, I I
probably agree with you.
>> It's part of
>> back in the day.
>> Back in the day.
>> I'll take this. Still take this.
>> No. 1983. 1983. We were playing a game
against Mississippi State. We all
decided we're going to shave our heads.
Mine never came back.
>> Oh, no.
>> Mine was self-inflicted, believe it or
not.
>> That's terrible.
>> Yeah, it's it's what happened.
>> Sad.
>> Yep. It's what happened. You feel like
it's just going to pop back up and you
you make that decision.
>> You make the decision. We're all going
to do burr haircuts. We're going to
Starkville, Mississippi. Try and win a
game.
>> Yeah. Went there.
>> You got to listen. I think we might have
lost the game and then also lost my hair
in the same deal.
>> They weren't doing cowbells back then,
were they?
>> Oh, yeah. They've always cowbells have
always been a part of that place.
>> That's one of the coolest environments
I've ever called a game in. It was
really, really cool. You were going to
road trip with me that week, but the
Cowboys had a road game. They did,
>> remember? You were going to You were
going to We had I had to drive to that
game overnight because I had to come
back afterwards because the Cowboys
played the next day.
>> Part of it. That was the Denver weekend
and then they got shellacked
>> against Denver. That was That was a
tough one. All right. TJ Hall, corner
from Iowa, goes to the Saints at 219
220.
>> Did you?
>> Yep. I got
>> Tell me about him. Why not? Yeah, why
not?
>> You did the work.
>> Yep, exactly. Uh, had him in the sixth.
Uh, I didn't have a lot of notes
actually. Really technical but lacks the
top end speed to be a boundary corner in
the league. I like the special teams
value. Bad tape Vanderbilt. Good tape
UMass.
>> And when your good tape is UMass, I
don't know. Big Doug.
>> I like it. Bad tape Andy. Good tape
UMass.
>> He had a foot injury in 23 that ended
his season prematurely. Shoulder and
hand injuries in 25 for what it's worth.
But there you go.
>> There you go. Torio Pride Jr. Missouri.
>> I looked at him too. Can we do that?
>> Yep. Goes to the Bills at 220. Go for
>> have a lot of nose there.
>> Go.
>> Good film. He's got bad film.
>> I like the play. Ran a super fast time.
>> He is the second fastest defensive
player at the combine. Speed shows up on
the boundary. I think there's inside
flex here. Ball production could
translate to the NFL level. Uh I would
bank on athleticism and experience. Work
on the technical aspects and he'll be a
fun development project. I had him as my
top corner in the fifth round. So I like
the value here actually. Uh CB22 for me.
Um, yeah. No injury history. Cleaning
bill of health. Uh, Clemson transfer.
>> What else we got, Kyle?
>> I know. Waiting on the Bengals. Yeah,
we're good.
>> What else we got? Roger.
>> He's He's long gone. He's already back
on the flight back to New York. H, he he
pops out there for for something late,
doesn't he? Usually, Roger.
>> No, I think I think
>> Gunzo. He doesn't do Mr. Relevant.
>> No.
>> Oh, man.
>> Troy Vincent, I think, or something.
>> Okay. Yeah. Brock party
>> pick is in for Cincy at 221. So we're
taking Hey, look. We're taking a look at
Mr. Toriano Pride Jr.
>> Can't stump Chris Beam, man.
>> Hell no.
>> Should we play that game? Stump
>> him here in a minute.
>> Is Is that more possible or less
possible this year, Beam? How does that
look back there? I know. I know. College
football has been a little different on
how film is presented these days.
>> Yeah. Ah.
>> Oh, Bengals.
The Dallas Cowboys have made their final
selection of the 2026 NFL draft at pick
number 218. They take the wide receiver
out of East Carolina, Anthony Smith. He
is drafted to the Cowboys. The Saints at
219 take TJ Hall, corner from Iowa. The
Bills at 220 uh take Toriono Pride Jr.
the corner from Missouri. 221. The
Bengals take Jack Injuries, the tight
end from Texas and the Lion Lions are on
the clock at 2:22. Matt, did I correctly
hear that we have Anthony Smith on the
line? All right, we do have Anthony
Smith on the line. Anthony,
congratulations on this moment. I know
it's a proud day for you and your
family. Take us through uh what's going
through your head right now as you are
now a member of the Dallas Cowboys.
>> Yes, sir, man. Well, shoot. The first
thing I just want to give it to God,
man. And like without him, I wouldn't be
in this position, man. All the
struggles, all the all the trials and
tribulations I done went through in
college and my family and stuff. And
shoot, he brought me out on the other
side. So for me and my family, man, this
is this is an ecstatic moment, bro. I
can't lie. So I'm feeling good, man. My
fans feeling good. I'm just ready to get
down to Dallas and play some ball, man.
>> Anthony, you and I have actually talked
a couple times during my time covering
the American Conference, and I've been a
big fan of your game for quite some
time. And for those at the NFL level or
the Dallas Cowboys level that may not
know, tell them what they're getting in
Anthony Smith as a wide receiver at the
next level.
>> Shoot, I know they're getting somebody
who can take the top off the defense,
somebody who's fast, and somebody who
loves to compete, ready to work every
day. So, shoot, just as a receiver, man,
I'm ready to just go get it.
>> Hey, Anthony, congratulations. Walk me
through the emotions of the weekend. Did
you expect to be picked coming in and
then when you finally got the phone
call, just talk me through the relief
and the moment?
Yeah, man. So, shoot. I I mean, I did
have that faith, man, that I was going
to get picked this weekend. Just just
having that hope. Um, and then as the
weekend went off went on and stuff like
that, I just seen the rounds go on and
on and stuff like that. And, um, I still
kept that hope. My family still kept
that hope that I was going to get
drafted. Um, and then me and my agent
had talked and stuff like that. And, um,
we were kind of prepared to go the UDFA
route. And then, um, the Cowboys had
called me, man, and uh, walked
downstairs with my family and told them
who I was on the phone with and stuff.
And I got a lot of family who's Dallas
fans. So when they heard that I was on
the phone with you guys, ready to get
drafted, they were they were so excited,
man. So for me and my family, bro, it's
just like it's a crazy process. It's a
long process, but it it was all worth
it, bro. For sure.
>> And then you'll be reuniting with Savone
Revel Jr., uh, have you talked to Van
yet? Has he shot you a text?
>> He hasn't. He hasn't just yet, but me
and him talked the other day though,
man. We had him talk the other day just
about like um he being at the next
level, things to expect and stuff like
that and the work that you got to put
in. And um I mean he's been there for a
year, so he's been pouring into me
knowing that um this is my goal that I
want to get to the NFL and I want to
play in the NFL. Um so like him just
pouring into me and just letting me know
the things that I need to get right and
check off the box um so that I can make
those things happen. So that's that's my
good man's for sure. As you reflect back
at at your college journey and and going
from NC State to Eastern Carolina, it
seems like it kind of like you had to go
through maybe some struggles there at NC
State and then finally blossom there at
East Carolina. What really stood out to
you about that and kind of helped you to
become the receiver you are now?
>> Yeah, I mean for me, bro, is really just
maturity and intentionality, man. Um,
just just getting older, you know what
I'm saying? Learning how to how to
really play ball and how to really, you
know what I'm saying? the ins and outs
of the offense and stuff like that. And
then um the intentionality that every
day coming in coming in the building,
whether it's treatment, lift, um
conditioning, practice that I'm just
trying to attack it um shoot get 1%
better each day, man. Just attack it
head on. Um and just compete at
everything I do, man. So
>> you also seem to have an outstanding
hair game, Anthony. Uh what goes into
that?
>> Shoot, not much, honestly. I mean,
shoot. I I uh I cut my hair not too long
ago. I used to have it super super long,
but I I cut it short now, so a little
bit more manageable, easy to maintain.
So,
>> that's just natural talent. That's all
it is.
>> Yeah, man. Just natural, bro. Just
natural.
>> Hey, Anthony, congratulations. Not sure
how I can transition to a much better
question there. Um, but
you know, at at East Carolina, didn't
play special teams and receion
for you at the NFL level. How open are
you to that? And is that something that
in in whatever conversations you've had
with Dallas that they've discussed with
you?
>> Yeah, man. I mean, shoot, for me, bro,
my goal is to play in the NFL, not just
make it. So, whether I get to play at
receiver, scout team, running back,
returner, front line on kickoff, for me,
it don't really matter, man. I just want
to just help the team win and make an
impact um wherever I can. So, for me,
man, I'm open to any and everything,
bro.
>> Anthony, talk to me about uh what the
Cowboys are getting from you off the
field. What do you like to do in your
free time outside of football? What kind
of person are you?
>> Shoot. For me, man, I'm a real chill,
relaxed person, man. I got two dogs. So,
for me, that's that's where I spend most
of my time when I'm not um at the
facilities or when I'm not doing
football. I'm usually outside the dog
park or laid up with my pups, man. So
that's uh that's something that shoot
that that's they've been ride or die on
me, man, since the NC State days. So
yeah, man. They get all my time when I'm
not doing ball, man.
>> What kind of dogs are they?
>> I got a lab retriever hound mix and then
I got a great pair of knees.
>> Oo, that's a lot of food. That's a lot
of food, man. Hey, good thing you're
getting a contract, man.
Congratulations.
>> Hey, for real, though, bro. I appreciate
you, brother.
>> We We do have a a dog food sponsor, so
go ahead and just get on that.
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah, that may come in handy.
>> Yeah, just just keep keep that in mind
whenever you get here to Dallas. What
are their names?
>> Yeah.
>> Uh my my girl, her name is Pinto and
then my boy, his name is Prince. So, two
P names then.
>> Pinto Prince.
>> There you go. That's awesome. Prento
Pince and a pirate, Mr. Anthony Smith
joining us here. Anthony, thanks so
much, man. We're excited to to see you
here in Dallas. Safe travels and we'll
talk to you again next week.
Yes sir, man. I appreciate y'all so much
for getting on the call, man. See y'all
soon, bro.
>> Thanks, Anthony.
>> Shoot. He's a good interview, man.
>> I would have said his h his hobby is
shooting.
>> Oh man, I like to shoot,
>> dude. He down good interview. He's a
leader. Has a lot of energy. He was a
huge leader in that locker room. Not
surprised to hear from Savone Rebel and
what they wanted uh across the board.
So, uh, good stuff from the, uh, the
call after the fact here.
>> The Jones is going to go talk now.
>> Is that what we're doing?
>> Oh, they're about to do the press
conference.
>> How about that?
>> A little early. How about that?
>> That's good stuff. So, we'll kill some
time here for a little bit.
>> That's fine. You guys do what you got to
do.
>> But let you get in here, baby. Uh,
>> it's overtime, bro. You feel me?
>> Let's Let's run through a couple of
these uh these last few picks that
happened while we were on the phone. uh
or shortly before we we're talking to
Anthony Smith, the most recent pick for
the Dallas Cowboys.
>> Can I talk about Robert Spears Jennings
just really quick Steelers? That is that
is a Donovan Wilson clone. He plays in
the blocks, plays in the box, flies
downhill. Uh I think he could have some
turnaround ability at the next level. I
loved him though. Third round for me.
That's a great steal for the Steelers.
Y'all have a great weekend. Thanks for
watching.
>> Lovely.
>> You guys might have a chance to come
back. We don't we don't know, but if he
does, we'll see. Uh, all right. So, Jack
Injuries, tight end from Texas, goes to
the Bengals at 221. Tyer West,
>> yeah,
>> defensive tackle from Tennessee goes 222
to the Detroit Lions.
>> Uh, Aphan Calamanis,
>> what
that's I don't know if that's it. Yeah,
Ruters quarterback 223 and then Robert
Spears Jennings goes 224 to the
Steelers. Any one of those, Brian, that
you want to talk about specifically? Uh,
no. I think Nick Nick knocked out the uh
the Spears one. I think he's got that
one. Everybody else I'm kind of
>> I did like Andre.
>> Oh, Andrew. Go ahead. Talk to I could do
that one. I could do that one.
>> Yeah. Go ahead. Led the Golden Bears in
receptions and yards as a red shirt
sophomore and then transferring to
Texas. It just didn't really in terms of
as a receiving tight end, it just it
didn't work as well. But he's super
tough. He can take some big hits. He
gets up, excels in making contested
catches. I think he's a decent blocker.
I mean, I think he he works the wham
blocks, the pulls. Texas would run right
behind him with lead blocking. Yeah, he
tracks the ball well. Uh, body catcher
downfield. He does showcase strong,
consistent hands. I didn't see a lot of
drops from him. I think he's got some
sneaky suddenness after the catch. He'll
use his momentum and almost slingshot
himself uh for for extra yards. But to
me, like the route running could
improve. He's a solid all-around player.
Uh he destroyed Texas A&M. I thought one
that was one of the best games that I
watched. But uh he he kind of reminded
me a little bit like a a Fergusonesque
type player entries. So uh you know the
seam he can stretch the field. I thought
he'd be drafted much higher than this. I
had him in the fourth.
>> Uh I had him in the fourth as well. The
only tight end that I had
>> ranked above him that's still on the
board is Michael Trigg. That's the only
one uh that I had.
>> I that's I'm the same way. Trig
>> I actually had I actually had in that
round I had Trigg and Royer Klene and
now Bentley I know Vach brought up
Bentley's name that was fifth round and
then Klein
>> Michigan right Michigan
>> second round Michigan but yeah second
round pick there so that was kind of a a
wonky thing where we saw a couple of
guys uh go in that uh tight ends go in
that second round
>> I do want to get the name right because
he is a quarterback Kakmanis for Ruters
is how you say is
>> Kalak Manis and he's also before
>> he better not be good.
>> Why is that?
>> Nobody's going to want to say that name
over and over when he drops back.
>> I kind of like it. Calcanis sounds like
a fun thing.
>> I think you're already saying it
different than you did about 10 seconds
ago.
>> I think that's a third different way
you've said it now.
>> Is it?
>> I think I think it's slightly different
each time. That's what I'm saying.
>> Back to past. Kak Manis looks to us
right.
>> You know who you know who really got us
screwed up? Was it last year or two
years ago?
>> Uh when I had I and I still think it's
been messed up for me. Kingsley uh Sua
Mata.
>> Oh yeah.
>> And then Nick came in here and kept
saying Suamatia.
>> Yes.
>> Oh yeah.
>> And I was like and I eventually got
confused. I was like which one is it?
And it started screwing up and I forgot
how to say it.
>> I don't know if I could say it right
this second.
>> I think it's Sua Mata.
>> Sua Mata. Okay. Interesting. Uh Titans
take another tight end. Jiren Kak. Uh
>> Kak Knak.
>> Actually I think it's connect.
>> That's different.
>> Yeah. You said it differently there,
too. You know, uh, tight end goes to the
Titans there at 225 from Oklahoma. Brian
Brian's looking at Bobby like a like a
disappointed uncle.
>> What do you Are we going to kiss and
make up? Like, do we got bad blood
going?
>> We had bad hostility.
>> It's good. Bobby and I Bobby and I love
to yell at each other.
>> It's good. I enjoy it.
>> Is it good?
>> Yes.
>> All right. No.
>> I don't like it. I don't like it when
you guys fight.
Uh
>> I think yeah we we fight in the way we
we argue and debate but we like there's
no hostility.
>> Not at all.
>> There's never hostility with it. There's
hostility when I argue with you like
when I was arguing with you about
Stafford and Dak. That was
>> Yeah, which I was right about, but
that's not Can we find a uh There was
guy just won an MVP.
>> I was now I was writing a uh I was
talking with Vach out in the hallway. I
am writing uh an AI brought us R&B song
>> for uh Monday that I'm working on. And
the hook starts out, I'm trusting the
tape. Just trusting the tape. I know
he's 5'8, but GD, he's great.
>> I like it.
>> I know he's 5'8.
>> It's going to be Gag of the Day.
>> I know I'll be fine. I know I'll be
fine.
>> I'm ready.
>> He runs a 49.
>> Let's go.
>> And he just turned 25.
>> But Brian's got him in the second round.
>> I do, man. My board My board got him My
board reflects all those guys.
>> That tape against Bucknell was
fantastic.
I'm still trying to figure out what's
wrong with Llewellyn. I really am.
>> I don't know.
>> I really am.
>> That's crazy.
>> I'll tell you where. I've got a large a
large pocket of players. This is those
it's those um it's the it's the edges in
the fifth round. It's the Reagars.
>> Yeah.
>> Heldman.
>> We all
>> James Newberry, Kamar, Sap, Tucker.
>> Yeah.
>> Those are all guys. I mean, none of
those guys. Usually I usually get some
of those guys picked get picked off and
and that that group that group stayed
solid the whole day when with nobody
wanting these guys. Well, we we'll see.
We got some few more picks, but
>> and then in the defensive tackle group,
that one technique, the the Kennan from
Alabama.
>> Yeah.
>> Cleveland and Cordaloney.
>> I was going to say we all we all like
and respect Lance Zerine from NFL
Network, right?
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> So, I was just looking over Lance's
rankings and grades for everybody. I
think his two highest play graded
players left on the board are both
defensive tackles.
>> There you go. Uh let's go ahead and take
a break now because we want to beat the
uh the the punch for the press
conference that's coming up here in a
little bit. There are about 30 picks
remaining in this year's NFL draft, but
the Cowboys are done for the day. So,
they're about to take to the podium.
You're listening to the 2026 NFL draft
on the Dallas Cowboys radio network and
on dallascowboys.com.
>> Highest graded ones left were Xavian
Harris. That's his number one still on
the board. Xavian Harris from
Mississippi.
>> Yeah, see that was I I heard some really
some bad things about him. Is that
character or?
>> Yeah, like there's there's Yeah, it's I
I don't probably shouldn't go on there
with it, but
>> he's also got uh best available Dion
Burks, VJ Payne, Diego Pounds.
Uh Brandon Cleveland, defensive tackle
from NC State.
>> Deontay Lawson.
>> He pounds. Yeah,
>> Mason Rager.
>> Yeah, Rager was the medical that you
were talking just apparently a bad
medical. And then Garrett Nesmeer. Uh,
where would you draft Jason Robertson if
he was a football player in this draft
class? Because he just scored a goal for
the Dallas Stars.
>> Oh, that's pretty good. You know,
>> Robo's just been hot, rolling, baby.
>> He said, "Everybody's hating on my
playoff performances. I'm going to just
go ahead and prove everybody wrong,"
which I love.
>> I would have let him take Kenneth
Murray's spot last year
>> at the very least.
>> Oh, everything.
>> Nick Harris really liked Kenneth Murray,
though.
>> He did.
>> He's wrong. He really liked him
>> out of the draft or
>> no like when is that why he compared
Jacob Rodriguez to Kenneth Murray?
>> That's why he compared him.
>> That's what
>> he thought it was a really good Samborn
was another one that kind of
>> Oh man.
>> I mean and then you and then you trade
and you're like
>> you trade for what? Wilson.
>> Yeah, Logan Wilson.
>> I liked Wilson out of the draft. I will
be serious about that one. And now you
got D-winners. You do have D-winners. I
like Dwinners. Hopefully he
>> Yeah, if you look at basically this
hall, if you include Dwinners in this as
being that's what they got, I don't
think it's a bad hall at all to say
Caleb DS, Malachi Lawrence, Jan Barum,
Drew Shelton, Devin Moore, LT Overton,
Anthony Smith, and then throwing
Dwinners on it. I think that's a pretty
good setup.
>> You could also go further than that and
throw George Pickkins onto that that
>> Yeah.
>> third round pick there if you wanted to.
>> Right. I mean, there's there's a couple
different things you've done in this
draft class or with the picks that you
were given in this draft class that have
made you a better football team. And the
fact that you have Caleb DS just kind of
started off is is really just an
incredible
>> interesting. Drew Shelton was the only
pick the Cowboys made this year that was
theirs.
>> That is that's crazy because they traded
every single one was a traded pick or a
move around or something.
>> Archer.
>> No, I just was looking at the NFL.com
sheet. have arrows on all of the the
barum or on the Shelton one.
>> Tweet that out before Archer gets to it.
>> Oh, Landon. Hey, Vachi. Landon Robertson
went to uh the Bengals.
>> Let's go. There we go. Good for him.
Yeah.
>> I don't remember who all the Bengals
have taken today, but I feel like there
have been a couple times where I'm like,
"Oh, I like that guy."
>> Yeah. Let's pull up their draft.
>> Anybody want to talk about Mr. Robinson?
>> Yeah. Hang on a second. Let me let me do
some housekeeping here.
>> We done drafting. I'm watching film,
bro.
>> Who you watching film of?
>> I'm about to go in the 2027 draft. I'm
about to get back into LT Overson and
and attempt to see the fit here. I'm not
gonna change my grades on nobody, but I
am gonna consider the fit because that's
what we're uh that's what we do. You
know what I mean?
>> Okay, I see what you got.
>> Yeah, I liked the Connor Lou pick. Uh
Brian Parker the second. They took both
those guys. Cincinnati did. Andre and
Robinson. I thought those were good.
They didn't have a lot of picks. Yeah,
they they didn't have a first this year.
Now, the beginning of their draft was a
little the fact that they traded for
Dexter Lawrence and then it's I mean
Cash's House is good, but I think Cash
Cash's House is just not going to be on
the field all the time.
>> Yeah, it it it could be good, it could
not be good. I think Kobe Young is so
stiff as a wide receiver out of Georgia.
I wasn't my I wasn't a huge fan of his
um in terms of my grades there. I liked
Parker though, the Duke center. Yeah,
>> I liked him as a a mid-round pick for
Cincy. So,
>> I really I really hated Tampa Bay's
draft. That maybe that might be one of
the worst drafts of all time.
>> You think so?
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. So, you've got Bane there. Troder.
>> Yep.
>> Um
>> I mean, Keanti Scott and Ruben Bane just
kills that
>> that draft for me.
>> You just hate Miami guys, hate Florida.
What's going on there?
>> I mean, just I don't know. I don't know
how I'm supposed to use him. Short arm
guy, tweener guy.
>> Uh
>> mine's not going now. He's he's he's
gotten disciplined with my hard count.
>> Do we need ECU offensive tape, by the
way?
>> Uh yeah, we did. That would help.
>> Uh 227, Jackson Kuwatch, linebacker from
Miami.
>> I'm trying to I'm trying to get I'm
trying to get Robinson up for us here. I
Yeah,
>> listen. Cincinnati does some crazy ass
stuff sometimes, but man, they might
have they might have just
>> might have got him one right here with
this guy. I know he's
>> steal of the draft. Bobby's not gonna
like the fact he's a little small.
>> No. R.J. Ooa just texted me and said he
just showed me he tweeted that Drew
Shelton not two and A HALF YEARS AGO.
>> OH MAN.
>> NOW I FEEL LIKE a phony.
>> R.J.'s got it down man. So you or he had
already tweeted
>> the exact.
>> Shout out to you RJ.
>> Yeah.
>> Jeez. Part of
>> I know it's upsetting.
>> That was Walchuck getting me back. He
hacked my Twitter and made that
embarrassing tweet. It was
>> all right. So, there is the post-draft
press conference as we wrap things up
here on the DallasCowboys.com and the
Cowboys Now app side of things. Thanks
for sticking around with us all the way
through. We do have about 10 selections
remaining, a little bit more than 10
selections, more like 13 selections
remaining until we get to Mr.
Irrelevant. And yes, we will continue
all the way through to 257 in Mr.
Irrelevant and then we will say so long.
Uh if thanks for switching over if you
were listening on the radio side of
things on 1053 the fan and the Dallas
Cowboys radio network back with Bobby
Belt, Brian Bratis, Vot Lombardi, Zack
Walchuk, I'm Kyle Yman's. We've got
Chris Beam, Matt Kent in the back. Any
uh anything said there, Bobby, that
stood out to you in terms of uh what
Dallas wanted to do in day three and how
they kind of filled some of their needs?
>> Um I'll be completely honest, uh Kyle, I
had my headphones off and so I didn't uh
I didn't hear it. Uh, I did hear them.
Thought
>> you maybe picked up on one thing.
>> No, I heard them reference Mike
McCarthy. My ears kind of perked up when
that happened. Uh, I'm uh, my mom used
to say all the time if I didn't hear
her, she would say, "You should be in
tune to the sound of my voice." I'm in
tune to the sound of Mike McCarthy's
name. So, when I hear it, I go, "What?
What are they saying? What's going on?"
So, I'll turn around, look. But, um, no.
Uh, other than that, and then the, uh, I
guess shotty saying that his kid's
question is play calling. Uh, I didn't
hear much else.
>> That's okay. I thought maybe there was
one thing that we picked. Cole Wnooki.
>> I was I was playing Immaculate.
>> Oh man, that's a bummer.
>> Uh here are some of the picks that Brian
just alluded to one of them, but here
are some of the picks that we uh did see
during the press conference. Stop me if
you guys want to read a scouting report
or uh talk about any of those guys. What
was that?
>> Just keep
>> No, there's one guy I know you want to
talk about. Uh let's start with Baron
Morton, quarterback from Texas Tech.
goes to the Patriots to 234. 235 the
Vikings Gavin Gearhart uh interior
offensive lineman from Cincinnati.
Seahawks take Andre Fuller, the corner
from Toledo.
>> Not a bad player.
>> Yeah. Colts take Seth McGawan, the
running back from Kentucky. Dolphins
take Max Llewellyn. The slide finally
stops as Luwelling, edge rusher from
Iowa goes at 238.
>> Thought he was a really good pass
rusher, Kyle. I mean, you know, I I
don't know how he's going to project to
the league, but if he's a guy that, hey,
there's one dude out of the seventh
round that's going to show up and do
great, I would expect Max would be the
guy, especially amongst this group of
seventh rounders. So,
>> he's it's going to be a hard guy to cut.
>> That just you you're talking about a guy
that's
>> pass rush ready.
>> Pass rush ready. He's going to he's a
tryhard guy, but he's more than a I say
tryh hard guy, but he's got skills. He
just he doesn't have the physical the
you know the great testing numbers, but
he's a hard guy to to to uh to get
around or to block because he's always
he's coming at you. He's doing moves.
He's chasing the football. He lines up
wide. He can line up inside. There's a
hand down, stand up. You know, the
modern football, these guys make teams
and they're they contribute because they
do a lot of different things.
After Llewellyn, the Bills take Tommy
Dolman Jr. the punter from Florida. Was
that one, don't you, Zack?
>> Not on I don't think on him. That was
another one of the guys.
>> We might need to change two dozen kicker
and punter reports and you didn't have
the one that got drafted.
>> I got I had I had Brett Thorson from
Georgia and Jack Stonehouse from
Syracuse.
>> You know what you could have done? You
could have read those reports as Tommy
Dolman and we wouldn't have known.
>> We wouldn't even know. You could have
just been
>> I was going to say nothing to him. Yeah,
it's very true.
>> I would have been like that's that
sounds like a good report.
>> That's what's going to happen next year.
>> That's good work right there.
>> Next year he's going to do that and then
we're going to turn around and make you
show your work like we like they do in
great
>> I'm going to ask Chad GP to write a
Tommy D. I'll get it to you.
>> You get it here in a second.
>> Velocity.
>> Uh Jags at 240 take Parker Hughes the
linebacker from Middle Tennessee. Bills
at 241. Armaj Reed Adams interior
offensive lineman from Texas A&M. I I I
liked him out of the shrine go uh shrine
game. Uh talked to him a little bit. He
wants to be a broadcaster when he's
done. Uh so I I talked to him. I was
like, I'll I'll let you know uh once
you're done and let's hope it's 12 or 13
years down the line. Hey, we've got
punter B-roll. We got the punter.
>> We don't need your chat, GPT. We've got
Chris Beam. That's what we need. How
about that pun?
>> I got it if you're ready.
>> Yeah, go ahead and read.
>> Long limb specialist with adequate size
and a repeatable motion, though not
without mechanical variance. operates
from a traditional two-step approach
with a moderately quick get off,
generally in the 1.9 to 2.1 second
range. Ball contact can be inconsistent
at times, leading to fluctuations in
distance and hang time. When he strikes
it cleanly, he shows the ability to
drive the ball with solid trajectory and
functional hang. I don't like that ter.
>> That's crazy.
>> Functional hang.
>> I don't like that. He's got
>> that level of contact isn't consistent
enough yet to project immediate
reliability at the next level. Um, they
wrote way too much. I just told I said I
just said just write a scattering report
about a fake punter. And it literally
gave me like six paragraphs.
>> You need a a chat GPT summarization on
the chat GPT answer.
>> The mental makeup appears steady.
Doesn't seem rattled by pressure
situations, but the inconsistency
suggests confidence can waver when
mechanics slip. Needs to prove he can
string together clean, repeatable
outings rather than alternating between
high-end and below end.
>> You know what? Hey, I made this up. And
we not going to double check. No, we
didn't.
>> We just going to assume they right.
>> He could have he could have read
anybody.
>> Ask him what the hell is functional
hang. I I
>> What is functional hang?
>> Just tell him elaborate on
>> What was the first sentence again?
>> I don't know what that is.
>> Uh the very first sentence of the
report. Yeah. Long limbmed specialist.
>> So you put that with functional hang and
I don't know if I'm okay with it.
>> Um I'm going to ask him say what the f
>> that is awkward.
>> No, no, no. Don't even say what the f
okay.
>> Just be inquisitive.
>> Okay.
>> Interrogative. What is functional? Hey.
>> Botch wants to know. Don't don't mention
my name.
>> Functional hang is I'm not going to be
the one responsible for writing that.
>> Don't mention my name. This your phone.
>> Functional hang is football
shortorthhand, not a formal metric. It
means hang time that actually does its
job. Okay. What?
>> Uh not just a stop off number.
>> If somebody if somebody like in the
scouting department hears us talking
about functional hang,
>> guys. I swear. Yeah, we did not write
this.
>> I don't know. We're going to get in.
We're going to get in trouble.
>> How about Florida, though? They get the
kicker and the punter.
>> Yeah. Yeah,
>> they must have had the best special
teams in in the league. They hit it a
lot.
>> That's true.
>> Yeah,
>> they did punt a lot. All right, Jags.
Jags at 240 take Parker Hughes,
linebacker from Middle Tennessee. I
mentioned him and Armag Reed Adams
skipping down. 242, the Seahawks take
Devin Eastern, the interior defensive
lineman from Minnesota. 243, the Texans
take Aiden Fischer, linebacker from
Indiana. It's a good player to go this
late.
>> It is, man. He's just uh he's
undersized, but he was a tackling
machine. He can blitz. He's got a good
feel for zone coverage. He can get
swallowed up by linemen, though. He'll
struggle to fight off blocks. I mean,
this is a guy that, you know, that's
that's the size. He's just tiny, but he
can shoot gaps. You'll see him get stuck
fighting through trash, change
direction. You know, he's going to
contribute on special teams, but uh he
really was kind of the heartbeat of the
middle of that Indiana defense. Just
tiny.
>> Uh the Eagles with a good pick at 244. I
really like uh uh Cole Wisnooki. He
visited a lot of teams on 30 visits is
what he did. And he's a transfer from
North Dakota State. He was a linebacker
with the Bisons before he moved to
safety.
>> He lines up in several different spots
as an as absolute best when he could
play going forward. Put him near the
ball and the best chance for success.
It's not to say he can't play with range
because he can. Uh he does really nice
job of getting to the ball. You see, he
sees it well. He's able to read screens
on the outside quickly. He's not going
to get fooled or put in difficult spots.
He looks like a relaxed pedal, but lacks
really quick feet to explode. Uh going
to have to get he's going to have to
gather himself then come forward. But
he's a sure tackler. He plays well in
space. He's not a hyped up name or a
headline grabber like Caleb DS. But he's
kind of the here we are with this word
functional piece that quietly changes
how the defense oper operates. So he's
kind of a guy that they use him for
blitzing. They use him around the line.
They use him back. Uh he's a he's a he's
a good player for for the seventh round.
Uh you got a guy that's uh it's a that
plays plays a very very high level.
>> So we got functional hang and functional
piece.
>> There you go.
>> There you go. Uh and by the way,
Wishnooi went on a lot of those 30
visits because he does have medical.
>> Ah Wishnooki
>> medical. Yeah. Philadelphia though with
the pick there.
>> He he didn't play all of 2024.
Like the whole season he didn't play.
>> Yeah. uh and he that was his last year
at North Dakota State and he was the
highest rated PFF safety in college
football in 2023. Was an all-American at
the FCS level, took the the year off
because of the injury, then trans
transfers to Texas Tech, played on that
defense, but he got lost in the shuffle,
not because he played poorly, but
because there were other guys on that
team and and so I I think that's a
tremendous late round pick by the
Eagles, as much as I hate to say it.
>> Uh Bobby, we got a question from uh
Twitter. appreciate you guys for tapping
in. Was Mike Mike Crumb asked, "How does
a punter's functional hang uh like how
does it work in cold weather?"
>> Okay.
>> Like, does it
>> You keep reading the pics. I'll find
I'll get the answer.
>> I got three more to get through.
>> Can you maintain functional hang in cold
weather?
>> That would be the name of my album.
>> Assuming Assuming in in outdoor
stadiums, I would say.
>> Yeah. Uh 245.
>> Yeah. The Patriots
245 the Patriots take Jam Miller the
running back from Alabama. 246 the
Broncos
>> Jam Miller.
>> Hey, he's a good player.
>> Hey, he's not bad.
>> Uh 246 Broncos take my Scott, the safety
from Illinois. 247 the Patriots take
Donovan Ezra's once teammate. Quintavius
Hutchkins, the edge rusher from Boston
College. And then Carson Ryan, the tight
end from BYU, just went to the Browns at
248. Now we're all caught up and
>> are we all are we all going to pick a
Mr. Relevant projection like we've done?
>> Sure.
>> I'm going to say Mason Raer.
>> The Broncos.
>> I knew you were going to do it.
>> I was going to gohead.
>> It hasn't been on Twitter yet, right?
>> No, they're still like 10 things away.
>> Uh, by the way, it says that functional
hang in cold weather matters a lot. And
yes, it's legitimately harder to
maintain.
>> That's what it says.
>> Oh, it does. You know,
>> you a lot.
>> I look right there. And that cold
weather impacts the hang.
>> So if you
>> and spin pop off the foot.
>> Yeah, that's true.
>> So the Bears play indoors, outdoors.
>> Outdoors.
>> Hey man, you a punter in Chicago. It get
cold out there in December.
>> Who has the last pick? By the way,
>> the Broncos.
>> The Broncos have the last two.
>> They have the last two. Yeah.
>> Says cold air is denser and so it
reduces.
>> You think Shawn Peyton would just take
Nus?
>> I think so. That's who I would pick.
>> Yeah,
>> I was good. Yeah, I was thinking NUS or
text and ask him. I don't think he'd
answer but
>> hold on I gotta look through some
>> I think I think he might you know what I
think he might like his dad you know in
that same
>> his hip snap is also affected
>> I'm going to pick Nes Mr. for the for
the Broncos. Did they do something a
quarterback rate or did they sign?
>> No, they haven't.
>> They don't even have a starter right
now.
>> Well,
>> oh no,
>> I'm not going to argue.
>> I would say Nesmire for the for
>> That's a good pick.
>> I like it.
>> I'm thinking quarterback, too. And I'm
going to say Saw Robertson out of
Baylor.
>> Okay.
>> I'm thinking the same kind of thing you
are. They they need some depth at
quarterback there. And Saw Robertson's
cousin is Jared Stitdom,
>> which would be interesting. They're
saying Dline, tight end, cornerback,
linebacker, O line.
>> Here is uh we've got a pick. We're back.
Yeah. 247. The Chiefs
on the clock
>> with the 249th pick in the 2026 NFL
draft. The Kansas City Chiefs select
Garrett Nusme.
>> Oh, that's perfect for a good spot.
Andy,
>> hey, that's your course for the weekend,
Brian. You say it and it just pops up
like that.
>> That's
>> That's perfect for Nuts. You're going to
wait.
>> What a long journey, man. Great team to
go to, by the way.
>> Absolutely.
>> He is uh
he I mean I I'm super biased. I watched
him, but Marcus, I think he's special.
He was around this football team for a
number of years. Um I I think I think
it's if there's things that knock them
down the board, fine. But if you just
want to talk about pure like playing
ability, like what they showed on tape
during their college career or whatever
and and how they project out, I thought
he was the second best one that I saw
this year.
>> 24 tape when he kind of pushed the ball
down the field a little more, a lot
more.
>> There's some Romo to him when you watch
him.
>> A lot more confident, tight windows, and
the competition, well, the not the
competition, but his uh his uh cast of
help was a lot better last year than it
was this year, too.
>> Yeah, it was. And I think the
coordinator made a difference.
>> Yeah. Shouts out to Les, man. Good.
>> He I mean, he can sling it. He makes
some throws and I'm like, "Wow."
>> He threw for 300 yards on the road
against USC, battled his ass off, and
then at the end of the day, the head
coach said, "Our quarterback didn't do
enough."
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I mean, he's super tough.
>> He played hurt.
>> He was hurt all year.
>> I like him. I mean, I'm stunned that he
lasted to the seventh round. I guess the
interviewing wasn't great, but he's got
a lot of NFL qualities about him. It's
hard to believe that the a guy who's
grew up around football, you know, his
dad's a coach and all that stuff like
that and been a lot of places his dad
that he would interview bad.
>> I think that's probably why it dropped
him so much because a lot of people were
like, whoa, this is not what we're
>> probably stood out more than
>> Yeah, I think was he a pain in the ass
in interviews? I mean, can someone tell
I mean I'm asking a lot of questions.
>> Like it was just kind of generalized
that it's just like it sounded like just
teams were not happy with some of the
answers that he gave. And
>> was he just honest and there were
questions that
>> he's not he's not blaming himself for
the stuff problems or
>> no like like just has a little bit of
like an attitude about it and like maybe
didn't uh didn't like like there was a
little bit of like a question of like
were you putting in all the work you
needed to your senior year?
>> Okay. And maybe didn't have the right
answer to it.
>> Yeah. And I think that's the thing is
just didn't didn't have good answers to
to explain that away. It's just I I mean
it was
>> it's a bummer he lasted this long. The
fact if he gets to sit behind Patrick
Mahomes and learn with Andy Reid then
that's probably good for him.
>> The Ravens just took Raan Benny the
defensive tackle out of Michigan.
>> I liked Benny quite a bit. I think I had
Rachan Benny actually in the fourth
round.
>> Wow.
>> So the Ravens uh Ravens going to Raven.
>> Yes they are.
>> And that's another guy that's got a lot
of versatility. Uh he can play up and
down the line of scrimmage. I get it.
Like we don't really love the Michigan
defensive lineman uh in Dallas
sometimes. I think Barnum's going to go
ahead and change that. But I liked Raan
Betty. I mean, I thought that this was a
guy that certainly had some versatility.
Uh he has some quickness to him. He's
got some power to his game. Difficult to
move off the line of scrimmage. He can
scrape down line. I like
>> functional hang.
>> Yeah, he's got some functional hang. He
does.
>> Are you getting choked up about all
this?
>> I'm getting
>> Sounds like it.
>> Went to Baltimore at 250. And he goes to
Baltimore. Unbelievable. They got a pick
again in a couple selections. It's the
Eagles, Eagles, Ravens. Back.
>> Yeah, it went Ravens, Eagles, Eagles,
Ravens, Colts, Seahawks, Broncos,
Broncos. It's some double dipping here
at the end.
>> Is what's the thought process behind
that? Oh, look. There's Nus Meyer
getting the call. That's cool. With with
Doug to his right uh on the screen. I'm
happy for them that he he did get a name
called because I know that like you
said, if that's the thought process and
that's the reason that there was a bit
of a drop, that's a tough moment for
him.
>> He's a uh yeah, I mean, look, I think I
think there was some sense too of just
like maybe lost his way a little bit in
a tough situation in LSU and and just
get
>> that coach was no help to him.
>> That coach is
>> that coach is I'm so glad he's gone.
>> There there's plenty of people around
college football and around the NFL who
will tell you lots of bad things about
that guy. So,
about Brian Kelly.
>> I'll take that too.
>> That was the moment that it went south.
>> Uh 251 pick is in for the Eagles went
south. That was like the first
appearance.
>> Exactly.
>> That's the thought over before it
started. Uh Eagles have their pick in. I
was just about to ask, what's the
thought process if you want to double
dip late in the seventh round? Just is
it
>> like backto-back picks at the end?
>> It's the same thought as Dallas. Hey,
let's take a guy that we don't want to
fight for later. And all these teams
right now are loving this times, right?
>> They're all loving this because they
don't have to. They could just take the
best two players off their board and
then now go fight the rest in free
agency, you know? I mean, Kansas City,
they were probably going to think about
they need maybe a quarterback we want to
bring in and who's our best one, you
know, Nesmire. Let's let's, you know,
let's go get him. So, they don't have to
battle. Now, I mean, Nusar was probably
sitting there thinking that I'm going to
have to make a determination in, you
know, for free agency where I want to
go, you know, and now he's he's got a
team locked in. So, nothing wrong with
that. The Eagles, like I say, the Eagles
got a couple back-to-back picks here.
That's a couple of guys that, you know,
Ravens, I mean, it's it's a good it's
good to have these picks like this late
in the seventh round so you don't have
to fight.
Here's the Eagles pick at 251 as they
walk out onto the stage for this one.
>> Archer, by the way, tweeted in the press
conference that I missed. Uh,
>> you are now witnessing history being
made.
>> All right.
With the 251st
pick in the 2026 NFL draft, the
Philadelphia Eagles select UA BERNARD.
>> YOU were so right.
>> Defensive tackle INTERNATIONAL PATHWAY
PROGRAM. LET'S GO.
>> So that one is an international pathway
program honore. He did not play college
football, but he's big dude.
>> Yeah. 6'4 and change and 308 pounds.
>> Eagles have had some success with those
international pathway selections.
>> Sure have.
>> Might as well take a flyer on him.
>> That's what they're going to do in the
seventh. And they get another pick right
this second. So,
>> played school and club basketball until
he was 19 years old. I'm just reading
what they have on the the lower third.
>> Was he the guy that was on We kept
seeing him on Twitter like he was the
workout guy and stuff like that. All
right. Mhm. Yeah. He's like he's a
defensive tackle and that's his build.
>> Okay.
>> That dude is jacked.
>> Yeah, he's massive. My
>> He's a He looks like a bodybuilder.
>> That guy was at Baylor back in the day.
>> Uh Sean Oakman. Sean.
>> He was He was
>> Whatever um Whatever happens to
>> I don't know anything about Bernard.
>> Yeah,
>> I I know. I can say in my scouting
report he's a better person than Sean
Oakman.
>> Bobby, what Bobby? Whatever happened to
the last cat that was like that? Oakman.
No, he ended up in jail, I think.
>> No, no, no, no, no.
>> Hey, he was exonerated. He was a
>> He was a playing Arena Football League
right now. Guy in the
>> No, he was um
>> looking now.
>> He was a uh he was a O lineman two years
ago
>> from Canada or something and he just had
some random work.
>> Oh, he was the uh the university.
>> Yeah. Manu Manu Manu. Yep. Yep.
>> What happened to him? Did that work out?
>> He got picked somewhere. I I haven't
seen him anywhere.
Yeah, he was a long time ago, wasn't it?
He played for like University of
Manitoba or something,
>> something crazy like that. It's always
like these these workout videos that
come out every now and then, and I I got
into some Twitter flushes.
>> He is
>> cuz I just asked if uh this cat right
here has some film out and apparently he
didn't, but he's a freak athlete and a
you know, incredible looking human being
or whatever. So, I guess that's part of
the the uh projection I guess. But
>> he went in the fourth round of the Lions
and I guess he's still on the roster,
but he hasn't really played.
>> Okay. So, I mean, we'll see. We'll see.
>> Yeah, he was monster. I did not
remember. He was 6'8, 352 with 35 inch
arms and 10 and a half inch hands.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> I remember seeing him walk on the field
at one point when we were when the Lions
were in town and I just remember
thinking, I've never seen anybody bigger
than that guy.
>> So, Brian, you was mentioning earlier
and if it's if like if it's Illuminati,
you ain't you a you you don't have to
say nothing. Is this the Eagles choice
that they wanted this guy or that
somebody tapped him on the shoulder and
said, "Hey,
>> I think the league asked these guys to
do this."
>> Maybe they got backtoback picks right
here.
>> Yeah, they they they Hey, Philly, would
you mind?
>> And this is trying to build football
nationally.
>> And that's kind of why he's in the draft
room.
>> I remember like there was a guy at
Germany that there was a wide receiver a
couple years ago.
>> Zimmer and Zimmer. They asked Zimmer and
them to pick him
>> is what they did. Yeah.
>> Okay. that dude that they
>> Oh, that looked like it was a rehearsed
clap with Howie in the the war room that
they're showing up there. I looked
>> He it looked like they were like, "All
right, 3 2 1
>> All right, guys.
>> The the beast has
>> like his his info like
>> the the the numbers here are ridicul if
he's six 30 and he ran 46340.
That's ridiculous.
>> 39 in vertical, 1010 broad jump,
>> 459 short shuttle. That's crazy. 8133
cone 31 bench presses.
>> He need to go to the UFC with some.
>> I mean that's just I mean that's
somebody that's somebody
>> see what's going to happen. I mean he's
going to end up like
>> you can stash him for like years.
>> Yeah. Who was the guy the offensive the
the talent
>> Isaac? Yeah. He Yeah. He played what he
was here like four years.
>> Yeah. Yeah. He's in San Francisco. Yeah.
I think you're right.
>> Drew Shelton's got him in the
>> end. Isaac ended up playing nose or
something.
>> You're right.
>> There's no worries. Drew Shelton.
>> Drew Shelton can handle him. He'll be
fine.
>> Preseason.
>> Yeah, he was with the Cowboys for four
years without I don't I don't think he
ever made the active roster. Never.
>> He just was able to sit on the P. I
mean, it's a good You should take
advantage of it if you have it.
>> It's incredible. It's an It's a roster
exemption. It gives a pathway for
international players to try and make it
to the league and some of them do. Some
of them have great careers out of it.
>> Wasn't Milada? Milada was that, wasn't
he?
>> Was he?
>> I think he was international pathway.
>> Yes. Chris Beam is saying yes. Uh they
did take a second edge right right after
that. Keshan James Newbie out of New
Mexico.
>> Okay.
>> So back-to-back picks for the Eagles.
They go with UR Bernard interior
defensive lineman through the
international pathway program. Then
Keshan James Newbie, the edge rusher out
of New Mexico. It's the Ravens, Colts,
Seahawks, Broncos, Broncos in the final
five selections of this year's draft.
Zack, did you give a guess for your Mr.
Irrelevant? Uh okay. So, since Nus is
gone, let's go with another quarterback.
I'll throw out uh how about Haynes King
from Georgia Tech.
>> That's a good one.
>> Brian, do you want to take a stab at it?
>> I'll do I'll be I'll go live.
>> What kind of players does Shawn Payeyton
like? Like, does he like like freak
athletes? Does he like mental
processors? Like, what's his his big
focus?
>> I think Shawn really likes
>> he liked Taesm Hill. So,
>> I think he likes guys you can use at a
lot of different positions.
>> Who's a Yeah. Who's a Till guy that's
left?
>> Um Jaylen Daniels.
>> Green's gone.
>> Sawyer Robertson.
I mean, Michael Trigg, I don't think
would be a bad pick for them.
>> Is Dan
>> I tell you what, I'll tell you what. How
about No, no. I think the pick of I I
think Hannes King is a really good one
for him because you know he'll do Hannes
King runs the ball. Like Hannes King,
you snap it to him and they run it like
18 times with him.
>> Yeah, he'll run. He's got that old
school throwing motion. He does.
>> Hannes King is Hannes King's because
he'll use him like he used Taesm Hill.
He'll use him as a running back. He'll
use throwing the I mean he'll he's a
tough kid, man.
>> He's a really tough kid. So yeah, I I
would I would say Hannes King has a good
shot here to getting this one done.
>> He's an East Texas legend. He brought a
championship to Long View for the first
time in a long time. Zach and I were on
the sidelines for that game. What a
special day. It was wild. 70K, wasn't
it?
>> Yeah, they sold it out.
>> I never I'd never seen that. like it was
up to the top tier.
>> It was unbelievable. But for
>> like the entire city of Long View came
out.
>> The air is crisp. Uh we got four picks
left. Will Pave go?
>> No,
>> I don't think so either.
>> Yeah, I Yeah, I doubt it.
>> If you're if you're already not taking a
guy,
>> why would you why would you subject
yourself to that in the final five
selections?
>> Looks like the Cowboys were kind of
eyeing possibly Cole Wiznooki's UDFA. Of
>> course they were. The the beats kind of
circling like, oh man, Will and Steven
were looking like ah darn it. So Archer
said that uh
>> Steven had said 10 to 12 players in UDFA
as their target.
>> Okay, there we go. Evan Beeren,
>> uh the guard from Northwestern just
went.
>> Oh, that's the Ravens.
>> The old books about the Bear family.
>> The Bernstein.
>> Oh,
>> that's the Mandela. Everybody hates you.
>> Damn it.
>> What?
>> Missed it.
the Maronstein Bears.
>> That James Newberry, by the way, he was
uh it was my they was in that pocket of
guys and finally one of the guys they
got picked. Those guys I had like there
in the fifth round
>> with the 254th pick in the 2026.
The Indianapolis Colts select Deion
Burks, wide receiver, Oklahoma.
>> Wow. At 254, Dion Burks, who Daniel
Jeremiah had as his last top 100 player
on the board.
>> Uh, wide receiver out of Oklahoma, goes
to the Colts here. Purdue transfer,
explosive, twitchy, has a lot of burst
and acceleration. He didn't make an
incredible sideline snag. You might see
it coming up against Alabama in the
playoff game. He's just he's he is
somewhat of a of a gadget type player.
He'll be a body catcher, Brian. I think
he's got great special teams value. He
he definitely has home run hitting
ability, but it's just a little bit
inconsistent, which is probably why he's
fallen to to this point. But hey, Deion
Burks
>> for Indianapolis here. I mean, he
definitely is a fun player.
>> I had him in the fourth round
>> is where I had him. I think I think I
think you got him right. I think you got
him right.
>> Yeah, he was up there for a lot of
people. And they took they were also uh
the team that took Seth McGawan, the
running back out of Kentucky in the last
round, too.
>> And Curry late. A couple good picks by
the Colts on day three. Late day three
at that. Uh
>> and Curry or And Curry?
>> And Curry.
>> Oh, I think A and D. Yeah,
>> they're talking about the Today Show.
>> Uh no, the Seahawks just took Michael
Dansby, Arizona corner, 5'11 and
Carlos's brother.
>> I think Arizona's entire secondary got
drafted.
>> Yeah, for real. Three safeties, two
corners.
>> I don't know if that's Carlos's brother,
by the way.
>> Okay.
>> I don't know how many Danes there are
playing in the NFL.
>> Yeah, maybe. I don't know. Uh, if you
want to talk about loyalty, you want to
talk about grit and the uh the ability
to finish, how about Nick Harris, who
just walked back in here after going to
the press conference and
>> put back on an opportunity. Can we turn
on this side mic here, Chris Beam? Is it
possible to turn that on?
>> Oh, it's on. It's on. Beautiful. Uh,
dude,
>> so are we doing Mr. Relevant
predictions?
>> Yeah, go for it. Yeah. Yep.
>> Campbell, Arkansas.
>> Campbell. I like it.
>> Why not?
>> That's That's interesting. What did you
think of the the pressure?
>> Uh basic, you know, nothing insane. Um
he he Brian Shottenheimr was tested a
little bit on Drew Shelton potentially
left tackle. He didn't give a whole lot
though, but
>> okay.
>> Um I think it's probably a situation he
wants to get Shelton in the building
first. But
>> yeah,
>> man,
>> if it were me, I'd be very open about
Yeah, Tyler Gayton, you're on watch. But
we'll see.
>> I think that would be a lie.
>> You think it would be a lie?
>> Yeah. for him.
>> I don't think so.
>> Moss, the running back from&M, hadn't
been selected, right?
>> No,
>> I'm gonna pick my I'm gonna pick Moss.
And I And I I don't have anything on my
phone or anything like that.
>> The pick hasn't been made yet. No,
you're fine.
>> Okay. So, I'm going to say I'm going to
say he's going to take the Texas A&M
kid. Moss, the running back.
>> Okay.
>> Vot, did you make a pick?
>> Hell no, man. Uh
>> yo, man, Robin Henry get drafted yet?
>> No.
>> Hey, man. Hey, man.
>> That'd be awesome. I'm here for it. I'm
here for it.
>> Robin Hair,
>> that'd be fun. Either either that or
he's a undrafted free agent, then I'm
here for it, too.
>> It better not be damn D pounds.
>> Dude, if D pounds is the Mr. irrelevant,
that would be a fun Speaking of D
pounds, how do y'all think Vables?
>> Functional hang. Ever heard of that?
>> That's a good question. I wonder how the
counseling
>> functional hang.
>> We we asked the chat GPT to write a
scouting report on a punter who was
picked and it kicked out and it said can
deal with functional hang.
>> It was what Bobby had when Nusmeer
finally got picked. Hey,
>> it was good. It was
>> Well done, sir.
>> That's That's more than fun.
>> That's quick.
>> I'll be here all week. No, really. Three
picks.
>> Oh, man. That was good. Quick stuff. Uh
Michael Danby, like we said, that was
corner to the uh
>> 255th
>> Victorian overall Seahawks.
>> Would it just be a total D move though
for the Broncos? Just like let's run out
the entire clock on this last game on
both of them. Yeah, just like just cuz
>> just to keep everybody around for a
little bit longer.
>> There's 250 left on this. They should
have just said both picks back to back.
>> There are 31 teams that have already had
their press conferences that are just
hanging out that are getting their their
final drinks after a long weekend.
They're getting their Miller Lights, the
only beer, the Dallas Cowboys, all those
things, you know. Got that read in right
at the last second.
>> Good stuff.
>> Uh Pittsburgh, the It looks like the
crowd is thinned out heavily.
>> What if we got a trade?
You can't trade Mr. irrelevant, but you
can trade the the penultimate.
>> Just real quick, just boop some trade.
>> Cowboys trade back up.
>> Sure, you can trade Mr. Bobby. You're
you're kind of a technologist.
>> Have they made these guys hold the mics
for seven hours today?
>> No. So, I mean, they will hold them, but
they'll I mean, they just set them down
and then pick them back up.
>> Remember, they don't stream like we do
non-stop where we don't have any
commercial breaks.
>> Bruce, let me ask you a question. If you
were a GM and you got the last pick,
>> Yeah. Can you call a prospect and be
like, "Hey, is anybody trying to give
you big money to be an undrafted dude?"
Like, if your demand is so high as an
undrafted guy, I draft you now.
>> I'll tell you what, if I had a problem
with the time,
>> Sure. If I had a problem that I knew
that I was going to have to pay somebody
big time
>> and I didn't want to do it, I'd draft
him right now.
>> For example, like if it's two players,
can you call and be like, "Hey, do you
have a lot of demand?"
>> One has a lot and another Absolutely.
Absolutely. Absolutely. Yeah. Okay. So,
for clarification, the rule is not about
trading, it's about passing. You can't
pass on your turn to deliberately
receive the the last pick. So, in this
spot where it's 256, if a team were to
sit there and say, you know what, we
don't really want to go now. And then
they don't turn on turn in the card,
they can wait and be passed up and then
they would be Mr. Irelevant. That's
where there's a rule. It's not trading
it. So,
>> wait. So, so like yeah, if you're like
what happen? So if the if they just
decide we're going to let the clock run
out by the way.
>> It should it should go to the Raiders.
>> Then what happens then?
>> Then it would it you would just lose the
pick. Then it would go to Mr. Revel. You
would lose the pick.
>> Bentley's not a that's a sneaky good one
there.
>> Yeah. Don Bentley tight end from Utah.
>> I think Cowboys would have been checking
him out in uh
>> unrafting like that.
>> That's a bummer for for
>> Utah, right? Yeah.
>> Yes, sir.
Trigg is the only guy of that fifth
round group now that has not been
>> there were some Baylor people
>> and you guys alerted me earlier that
Trigg's stuff off the field
>> I had just heard some like you didn't
really you don't want anything to do
with him but I think he's a really good
player at least as a receiving tight end
>> yeah that's
>> maybe it's not you know
>> the fact that Sawyer Robertson didn't go
either
>> Robert and
That would be interesting.
>> Bishop Fitz. No, I'm just talking names
that are left. Bishop Fitzgerald. J Mike
J. Michael Sturdivan out of Florida
who's a local guy. So it would make
sense maybe for the Cowboys.
>> Uh Raer.
>> Did York and Murdoch get drafted?
>> No. York hasn't gone and Murdoch hasn't
gone.
>> Dante Corleó from Utah.
>> You have to draft a Corleó.
>> Yeah.
>> Kolone.
>> Coron. Roman Hembi.
>> So the pick is in for Denver. That means
that means this draft this lady's going
to come up and tell us the history of
Long Beach.
>> Exactly. This pick is uh the final one.
That means the draft is in the books
officially. So can you start right this
second now that the pick is in or do you
have to wait for Mr. Irelevant to be
announced?
>> It's a good question. I don't know like
I mean they obviously are doing their
recruiting before then but in terms of
like officially putting pen to paper I
don't know if they can do it once the
pick is in or if it has to be announced
first.
>> Yeah. When the le when it's over then
you get to start doing this. You get
Well, you're you're probably talking to
the dudes,
>> right? But like pen to paper right now
pick is in. You can't do it yet. Okay.
>> So they have to announce it first.
>> Yeah, they do.
>> They should send Mark Griffin out there
to read this.
>> Brian on
Jeremiah's board. Brian, he had Heldman,
our guy from uh Central Michigan as his
140th guy and Lucas from USC is like 189
for him.
>> Wow.
>> That's
>> We had We had We had We had Lucas up,
but we had helmet up there, too. I had I
had Lucas in the third and I had uh
Heldman.
He must be down to my others.
>> See, I think that Lucas thing I don't
think people remember him like playing
as a standup guy but not really having
any burst or any speed.
>> He was a bigger dude that just happened
stand up.
>> Yeah. Remember but we did him early.
Yeah.
>> We we studied him early.
>> Yeah.
>> And then he just kept going down the
board. He just kept there more people
the more you studied the more you put
him down the board.
>> Yeah. I don't understand. I remember
talking to somebody about Lucas and they
were like
very impressive. Uh he has zero
instincts. Yeah. He's gonna have to
learn how to play.
>> Just not a lot of production.
>> But a but a damn punter's off the board
now. You know, he was just a UD
>> because of his uh immaculate what or
what was it?
>> I don't even want to say it no more.
>> Yeah. I don't know.
>> All right. Here's the Broncos Mr.
Irelevant and the history behind the
pick. It'll take a minute, but here is
the final pick of the 2026 NFL draft.
>> My dad actually played for the
Pittsburgh Steelers, so we uh
>> Of course he did.
He was irrelevant.
>> With the 257th pick in the 2026 NFL
draft, the 51st Mr. Irrelevant,
drafted by the Denver Broncos, the 257th
pick is Red Murdoch.
>> Red Murdoch.
>> Hell yeah.
>> Can we get a report on Mr.
>> Let's break him down.
>> Let's break him down. Damn it. Go ahead.
Go ahead. We'll check. You got him.
>> Yeah. We we you whoever. Okay. No, you
got it. Go for it.
>> Fred Murdoch from Memphis. This guy, you
talk about turnovers, he'll get him for
you. All-American linebacker, ranked
second in the nation in tackles the last
two years. He's the record holder with
17 forced fumbles, added a team best 13
and a half TFLs, five sacks this past
year. He will smack you. He'll leave
remember me shots. He's good in space.
He's a sure tackler. Plays with
instincts. He's got a natural feel for
the game. I loved him. He's explosive
downhill. He just can't cover. He
legitimately is not a guy that you
really want going backwards from the
line of scrimmage, but he is a menace
who is all around the field. He'll
impact the game. He's just an all-around
good football player. Does he have some
warts? Is he a little stiff? Sure he is.
But he's a splash play kind of guy.
>> What are remember me shots?
>> Remember me shots.
>> Boy, somebody hits you, you remember
that.
>> 113th player on my board.
>> It feels different when certain guys
smack you. He feels that way about no
smud.
>> Red Murdoch. Yeah. A super physical
downhill defender. So the previous FBS
record holder for career force fumbles
was Khalil Mack.
>> Another Buffalo guy. Wow.
>> And Red Murdoch uh eclipse that uh
record to 17. Tackling machine.
Obviously the level of competition is a
concern, especially without the verified
testing and the draft process, but the
physicality and production is worth
betting on. At the very least, he's a
special teams contributor in year one.
The only concern I really have in his
overall game aside from verified testing
is being isolated in coverage. So, I'm
I'm right there with you, Zach. If he
can be confined to between the hashes,
work the run game, uh, then he's he's
got potential as as a linebacker in the
NFL.
>> Tommy, how do you feel about Red
Murdoch?
>> He's nice.
>> There he is.
>> Thank you very much, Tommy. Y
>> walking in.
>> So, the buzzer, okay, so the the
medical's here, chipped bone in an
ankle. Uh, as of right now, he hasn't
gotten surgery, and so the thought is he
might have to get surgery. So I think
that's why a reason he slipped, sprained
MCL in 22 and he tore his hip labum in
high school. So he's got a lot of
baggage there with him as well.
>> So that is Mr. Irrelevant. The final
pick out of 257 total. Red Marduk goes
to the Denver Broncos linebacker out of
Buffalo. Gentlemen, we did it.
>> The weekend is over. We can now drink
all these Miller Lights. Vach is going
to take all those and make sure that
they are good to go. There you go. Go
ahead and we got one reported Jordan
Hudson. to the Cowboys.
>> Ah, UDFAC
SMU wide receiver wide receiver. That's
awesome. That's who it is. Yeah, that's
who's making it happen. Tom Pelisero.
>> Gentlemen, it's always a pleasure
getting to do this weekend with you and
and getting to study throughout the
entire draft process. You guys are all
incredible. You're you're good people.
First off, you're incredible analysts
and incredible knowledge uh base in in
everything that you guys do.
>> I had that. I just didn't have my phone
out. I do want to say I do want to say I
want to dedicate this entire weekend to
Mr. Bratis' mother who passed away uh
during the draft process. So I wanted to
to say once again condolences to you and
your family. Appreciate that. We miss
her cuz we know she used to listen to
this all the time.
>> She listened she would have all the
picks in. She absolutely loves everybody
sitting at this table. So thank you very
much. It's very it's an honor for uh for
her. I know that. And uh thank you guys
again. And I know that uh I was um you
know not part of the the draft show this
year with you guys but to get to come
back and work with you on 1053 the fan
on dallascowboys.com it means a lot.
>> Hey that's always your chair.
>> Always always welcome Chris Beam Matt
Kent who are bringing in some more
Miller lights because we didn't have
enough to fill the studio.
>> Roxy thanks to Roxy Roxy. Roxy getting
all our interview
>> Roxan Medina, the scouting department,
the coaching staff for being so open
with us and having so many conversations
with us throughout the year. We we have
so much uh respect for what they do on a
normal basis and we appreciate all the
information that they're able and
willing to share uh on our side. Scott
Purcell, Matt Kent, uh Josh Rodriguez,
Fica, uh Evan Brown in the back. I'm
trying to think of everybody. I'm going
to miss somebody. Uh but everybody that
had their hands on this one on our end
too on 1053 the family Russell Kevin
Walker Tim Collins Doug Bearclaw Hall
everybody thank you so much.
>> This is uh this is a a wild event and a
wild weekend where we are on the air for
20 hours in the course of 48 total hours
and and we wouldn't have it any other
way. But cheers to you guys. Cheers to
another NFL draft that is in the books.
The Cowboys make their selections. We
got plenty of time until training camp
to break it all down for you. down.
>> We did get Caleb DS. GOT TO LOVE IT. As
always, appreciate you guys joining us
for Brian Bratus, Zack Walchuk, Tommy
Aris, Vach Lombardi, Nick Harris, Bobby
Belt. I'm Kyle Yman saying so long from
the 2026 NFL draft. This has been the
Draft Show presented by Miller Light.
>> On your mom.
>> This has been a production of Dallas
Cowboys.com and the Dallas Cowboys
Football Club.